<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ECC on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/ecc/</link><description>Recent content in ECC on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:09:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/ecc/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preparing for Quantum Computing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/04/21/preparing-for-quantum-computing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:09:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/04/21/preparing-for-quantum-computing/</guid><description>Quantum computing is advancing, and while experts are not sure when there will be a quantum computer powerful enough to break the RSA and ECC cryptographic algorithms that are currently in use, many are operating under the assumption that this can happen within a 10-15 year timeframe.</description></item><item><title>What Are Subordinate CAs and Why Would You Want Your Own?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</guid><description>Digital certificate and PKI adoption has changed quite a bit in recent years. Gone are the days where certificates were only synonymous with SSL/TLS; compliance drivers like stronger authentication requirements and digital signature regulations (e.g. eIDAS) have greatly expanded the role of PKI within the enterprise.
As PKI usage has expanded, conversation has moved beyond just the number and type of certificates needed and onto deeper dialogue about custom PKI deployments.</description></item><item><title>2019 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2018 2018 was an active year for SSL/TLS. We saw the SSL/TLS certificate validity period drop to 825-days and the mass deployment of Certificate Transparency (CT). TLS 1.3 protocol was finally completed and published; and Chrome status bar security indicators changing to remove “secure” and to concentrate on “not secure.” The CA/Browser Forum has been reformed, the London Protocol was announced and the nearly full distrust of Symantec SSL completed.</description></item><item><title>2018 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2017 2017 saw the end of SHA-1 in public trust SSL/TLS certificates and the start of Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) allowing domain owners to authorize their CA. A “Not secure” browser indication was propagated to push more websites to support HTTPS. There was also a change in the certification authority (CA) ownership with DigiCert acquiring Symantec’s SSL and related PKI business and Francisco Partners buying Comodo’s CA.</description></item><item><title>TLS Certificates on the Web – The Good, The Bad and The Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/05/17/tls-certificates-on-the-web-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/05/17/tls-certificates-on-the-web-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>It might be hard to believe, but the SSL/TLS Ecosystem is nearly 20 years old. It’s time to take stock and see how we’re doing with regards to TLS certificates. In this article, we’ll primarily discuss certificates themselves and not web server configuration, although that is often a source of problems.
In the last few years, we’ve endured three major certificate-based migrations:
Away from the MD2 and MD5 hash algorithms to SHA-1 Away from small RSA keys to 2048-bit keys or larger Away from the SHA-1 hash algorithm to SHA-256 What’s driving these migrations?</description></item><item><title>New Directions for Elliptic Curve Cryptography in Internet Protocols</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/06/24/new-directions-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-in-internet-protocols/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 18:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/06/24/new-directions-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-in-internet-protocols/</guid><description>Last week I attended and presented at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Workshop on Elliptic Curve Cryptography Standards. In NIST’s words, “The workshop is to provide a venue to engage the crypto community, including academia, industry, and government users to discuss possible approaches to promote the adoption of secure, interoperable and efficient elliptic curve mechanisms.”
We began by discussing the reasons for holding this workshop. Speakers acknowledged that although there are no known issues with the current set of NIST curves, in some circles they are widely distrusted.</description></item><item><title>Benefits of Elliptic Curve Cryptography</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/06/10/benefits-of-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/06/10/benefits-of-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</guid><description>Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) has existed since the mid-1980s, but it is still looked on as the newcomer in the world of SSL, and has only begun to gain adoption in the past few years. ECC is a fundamentally different mathematical approach to encryption than the venerable RSA algorithm. An elliptic curve is an algebraic function (y2 = x3 + ax + b) which looks like a symmetrical curve parallel to the x axis when plotted.</description></item><item><title>Perfect Forward Secrecy</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/11/perfect-forward-secrecy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/11/perfect-forward-secrecy/</guid><description>Recent revelations from Edward Snowden about pervasive government surveillance have led to many questions about the safety of communications using the SSL/TLS protocol. Such communications are generally safe from eavesdroppers, as long as certain precautions are observed. For example, configuring your web server to avoid using SSL2 and SSL3, favoring newer versions of TLS like TLS 1.2, selecting strong ciphersuites, etc.
But even if your server is configured properly, you still must secure the private key associated with your SSL certificate.</description></item><item><title>2014 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 20:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2013 Protocol Attacks The year started with a couple of SSL/TLS protocol attacks: Lucky Thirteen and RC4 attack. Lucky Thirteen allows the decryption of sensitive information, such as passwords and cookies, when using the CBC-mode cipher suite. Lucky Thirteen can be mitigated by implementing software patches or preferring the cipher suite RC4.
That being said, RC4 was also attacked, where through 16 million sessions a small amount of plaintext can be recovered.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Still Works – It’s About How You Implement It</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/13/encryption-still-works-its-about-how-you-implement-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 17:04:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/13/encryption-still-works-its-about-how-you-implement-it/</guid><description>The September 5th joint article by the New York Times and Guardian newspapers on NSA’s and GCHQ’s efforts to circumvent encryption implementation have left many people speculating on the security of the data they are transmitting over the Internet. Hopefully, this blog post will provide some guidance and help understand SSL in light of these recent articles. Importantly, the articles point out that the primary means of attacking SSL/TLS do not exploit a vulnerability in the protocol itself but instead aim to exploit poor implementations of the protocol, insecure servers, and weak cryptography.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 1: Choose the Right Certificate</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/25/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-1-choose-the-right-certificate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 01:09:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/25/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-1-choose-the-right-certificate/</guid><description>SSL and HTTPS are two of the most common security technologies on the internet today, but at the same time their use can be complex and challenging to get right. Over the next few weeks, we’ll be publishing a series of articles aimed at identifying some of the decisions that need to be made when buying, installing, and using SSL certificates. In this first installment, I’ll discuss some of the issues to consider when buying and requesting a certificate.</description></item></channel></rss>