<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSH on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/ssh/</link><description>Recent content in SSH on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 17:02:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/ssh/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How a SWEET32 Birthday Attack is Deployed and How to Prevent It</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/09/07/how-a-sweet32-birthday-attack-is-deployed-and-how-to-prevent-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 17:02:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/09/07/how-a-sweet32-birthday-attack-is-deployed-and-how-to-prevent-it/</guid><description>Details surrounding the SWEET32: Birthday attacks on 64-bit block ciphers in TLS and OpenVPN can be found in the paper released by Karthikeyan Bhargavan and Gaëtan Leurent from INRIA in France. The paper shows that cipher suites using 64-bit block length ciphers are vulnerable to plaintext recovery attacks. As such, Triple-DES (3DES) and Blowfish are vulnerable. Here’s an overview.
Vulnerabilities to a SWEET32 Birthday Attack Certain scenarios are pre-disposed to a SWEET32 Birthday attack.</description></item><item><title>Ten Steps to Take If Your Website Is Compromised</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/02/12/ten-steps-to-take-if-your-website-is-compromised/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 20:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/02/12/ten-steps-to-take-if-your-website-is-compromised/</guid><description>After the news broke that 40 million credit card numbers were stolen from Target in a data breach of epic proportions, many of their customers went to work checking their accounts for fraudulent purchases and replacing cards we’d used recently at Target. These have become standard responses to news of this sort. In much the same way, there are some common actions that you should be aware of if your website becomes compromised.</description></item></channel></rss>