<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RSA on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/rsa/</link><description>Recent content in RSA on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:09:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/rsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preparing for Quantum Computing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/04/21/preparing-for-quantum-computing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:09:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/04/21/preparing-for-quantum-computing/</guid><description>Quantum computing is advancing, and while experts are not sure when there will be a quantum computer powerful enough to break the RSA and ECC cryptographic algorithms that are currently in use, many are operating under the assumption that this can happen within a 10-15 year timeframe.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Members Presentation at RSA 2014 Conference: New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</guid><description>CA Security Council (CASC) members Trend Micro, Go Daddy, and Symantec participated in a discussion panel at the 2014 RSA Conference in San Francisco on February 24 entitled “New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet.” Panel members included Kirk Hall of Trend Micro (Moderator), Wayne Thayer of GoDaddy (Panelist), and Rick Andrews of Symantec (Panelist).
Introduction to the Topic Hall began by introducing the topic – all three alternative technologies (Certificate Transparency or CT, Certificate Authority Authorization or CAA, and Certificate Pinning) are intended to make the internet safer by dealing with mis-issued digital certificates, including so-called “rogue” certs like those obtained by a hacker from the now-defunct Diginotar Certification Authority (CA).</description></item><item><title>RSA Recap – Securing Your Site</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/08/rsa-recap-securing-your-site/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/08/rsa-recap-securing-your-site/</guid><description>At RSA last week a few of us participated in panel discussions that focused on SSL/TLS. During the panel that I moderated on Friday, one theme we addressed was secure server configuration. One of CASC’s goals is to help harden existing SSL/TLS implementations against vulnerabilities—because most SSL/TLS exploits arise from suboptimal website configurations. These vulnerabilities and attacks can be mitigated or even eliminated with proper server configuration and good website design.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at RSA</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/25/casc-happenings-at-rsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 15:32:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/25/casc-happenings-at-rsa/</guid><description>We are excited to have members of the CASC attending and speaking at this year’s RSA Conference. The events and panels will cover various topics that revolve around the security of the Internet and CAs as a whole. You can follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item></channel></rss>