<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3DES on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/3des/</link><description>Recent content in 3DES on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 21:11:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/3des/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2017 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 21:11:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2016 Fortunately, 2016 was not a year full of SSL/TLS vulnerabilities. Although some researchers did prove old cryptography algorithms should be put out to pasture. The year showed the end of public-trusted SHA-1 SSL/TLS certificates. It also showed more transparency should be considered due to issues discovered with a few certification authorities (CAs). The great news is HTTPS is no longer the minority — after 20 years, connections using HTTPS has surpassed HTTP.</description></item><item><title>Stricter Standards for SSL Server Test Coming in 2017</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/13/stricter-standards-for-ssl-server-test-coming-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 16:32:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/13/stricter-standards-for-ssl-server-test-coming-in-2017/</guid><description>This is a good time to offer a reminder that the CASC has a great tool for secure server testing, the SSL Server Test. The tool grades your server installation and reviews the: certificate, protocol support, key exchange and cipher strength for security against standards and known vulnerabilities.
The grading tool also provides feedback on handshake simulations with various versions of browsers and operating systems. This lets the server administrator know which implementations are supported.</description></item><item><title>How a SWEET32 Birthday Attack is Deployed and How to Prevent It</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/09/07/how-a-sweet32-birthday-attack-is-deployed-and-how-to-prevent-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 17:02:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/09/07/how-a-sweet32-birthday-attack-is-deployed-and-how-to-prevent-it/</guid><description>Details surrounding the SWEET32: Birthday attacks on 64-bit block ciphers in TLS and OpenVPN can be found in the paper released by Karthikeyan Bhargavan and Gaëtan Leurent from INRIA in France. The paper shows that cipher suites using 64-bit block length ciphers are vulnerable to plaintext recovery attacks. As such, Triple-DES (3DES) and Blowfish are vulnerable. Here’s an overview.
Vulnerabilities to a SWEET32 Birthday Attack Certain scenarios are pre-disposed to a SWEET32 Birthday attack.</description></item><item><title>Perfect Forward Secrecy</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/11/perfect-forward-secrecy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/11/perfect-forward-secrecy/</guid><description>Recent revelations from Edward Snowden about pervasive government surveillance have led to many questions about the safety of communications using the SSL/TLS protocol. Such communications are generally safe from eavesdroppers, as long as certain precautions are observed. For example, configuring your web server to avoid using SSL2 and SSL3, favoring newer versions of TLS like TLS 1.2, selecting strong ciphersuites, etc.
But even if your server is configured properly, you still must secure the private key associated with your SSL certificate.</description></item></channel></rss>