<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CA Security Council on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/authors/ca-security-council/</link><description>Recent content in CA Security Council on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/authors/ca-security-council/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CASC Announces Launch of London Protocol to Improve Identity Assurance and Minimize Phishing on Identity Websites</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</guid><description>LONDON – (June 27, 2018) – The Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of the security of websites and online transactions, announced at the CA/Browser Forum event in London the launch of the London Protocol – an initiative to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted with organization validated (OV) and extended validation (EV) certificates, which contain organization identity information (Identity Certificates).</description></item><item><title>The London Protocol</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/the-london-protocol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/the-london-protocol/</guid><description>The objective of The London Protocol is to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted by OV (organization validated) and EV (extended validation) certificates (together referred to as “Identity Websites”). The London Protocol reinforces the distinction between Identity Websites making them even more secure for users than websites encrypted by DV (domain validated) certificates. That security feature can then be utilized by others for their own security purposes, including informing users as to the type of website they are visiting and use by antiphishing engines and browser filters in their security algorithms.</description></item><item><title>Fortify Provides a More Secure Web Experience for Certificates and Smart Cards</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-provides-a-more-secure-web-experience-for-certificates-and-smart-cards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-provides-a-more-secure-web-experience-for-certificates-and-smart-cards/</guid><description>San Francisco – June 19, 2018 – The Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of web security, today announced that Fortify, an open source application sponsored by the Council, is now available for Windows and Mac. Fortify, a free app, connects a user’s web browsers to smart cards, security tokens, and certificates on a user’s local machine. This allows users to generate X.509 certificates in their browser, replacing the loss of key generation functionality.</description></item><item><title>Leading Certificate Authorities and Microsoft Introduce New Standards to Protect Consumers Online</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 21:05:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</guid><description>San Francisco –December 8, 2016 – the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement web security, today announced the Code Signing Working Group has released new Minimum Requirements for Code Signing for use by all Certificate Authorities (CA). These requirements represent the first-ever standardized code signing guidelines. Code signing is the method of using a certificate-based digital signature to sign executables and scripts in order to verify the author’s identity and ensure that the code has not been changed or corrupted.</description></item><item><title>Code Signing Baseline Requirements</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/11/30/code-signing-baseline-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 17:51:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/11/30/code-signing-baseline-requirements/</guid><description>You may have heard that the CA/Browser Forum is getting ready to approve Baseline Requirements for Code Signing certificates. But why is this important?
Let’s back up and get some background on code signing. Software code that is digitally signed indicates to the user that the code has not been tampered with since it was signed. It also provides authenticity as to who signed it and when. With the advent of malware, it’s important to insure that the code which was written by the developer is the same code which you downloaded and installed into your computer or mobile phone.</description></item><item><title>How Safe Are Your Business’ Online Payments?: E-Commerce Sites and Protected Payment Gateways</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/10/21/how-safe-are-your-business-online-payments-e-commerce-sites-and-protected-payment-gateways/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 15:07:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/10/21/how-safe-are-your-business-online-payments-e-commerce-sites-and-protected-payment-gateways/</guid><description>This blog was originally posted on staysafeonline.org on June 29, 2015.
Online payments can be made in a variety of ways, but majority of the online financial transactions are done through secured payment gateways. Secure payment gateways, as the name suggests, are application service providers for ecommerce websites that authorize various financial transactions taking place on online stores for ensuring safety for both the retailers and the online buyers. The key goal of payment gateways is to secure personal information like cconsumers’ credit card numbers by encrypting their personal and confidential information.</description></item><item><title>Extended Validation Builds Trust (Infographic)</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/15/extended-validation-builds-trust-infographic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/15/extended-validation-builds-trust-infographic/</guid><description>Click on the image above to download a full-size version.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Report: Consumers Don’t Know Much About Security, But They Trust the Padlock and Green Bar When Shopping Online</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/13/ca-security-council-report-consumers-dont-know-much-about-security-but-they-trust-the-padlock-and-green-bar-when-shopping-online/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/13/ca-security-council-report-consumers-dont-know-much-about-security-but-they-trust-the-padlock-and-green-bar-when-shopping-online/</guid><description>San Francisco – April 13, 2015 – The CA Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of the security of websites and online transactions, today released its 2015 Consumer Trust Survey which found that validation matters. While consumers are confused about some aspects of security, they recognize and trust the security that SSL brings to e-commerce sites. Fifty-three percent of respondents identify the padlock as adding confidence in an e-commerce site, with 42 percent associating the green bar and organization name in the URL with greater safety.</description></item><item><title>Fighting the Good Fight for Online Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:47:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</guid><description>Once again Browsers and Certificate Authorities are in the news over the reported mis-issuance of an SSL server certificate to a google.com domain. Discovered by Google most likely via technology known as key pinning and discussed by Google’s Adam Langley in this blog, a Chinese certificate authority, CNNIC (Chinese Internet Network Information Center), apparently issued an intermediate certificate to an Egyptian company called MCS Holdings. Because the CNNIC root certificate is included in the root store of most major browsers, users would not see any warnings on sites that have certificates issued by CNNIC or MCS Holdings.</description></item><item><title>’Tis the Season for Online Safety</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/11/30/tis-the-season-for-online-safety/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 13:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/11/30/tis-the-season-for-online-safety/</guid><description>The holidays are approaching as quickly as a sleigh pulled by magic reindeer, and every year it seems like the shopping season starts earlier and earlier. In many places, Christmas decorations are now put up before Halloween, ensuring a long and profitable season for merchants. And while most of us have had the experience of opening a disappointing gift on Christmas morning, one thing that can ruin your holiday faster than a homemade sweater is finding out that someone has obtained your credit card number, or compromised your account on your favorite shopping website.</description></item><item><title>Google Plans to Deprecate SHA-1 Certificates – Updated</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/09/24/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates-updated/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 18:26:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/09/24/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates-updated/</guid><description>UPDATED September 23, 2014: The following blog post has been updated with action taken in recent weeks, as well as to reflect helpful user comments left on our August 28 blog post on this topic.
On August 19, Google announced a new policy that accelerates the deprecation of SHA-1 certificates, potentially causing websites using SHA-1 certificates to display warnings in the near future. While keeping with an earlier Microsoft announcement to accept SHA-1 certificates with an expiration date before Jan.</description></item><item><title>Google Plans to Deprecate SHA-1 Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/28/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 14:07:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/28/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates/</guid><description>On August 19, Google announced a new policy that accelerates the deprecation of SHA-1 certificates, potentially causing websites using SHA-1 certificates to display warnings in the near future. With the change, Chrome 39 will show a warning for sites that have a SHA-1 certificate expiring in 2016 and require a click through warning for sites with a SHA-1 certificate expiring in 2017 or later. This proposal is scheduled for Chrome 39, which could be released as early as 12 weeks from now.</description></item><item><title>CASC Heartbleed Response</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/05/08/casc-heartbleed-response/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 15:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/05/08/casc-heartbleed-response/</guid><description>The recent Heartbleed issue has reawakened interest in SSL certificate revocation (see Adam Langley’s blog, Larry Seltzer’s articles here and here, and Steve Gibson’s web pages)
Several years ago, the CA Browser Forum convened a special Revocation Working Group to explore issues and solutions. Leading CAs were actively involved in that group, and many of them invested in moving their OCSP responders to high-performance, high-availability Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) to respond to browser vendors’ requests for increased performance and reliability.</description></item><item><title>What Is Certificate Transparency and How Does It Propose to Address Certificate Mis-Issuance?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/09/what-is-certificate-transparency-and-how-does-it-propose-to-address-certificate-mis-issuance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/09/what-is-certificate-transparency-and-how-does-it-propose-to-address-certificate-mis-issuance/</guid><description>As originally architected by Netscape and others in the mid-1990s, the certificate issuance process envisioned that the CA would present the certificate and its contents to the named subject who would review and accept the certificate first. Then the CA would publish the certificate to a repository. That process would establish that the certificate’s subject was aware of certificate issuance. (Otherwise, an unscrupulous CA could sign a subscriber’s public key and create a certificate for the subscriber without its knowledge.</description></item><item><title>5 Tips for SMBs to Help Secure Their Online Presence</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/17/5-tips-for-smbs-to-help-secure-their-online-presence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 20:12:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/17/5-tips-for-smbs-to-help-secure-their-online-presence/</guid><description>With National SMB Week upon us, the CASC has come up with its five tips for SMBs to help secure their online presence. By implementing these simple steps SMBs can build trust and loyalty by ensuring their website is safe to visit, search, enter personal information, or complete a transaction.
Create unbreakable passwords – Strong passwords are essential on any account related to your online presence (domain registrar, hosting account, SSL provider, social media, PayPal, etc.</description></item><item><title>Some Comments on Web Security</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/05/some-comments-on-web-security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 02:23:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/05/some-comments-on-web-security/</guid><description>Steve Johnson of the Mercury News posted an article on Web security and highlighted some of the issues.
The posted issues help to explain why we created the Certificate Authority Security Council. We want to determine the issues, have them addressed and provide awareness and education on the solutions. The CAs also work with the browsers and other experts in the industry to develop standards for all CAs to be audited against through the CA/Browser Forum.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to OCSP Multi-Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 21:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</guid><description>OCSP Stapling OCSP is a protocol used to check the validity of certificates to make sure they have not been revoked. OCSP is an alternative to Certificate Revocation Lists (CRLs). Since OCSP responses can be as small as a few hundred bytes, OCSP is particularly useful when the issuing CA has relatively big CRLs, as well as when the client has limited memory and processing power.
OCSP can also provide much more timely information than CRLs about the status of a certificate since the information is generally fetched more frequently.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at NIST</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</guid><description>This week members of the CASC will be attending and speaking at the NIST Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace. You can also follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Even if you can’t make it to Maryland, you can still watch the event via the live webcast. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item><item><title>What the ICANN SSAC Report Doesn’t Tell You</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/22/what-the-icann-ssac-report-doesnt-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:19:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/22/what-the-icann-ssac-report-doesnt-tell-you/</guid><description>The CA Security Council, which comprises seven of the largest CAs, read with interest the article titled, “Internal-use SSL certificates pose security risk for upcoming domain extensions.” As a group in one of the best positions to understand the impact of the new gTLDs on organizational security infrastructure and the Internet as a whole, we felt it appropriate to comment on this and related stories which summarize the ICANN Security and Stability Advisory Committee (SSAC) report sac 045 Invalid Top Level Domain Queries at the Root Level of the Domain Name System.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at RSA</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/25/casc-happenings-at-rsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 15:32:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/25/casc-happenings-at-rsa/</guid><description>We are excited to have members of the CASC attending and speaking at this year’s RSA Conference. The events and panels will cover various topics that revolve around the security of the Internet and CAs as a whole. You can follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item><item><title>Certificate Revocation and OCSP Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</guid><description>Revocation As a body of global CAs, the CA Security Council is committed to educating server administrators, end-users and other interested parties about SSL enhancements and best practices that can better protect everyone. An important initiative that can make a practical difference right now is addressing easily implemented improvements to certificate status services that handle revocation of invalid or expired certificates, specifically the implementation of OCSP stapling.
What is certificate revocation?</description></item><item><title>World’s Leading Certificate Authorities Come Together to Advance Internet Security and the Trusted SSL Ecosystem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</guid><description>San Francisco, CA. – February 14, 2013 – Leading global certificate authorities announced the creation of the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group, committed to the exploration and promotion of best practices that advance the security of websites and online transactions. Through public education, collaboration, and advocacy, the CASC strives to improve understanding of critical policies and their potential impact on the internet infrastructure. Members of the CASC include Comodo, DigiCert, Entrust, GlobalSign, Go Daddy, Symantec, and Trend Micro.</description></item></channel></rss>