<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SHA2 on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/sha2/</link><description>Recent content in SHA2 on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/sha2/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Year Certs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</guid><description>Starting on September 1st, SSL/TLS certificates cannot be issued for longer than 13 months (397 days). This change was first announced by Apple at the CA/Browser Forum Spring Face-to-Face event in Bratislava back in March.</description></item><item><title>Reducing the Impact of Government Spying</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/04/reducing-the-impact-of-government-spying/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/04/reducing-the-impact-of-government-spying/</guid><description>Last year, Edward Snowden, an American computer-specialist working as a contractor for the National Security Agency (“NSA”), shocked web-users around the world by publicizing documents showing that the NSA was gathering intelligence on Internet users. The realization that the US government was gathering sensitive information has led to a worldwide demand for better protection of online communication and data and a general worry about the effectiveness of existing infrastructures. Specifically, some entities have asked whether PKI is still a robust way to protect online information.</description></item><item><title>Why We Need to Move to SHA-2</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/30/why-we-need-to-move-to-sha-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 18:30:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/30/why-we-need-to-move-to-sha-2/</guid><description>Previously, we advised that the SSL industry must move to the SHA-2 hashing algorithm for certificate signatures. We thought it would be helpful to provide the reasoning behind the position.
In the context of SSL, the purpose of a hashing algorithm is to reduce a message (e.g., a certificate) to a reasonable size for use with a digital signature algorithm. The hash value, or message digest, is then signed to allow an end-user to validate the certificate and ensure it was issued by a trusted certification authority (CA).</description></item><item><title>It’s Time for TLS 1.2</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/19/its-time-for-tls-1.2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/19/its-time-for-tls-1.2/</guid><description>In a previous post titled Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2, we touched on the recommendation that Web servers be configured to prefer Transport Layer Security (TLS) version 1.2. With the planned release of Firefox 24 and recent release of Chrome 29 adding support for TLS 1.2, now is a great time for website administrators to make the switch.
Transport Layer Security was formerly called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and is the protocol that enables secure “https://” connections to websites.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Still Works – It’s About How You Implement It</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/13/encryption-still-works-its-about-how-you-implement-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 17:04:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/13/encryption-still-works-its-about-how-you-implement-it/</guid><description>The September 5th joint article by the New York Times and Guardian newspapers on NSA’s and GCHQ’s efforts to circumvent encryption implementation have left many people speculating on the security of the data they are transmitting over the Internet. Hopefully, this blog post will provide some guidance and help understand SSL in light of these recent articles. Importantly, the articles point out that the primary means of attacking SSL/TLS do not exploit a vulnerability in the protocol itself but instead aim to exploit poor implementations of the protocol, insecure servers, and weak cryptography.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 1: Choose the Right Certificate</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/25/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-1-choose-the-right-certificate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 01:09:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/25/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-1-choose-the-right-certificate/</guid><description>SSL and HTTPS are two of the most common security technologies on the internet today, but at the same time their use can be complex and challenging to get right. Over the next few weeks, we’ll be publishing a series of articles aimed at identifying some of the decisions that need to be made when buying, installing, and using SSL certificates. In this first installment, I’ll discuss some of the issues to consider when buying and requesting a certificate.</description></item></channel></rss>