<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Announcement on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/announcement/</link><description>Recent content in Announcement on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 17:50:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/announcement/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Certificate Transparency (CT) to Expand to All Certificates Types</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/11/08/google-certificate-transparency-ct-to-expand-to-all-certificates-types/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 17:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/11/08/google-certificate-transparency-ct-to-expand-to-all-certificates-types/</guid><description>The policy change goes into effect October 2017 A recent Google announcement stated that all publicly trusted SSL/TLS certificates issued in October 2017 or later will be expected to comply with Chrome’s Certificate Transparency (CT) policy or be untrusted by the browser.
Since January 2015, Chrome has required Extended Validation (EV) certificates to comply with CT. With this policy change, the Chrome CT policy will also apply to Domain Validated (DV) and Organization Validated (OV) certificates.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Will Stop Supporting SHA-1 in October</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/06/08/facebook-will-stop-supporting-sha-1-in-october/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 16:14:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/06/08/facebook-will-stop-supporting-sha-1-in-october/</guid><description>On June 2, 2015, Facebook announced that it would stop supporting Facebook-connected apps that were signed with SHA-1, as of October 1, 2015.
“These changes are part of a broader shift in how browsers and web sites encrypt traffic to protect the contents of online communications. Typically, web browsers use a hash function to create a unique fingerprint for a chunk of data or a message. This fingerprint is then digitally signed to prove that a message has not been altered or tampered with when passing through the various servers and systems between your computer and Facebook’s servers.</description></item><item><title>HTTP/2 Is Speedy and Secure</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/20/http/2-is-speedy-and-secure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/20/http/2-is-speedy-and-secure/</guid><description>Since we last wrote about SSL/TLS performance, there has been a lot of activity in the IETF HTTP Working Group, resulting in the February announcement that the next version of HTTP has been approved. This is big news because it means that major SSL/TLS performance improvements are on the way.
Background When your browser connects to a website today, it most likely uses the HTTP/1.1 protocol that was defined in 1999 in RFC 2616.</description></item><item><title>Google Plans to Deprecate SHA-1 Certificates – Updated</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/09/24/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates-updated/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 18:26:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/09/24/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates-updated/</guid><description>UPDATED September 23, 2014: The following blog post has been updated with action taken in recent weeks, as well as to reflect helpful user comments left on our August 28 blog post on this topic.
On August 19, Google announced a new policy that accelerates the deprecation of SHA-1 certificates, potentially causing websites using SHA-1 certificates to display warnings in the near future. While keeping with an earlier Microsoft announcement to accept SHA-1 certificates with an expiration date before Jan.</description></item><item><title>Google to Give Priority Ranking to SSL Enabled Sites</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/21/google-to-give-priority-ranking-to-ssl-enabled-sites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 17:30:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/21/google-to-give-priority-ranking-to-ssl-enabled-sites/</guid><description>Google’s announcement that it will give priority ranking to SSL enabled sites is a key milestone for increased use of SSL on the Internet.
Google announced a change to its ranking algorithm to include use of SSL on the site as a “very lightweight [positive] signal”. Although, this might not have an immediate impact to website owners/operators that are not currently using SSL, this is still an important signal indicating everyone should be prepared to encrypt all their websites if they want to remain relevant.</description></item><item><title>OCSP Must-Staple</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/06/18/ocsp-must-staple/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 18:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/06/18/ocsp-must-staple/</guid><description>With the announcement of the Heartbleed bug and the resulting need to revoke large numbers of SSL certificates, the topic of certificate revocation has, once again, come to the fore.
There have been many issues with how revocation information is provided to the browsers. First let’s review how SSL certificate status may currently be obtained: How
| How | Definition | Pros | Cons | | signed list of the serial numbers of all revoked certificates that were signed by the CA’s certificate.</description></item><item><title>ICANN’s Accelerated gTLD Delegation Process and How This Impacts Your Organization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</guid><description>After the CASC’s previous letter addressing ICANN’s proposal to delegate nearly 2000 new gTLDs for use on the public Internet, ICANN identified and initiated an extensive study on two significant security issues. Now, based on the conclusions of the studies, ICANN is moving forward quickly with the delegation process, delegating more than 30 in the last two months alone. With ICANN ramping up the delegation process, nearly all 2000 will be delegated under the new rules, with only .</description></item><item><title>CAs Unite</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/cas-unite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/cas-unite/</guid><description>Today marks an important day for internet security and future SSL enhancements, as the world’s seven largest publicly trusted Certificate Authorities are announcing the formation of the Certificate Authority Security Council.
While leading CAs have worked together for years to address security challenges and meet them with evolving and increasingly strict standards and best practices through the CA/Browser Forum and other industry venues, we’ve lacked a union where we can come together and speak with a unified CA voice.</description></item></channel></rss>