<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Qualified on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/qualified/</link><description>Recent content in Qualified on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 17:00:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/qualified/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Trust Is Elusive – Are Qualified Trust Services A Solution?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/05/01/digital-trust-is-elusive-are-qualified-trust-services-a-solution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/05/01/digital-trust-is-elusive-are-qualified-trust-services-a-solution/</guid><description>A popular saying goes: “Trust takes years to build, seconds to break, and forever to repair.”
While I wouldn’t completely agree, the idea isn’t wrong. In real life trust between two parties is established over some period of time, depending on a variety of factors. Have you ever wondered why you initially trust some people more and others less, even if you’ve never met them before? There are a complicated multitude of factors that influence our thoughts: the person’s appearance, tone of voice, title or rank, etc.</description></item><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>9 Common Myths About CAs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</guid><description>Over the years misconceptions about CAs and the SSL infrastructure have arisen. Below is a list of common myths related to SSL and CAs.
Myth #1: CAs are not regulated Fact: CAs are subject to various checks and balances, including third-party qualified audits through WebTrust or ETSI and strict criteria set forth by leading browsers, before they are accepted in browser root stores. Similarly, the CA/Browser Forum’s Baseline Requirements and Network Security Guidelines establish global standards for certificate issuance and CA controls that will soon be included in third-party auditing standards.</description></item><item><title>2019 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2018 2018 was an active year for SSL/TLS. We saw the SSL/TLS certificate validity period drop to 825-days and the mass deployment of Certificate Transparency (CT). TLS 1.3 protocol was finally completed and published; and Chrome status bar security indicators changing to remove “secure” and to concentrate on “not secure.” The CA/Browser Forum has been reformed, the London Protocol was announced and the nearly full distrust of Symantec SSL completed.</description></item><item><title>The Latest on Certification Authority Authorization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/03/21/the-latest-on-certification-authority-authorization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 20:40:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/03/21/the-latest-on-certification-authority-authorization/</guid><description>Things are certainly heating up at the CA/Browser with exciting proposals surrounding inclusion of the Wi-Fi Alliance (WFA) as a subjectAltName otherName, new validation methods, and debates over how the CAB Forum will continue operating. One of these newly passed ballots requires all CAs to check and process a domain name’s DNS Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) resource record prior to issuing a digital certificate.
Background RFC 6844 created CAA records as a method for domain owners to specify a policy on which certificate authorities are authorized to issue certificates for the associated domain.</description></item><item><title>Always-On SSL</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/09/30/always-on-ssl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 17:12:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/09/30/always-on-ssl/</guid><description>There is no doubt that content owners and publishers have a duty to encourage trust and the confidence during internet usage by adopting security best practices. If a customer believes that their data and identity are safe and protected, they are more inclined to continue their online transactions. Industry best practices for website protection should be vendor-neutral, easy to implement, and globally accessible. Websites should take all the reasonable steps possible to adopt best practices in secure design and implementation, and this includes using Always-On SSL across the entire website.</description></item><item><title>CA/B Forum Istanbul 2015</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/11/10/ca/b-forum-istanbul-2015/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 16:20:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/11/10/ca/b-forum-istanbul-2015/</guid><description>While some face to face meetings can be rather mundane and boring, that can’t be said about October’s CA/B Forum meeting in Istanbul, Turkey. Guest speaker Andrea Servida from the European Commission gave an overview of the new eIDAS regulation on electronic identification and trust services. While not everyone in the room agreed with his points, all were made aware that this has now become the law in the EU and certificate authorities which plan to issue the new EU Qualified website certificates must comply with it.</description></item><item><title>What To Do When You Rely on Internal Names in TLS/SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/18/what-to-do-when-you-rely-on-internal-names-in-tls/ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 18:20:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/18/what-to-do-when-you-rely-on-internal-names-in-tls/ssl-certificates/</guid><description>A deadline set by the CA/Browser Forum for the use of Internal Names is quickly approaching, and many system administrators need to understand how best to adapt to this change. At the same time, hundreds of new top-level domains are being launched, which redefines what constitutes an Internal Name. In this post we’ll explain what the changes are, why they’re being made, and how you can update your systems in response to the problem.</description></item><item><title>Always-On SSL, Part II</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/02/05/always-on-ssl-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 20:30:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/02/05/always-on-ssl-part-ii/</guid><description>The SSL/TLS protocol has more to offer than just providing you with transmission encryption. Its main benefit is that it provides a way for third parties to authenticate connections to your website over the Internet. A user who can connect to your site and retrieve information via SSL/TLS will have greater assurance and trust that information came from you. The point of Always-On SSL is that once a user is able to create an authenticated connection to your point of presence via https, then he or she should not be bounced back outside of that zone of protection.</description></item><item><title>CA Day in Berlin</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/24/ca-day-in-berlin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 18:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/24/ca-day-in-berlin/</guid><description>“CA Day” (also known as CA Conformity Assessment) was hosted by the German company TuVIT in Berlin on January 16, 2014. In attendance were approximately 100 people from mostly European CAs. Under the European regulatory framework, CAs are included in a group referred to as “Trust Service Providers” or “TSPs.” CASC members in attendance at CA Day were Symantec, Digicert and Comodo. The dominant theme for this CA Day was the draft Regulation on Electronic identification and trust services for electronic transactions in the internal market (eIDAS) and upcoming changes in EU regulations for Qualified Certificates, which was briefed by Gerard Galler from the European Commission and discussed in greater detail by several European TSPs.</description></item><item><title>ICANN’s Accelerated gTLD Delegation Process and How This Impacts Your Organization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</guid><description>After the CASC’s previous letter addressing ICANN’s proposal to delegate nearly 2000 new gTLDs for use on the public Internet, ICANN identified and initiated an extensive study on two significant security issues. Now, based on the conclusions of the studies, ICANN is moving forward quickly with the delegation process, delegating more than 30 in the last two months alone. With ICANN ramping up the delegation process, nearly all 2000 will be delegated under the new rules, with only .</description></item><item><title>Certificate Authority Audits and Browser Root Program Requirements</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/10/15/certificate-authority-audits-and-browser-root-program-requirements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/10/15/certificate-authority-audits-and-browser-root-program-requirements/</guid><description>Recent news stories have highlighted the need for strong security in online communications, and use of SSL certificates issued by a publicly trusted Certification Authority (CA) is perhaps the best way to achieve that. But why should the public trust SSL certificates issued from commercial CA roots, which are embedded as trust anchors in web browsers?
One answer is because of the multiple layers of standards and tough requirements that all commercial CAs must meet – and for which they are audited every year.</description></item></channel></rss>