<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NIST on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/nist/</link><description>Recent content in NIST on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:09:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/nist/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preparing for Quantum Computing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/04/21/preparing-for-quantum-computing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:09:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/04/21/preparing-for-quantum-computing/</guid><description>Quantum computing is advancing, and while experts are not sure when there will be a quantum computer powerful enough to break the RSA and ECC cryptographic algorithms that are currently in use, many are operating under the assumption that this can happen within a 10-15 year timeframe.</description></item><item><title>New Directions for Elliptic Curve Cryptography in Internet Protocols</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/06/24/new-directions-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-in-internet-protocols/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 18:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/06/24/new-directions-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-in-internet-protocols/</guid><description>Last week I attended and presented at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Workshop on Elliptic Curve Cryptography Standards. In NIST’s words, “The workshop is to provide a venue to engage the crypto community, including academia, industry, and government users to discuss possible approaches to promote the adoption of secure, interoperable and efficient elliptic curve mechanisms.”
We began by discussing the reasons for holding this workshop. Speakers acknowledged that although there are no known issues with the current set of NIST curves, in some circles they are widely distrusted.</description></item><item><title>Recap of NIST’s Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/17/recap-of-nists-workshop-on-improving-trust-in-the-online-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 18:29:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/17/recap-of-nists-workshop-on-improving-trust-in-the-online-marketplace/</guid><description>On April 10 and 11, NIST held a workshop in Maryland to bring together many parties (industry, research and academia communities, and government sectors) to examine “technical and administrative efforts to increase trust online by improving the Public Key Infrastructure certificate marketplace supporting SSL and TLS.”
From the opening keynote to the final remarks, we heard from experts around the world. There were presentations on the current state of trust infrastructure and audits, the impact of recent breaches, detailed looks on some emerging solutions like Certificate Transparency and DANE, and new ideas to manage and minimize risk in key usage.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at NIST</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</guid><description>This week members of the CASC will be attending and speaking at the NIST Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace. You can also follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Even if you can’t make it to Maryland, you can still watch the event via the live webcast. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item><item><title>Self-Signed Certificates Don’t Deliver Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/02/self-signed-certificates-dont-deliver-trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 20:48:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/02/self-signed-certificates-dont-deliver-trust/</guid><description>We’ve heard the argument that website operators could just use self-signed certificates. They are easy to issue and they are “free.” Before issuing self-signed certificates, it’s a good idea to examine the trust and security model. You should also compare self-signed certificates to the publicly trusted certification authority (CA) model; and then make your own decision.
Self-Signed Certificate Model Owner says who they are Owner issues on their own policy Owner is responsible for quality Owner may not follow industry guidelines Owner may not provide certificate status Compromised certificates may not be able to be revoked Owner is not audited Issuer of certificate may not be authorized by the domain owner Certificates may not be renewed if there are no reminders Self-signed certificate model does not provide trust and the browser provides a trust dialogue box to indicate such Publicly-Trusted CA-Signed Certificate Model CA verifies the owner of the domain and the certificate applicant CA operates to a policy in conformance with the requirements of the browser and operating system vendors.</description></item></channel></rss>