<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NIST on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/nist/</link><description>Recent content in NIST on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 18:29:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/nist/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recap of NIST’s Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/17/recap-of-nists-workshop-on-improving-trust-in-the-online-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 18:29:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/17/recap-of-nists-workshop-on-improving-trust-in-the-online-marketplace/</guid><description>On April 10 and 11, NIST held a workshop in Maryland to bring together many parties (industry, research and academia communities, and government sectors) to examine “technical and administrative efforts to increase trust online by improving the Public Key Infrastructure certificate marketplace supporting SSL and TLS.”
From the opening keynote to the final remarks, we heard from experts around the world. There were presentations on the current state of trust infrastructure and audits, the impact of recent breaches, detailed looks on some emerging solutions like Certificate Transparency and DANE, and new ideas to manage and minimize risk in key usage.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at NIST</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</guid><description>This week members of the CASC will be attending and speaking at the NIST Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace. You can also follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Even if you can’t make it to Maryland, you can still watch the event via the live webcast. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item></channel></rss>