<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Members on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/</link><description>Recent content in Members on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:44:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/members/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Firmaprofesional</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/firmaprofesional/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 09:11:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/firmaprofesional/</guid><description>We innovate to create secure and efficient transaction environments We are a Trust Service Provider focussed on driving the digital competitiveness of organisations, covering identity and electronic signature services with the utmost legal validity. Moreover, our technology fully integrates into any platform or management system, guaranteeing its ease of use and availability.
We lead the trusted services market thanks to specialization and our ability to adapt to the specific needs of our customers.</description></item><item><title>Buypass</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/buypass/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 09:14:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/buypass/</guid><description>Working for a safer digital life Buypass was established in 2001, and has built up a unique environment of competence in the development of secure and user-friendly ID and payment solutions. Our solutions satisfy the strictest security requirements of private enterprise and government.
We provide a complete portfolio of services for identifying and encrypting information throughout the digital value chain. Buypass is also Norway&amp;rsquo;s only issuer of internationally approved SSL certificates and certificates according to eIDAS and PSD2.</description></item><item><title>D-Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/dtrust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 09:14:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/dtrust/</guid><description>About D-Trust Trust is a decisive factor for communication in the digital world and when transmitting sensitive data. As an independent and certified trust service provider, D-TRUST has been listed with the Federal Network Agency under the eIDAS Regulation since 2016. As a member of the Bundesdruckerei Group, the D-TRUST provides legally compliant and certified trust services that include digital certificates and electronic signatures. These services meet the highest security standards of modern infrastructures and enable secure digital identities for companies, public authorities and private individuals.</description></item><item><title>Entrust</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/entrust/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/entrust/</guid><description>Securing a World in Motion Since 1969 At Entrust, we’ve established secure connections across the planet and even into outer space. We’ve enabled reliable debit and credit card purchases with our card printing and issuance technologies. Protected international travel with our border control solutions. Created secure experiences on the internet with our SSL technologies. And safeguarded networks and devices with our suite of authentication products.
Founding member Back in 2013, Entrust was one of the seven CA&amp;rsquo;s who founded the CA Security Council.</description></item><item><title>Harica</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/harica/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/harica/</guid><description>What is HARICA ? HARICA is currently the only &amp;lsquo;Root CA Operator&amp;rsquo; in Greece that participates in all major Global &amp;lsquo;ROOT CA&amp;rsquo; Trust Programs (360, Adobe, Apple, Microsoft, Mozilla), and operates as a &amp;lsquo;Trust Anchor&amp;rsquo; in widely used Application Software and Operating Systems (Adobe, Apple, Google, Microsoft, Mozilla, Linux).
HARICA, is currently funded by Academic Network (GUnet), a non-profit civil company. Its members are all the Higher Education and Academic Institutions of Greece.</description></item><item><title>Sectigo</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/sectigo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/sectigo/</guid><description>A Seasoned Team of Industry Veterans The Sectigo executive team includes industry veterans from Comodo, VeriSign, Symantec, Entrust, and DigiCert, bringing more than 200 years of combined experience in the PKI industry as well as other technology spaces.
Global Organization Sectigo has offices located in North America, Europe, and Asia and supports customers in over 15 languages in nearly 200 countries. Thousands of enterprises worldwide rely on Sectigo to protect, monitor, recover, and manage their identities, web presence, and connected devices.</description></item><item><title>Secure Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/securetrust/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/securetrust/</guid><description>SecureTrust, the global leader in payment security and compliance We are the only company that can meet your organization’s end-to-end needs. Working with our team enables you to reduce costs and manage risks by better managing compliance requirements tailored to your needs and your environment.
While we are industry experts in Payment Card Industry (PCI) compliance, our team also delivers comprehensive expertise in risk management and regulatory compliance. Working with one team that understands the interplay between data privacy, compliance requirements, risk management and PCI is more streamlined and cost effective than anything our competitors can promise.</description></item><item><title>SSL.com</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/sslcom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/sslcom/</guid><description>Trust is What We Do SSL.com is a publicly-trusted commercial certificate authority expanding the boundaries of encryption and authentication relied upon by users worldwide. Founded in 2002, we have grown to be used in over 120 countries by leading organizations and governments of all sizes. We provide a wide range of digital certificates to fit any need, including SSL/TLS server certificates, code signing, document signing, and S/MIME email certificates. As a voting member of the CAB Forum, we provide unique, insightful preparation for our clients and partners into the future development of digital certificate technologies and policies.</description></item><item><title>Izenpe</title><link>https://pkic.org/members/izenpe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/members/izenpe/</guid><description>A certification and services company Izenpe is a public limited company incorporated in 2002 and is a project promoted by the Basque Government and the Provincial Councils, incorporated through its it companies: EJIE, LANTIK, IZFE and CCASA.
We are a Trust Service Provider, that is, an organization that provides electronic signature services. Electronic signatureing can be defined as a set of technical and legal procedures that allow to &amp;ldquo;replace&amp;rdquo; the conventional manual signature in order to be able to carry out through the Internet and the telephone procedures that before they had to be done in person.</description></item></channel></rss>