<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CAA on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/caa/</link><description>Recent content in CAA on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 14:30:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/caa/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to do HTTPS … The Right Way</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/06/02/how-to-do-https-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 14:30:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/06/02/how-to-do-https-the-right-way/</guid><description>With secure HTTP — aka HTTPS (the “S” is short for “secure”) — swiftly becoming universal on the Internet, it is important to know how to configure HTTPS for your website the right way. The payoff for properly securing your website has many benefits.</description></item><item><title>2018 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2017 2017 saw the end of SHA-1 in public trust SSL/TLS certificates and the start of Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) allowing domain owners to authorize their CA. A “Not secure” browser indication was propagated to push more websites to support HTTPS. There was also a change in the certification authority (CA) ownership with DigiCert acquiring Symantec’s SSL and related PKI business and Francisco Partners buying Comodo’s CA.</description></item><item><title>The Latest on Certification Authority Authorization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/03/21/the-latest-on-certification-authority-authorization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 20:40:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/03/21/the-latest-on-certification-authority-authorization/</guid><description>Things are certainly heating up at the CA/Browser with exciting proposals surrounding inclusion of the Wi-Fi Alliance (WFA) as a subjectAltName otherName, new validation methods, and debates over how the CAB Forum will continue operating. One of these newly passed ballots requires all CAs to check and process a domain name’s DNS Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) resource record prior to issuing a digital certificate.
Background RFC 6844 created CAA records as a method for domain owners to specify a policy on which certificate authorities are authorized to issue certificates for the associated domain.</description></item><item><title>2017 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 21:11:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2016 Fortunately, 2016 was not a year full of SSL/TLS vulnerabilities. Although some researchers did prove old cryptography algorithms should be put out to pasture. The year showed the end of public-trusted SHA-1 SSL/TLS certificates. It also showed more transparency should be considered due to issues discovered with a few certification authorities (CAs). The great news is HTTPS is no longer the minority — after 20 years, connections using HTTPS has surpassed HTTP.</description></item><item><title>2016 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2015 A number of new tactics proved 2015 was no exception to an active year defending against ever increasing security issues. Vendors found new and creative ways to provide vulnerabilities including the now popular man-in-the-middle (MitM) attacks. MitM as well as a host of other new vulnerabilities caused browsers to rethink their security requirements. This article gives a flashback of the exploits and industry changes from 2015 and looks ahead at the latest security requirements and how it impacts IT security teams.</description></item><item><title>Fighting the Good Fight for Online Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:47:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</guid><description>Once again Browsers and Certificate Authorities are in the news over the reported mis-issuance of an SSL server certificate to a google.com domain. Discovered by Google most likely via technology known as key pinning and discussed by Google’s Adam Langley in this blog, a Chinese certificate authority, CNNIC (Chinese Internet Network Information Center), apparently issued an intermediate certificate to an Egyptian company called MCS Holdings. Because the CNNIC root certificate is included in the root store of most major browsers, users would not see any warnings on sites that have certificates issued by CNNIC or MCS Holdings.</description></item><item><title>2015 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2014 End of 1024-Bit Security In 2014, the SSL industry moved to issuing a minimum security of 2048-bit RSA certificates. Keys smaller than 2048 are no longer allowed in server certificates. In addition, Microsoft and Mozilla started to remove 1024-bit roots from their certificate stores. Hopefully, the key size change will support users through to 2030.
Push to Perfect Forward Secrecy Following the Edward Snowden revelations of pervasive surveillance, there was a big push to configure web servers to support Perfect Forward Secrecy.</description></item><item><title>In the Wake of Unauthorized Certificate Issuance by the Indian CA NIC, can Government CAs Still be Considered “Trusted Third Parties”?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</guid><description>Short answer: Government CAs can still be considered “trusted third parties,” provided that they follow the rules applicable to commercial CAs.
Introduction On July 8 Google announced that it had discovered several unauthorized Google certificates issued by the National Informatics Centre of India. It noted that the Indian government CA’s certificates were in the Microsoft Root Store and used by programs on the Windows platform. The Firefox browser on Windows uses its own root store and didn’t have these CA certificates.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Members Presentation at RSA 2014 Conference: New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</guid><description>CA Security Council (CASC) members Trend Micro, Go Daddy, and Symantec participated in a discussion panel at the 2014 RSA Conference in San Francisco on February 24 entitled “New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet.” Panel members included Kirk Hall of Trend Micro (Moderator), Wayne Thayer of GoDaddy (Panelist), and Rick Andrews of Symantec (Panelist).
Introduction to the Topic Hall began by introducing the topic – all three alternative technologies (Certificate Transparency or CT, Certificate Authority Authorization or CAA, and Certificate Pinning) are intended to make the internet safer by dealing with mis-issued digital certificates, including so-called “rogue” certs like those obtained by a hacker from the now-defunct Diginotar Certification Authority (CA).</description></item><item><title>2014 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 20:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2013 Protocol Attacks The year started with a couple of SSL/TLS protocol attacks: Lucky Thirteen and RC4 attack. Lucky Thirteen allows the decryption of sensitive information, such as passwords and cookies, when using the CBC-mode cipher suite. Lucky Thirteen can be mitigated by implementing software patches or preferring the cipher suite RC4.
That being said, RC4 was also attacked, where through 16 million sessions a small amount of plaintext can be recovered.</description></item><item><title>What is Certification Authority Authorization?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/25/what-is-certification-authority-authorization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 17:00:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/25/what-is-certification-authority-authorization/</guid><description>DNS Certification Authority Authorization (CAA), defined in IETF draft RFC 6844, is designed to allow a DNS domain name holder (a website owner) to specify the certificate signing certificate(s) authorized to issue certificates for that domain or website. Usually, the certificate signing certificate will belong to the Certification Authority (CA) that issues SSL certificates to you. It’s a way for you to indicate which CA or CAs you want to issue certificates for your domains.</description></item></channel></rss>