<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EV on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/ev/</link><description>Recent content in EV on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:18:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/ev/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don’t ‘Compromise’ Your Code Amid Malware Mayhem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/05/12/dont-compromise-your-code-amid-malware-mayhem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:18:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/05/12/dont-compromise-your-code-amid-malware-mayhem/</guid><description>Code Signing Certificates demand a price premium in the underground online marketplace. This is no surprise considering that criminals sometimes use them to dupe their potential victims into installing malware in their machine.</description></item><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>Online Identity Is Important: Let’s Upgrade Extended Validation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/10/21/online-identity-is-important-lets-upgrade-extended-validation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 18:11:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/10/21/online-identity-is-important-lets-upgrade-extended-validation/</guid><description>It’s time for the CA/Browser Forum to focus on the other half of its mandate Let’s have a candid discussion about Extended Validation SSL. What’s working. What’s NOT. And what can be done to fix it so that all parties involved are satisfied.
But first, let’s zoom out and talk big picture. The vast majority of website owners almost never think of SSL. They worry about it once every year or so when it needs to be replaced, but it’s not really a major point of consideration.</description></item><item><title>The Insecure Elephant in the Room</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/10/10/the-insecure-elephant-in-the-room/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:52:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/10/10/the-insecure-elephant-in-the-room/</guid><description>The purpose of this article The purpose of this article is to demonstrate why I believe browser-based UI for website identity can make the web safer for everyone. I explain in great detail, the reasons why the UI and UX didn’t work in the past. And what’s left is only making the problem worse instead of better.
Some people seem to find it difficult to consume my thoughts about the enforcement of “HTTPS EVERYWHERE”, free DV certs and the browser padlock.</description></item><item><title>Why Are You Removing Website Identity, Google and Mozilla?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/27/why-are-you-removing-website-identity-google-and-mozilla/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/27/why-are-you-removing-website-identity-google-and-mozilla/</guid><description>You can’t have consumer privacy without having strong website identity Today there’s a huge wave toward protecting consumer privacy – in Congress, with the GDPR, etc. – but how can we protect user privacy on the web without establishing the identity of the websites that are asking for consumer passwords and credit card numbers? Extended Validation (EV) certificates provide this information and can be very useful for consumers.
Recently, Google and Mozilla have announced plan to eliminate the distinctive indicators in the Chrome and Firefox browsers that let consumers know that they are looking at a site authenticated with an EV certificate.</description></item><item><title>What Are Subordinate CAs and Why Would You Want Your Own?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</guid><description>Digital certificate and PKI adoption has changed quite a bit in recent years. Gone are the days where certificates were only synonymous with SSL/TLS; compliance drivers like stronger authentication requirements and digital signature regulations (e.g. eIDAS) have greatly expanded the role of PKI within the enterprise.
As PKI usage has expanded, conversation has moved beyond just the number and type of certificates needed and onto deeper dialogue about custom PKI deployments.</description></item><item><title>What the Latest Firefox Update Means for SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/14/what-the-latest-firefox-update-means-for-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 18:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/14/what-the-latest-firefox-update-means-for-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Last month marked the release of Firefox 66, the newest iteration of the ever-popular web browser. The update adds a number of interesting new features, including improvements to content loading and extension storage, auto-play sound blocking, and support for the AV1 codec (on the Windows version at least). The search feature has also been improved, and, as is typical of browser updates, a number of known security vulnerabilities have been patched.</description></item><item><title>2019 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2018 2018 was an active year for SSL/TLS. We saw the SSL/TLS certificate validity period drop to 825-days and the mass deployment of Certificate Transparency (CT). TLS 1.3 protocol was finally completed and published; and Chrome status bar security indicators changing to remove “secure” and to concentrate on “not secure.” The CA/Browser Forum has been reformed, the London Protocol was announced and the nearly full distrust of Symantec SSL completed.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 18:07:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>As the legendary coach of the NY Yankees Yogi Berra allegedly said, “It’s difficult to make predictions, especially about the future.” But we’re going to try.
Here are the CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly.
The Good Prediction: By the end of 2019, over 90% of the world’s http traffic will be secured over SSL/TLS
Encryption boosts user security and privacy, and the combined efforts of browsers and Certification Authorities (CAs) over the past few years have moved us rapidly to a world approaching 100% encryption.</description></item><item><title>CASC Announces Launch of London Protocol to Improve Identity Assurance and Minimize Phishing on Identity Websites</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</guid><description>LONDON – (June 27, 2018) – The Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of the security of websites and online transactions, announced at the CA/Browser Forum event in London the launch of the London Protocol – an initiative to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted with organization validated (OV) and extended validation (EV) certificates, which contain organization identity information (Identity Certificates).</description></item><item><title>The London Protocol</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/the-london-protocol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/the-london-protocol/</guid><description>The objective of The London Protocol is to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted by OV (organization validated) and EV (extended validation) certificates (together referred to as “Identity Websites”). The London Protocol reinforces the distinction between Identity Websites making them even more secure for users than websites encrypted by DV (domain validated) certificates. That security feature can then be utilized by others for their own security purposes, including informing users as to the type of website they are visiting and use by antiphishing engines and browser filters in their security algorithms.</description></item><item><title>How Browser Security Indicators Can Protect You from Phishing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/06/06/how-browser-security-indicators-can-protect-you-from-phishing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 14:04:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/06/06/how-browser-security-indicators-can-protect-you-from-phishing/</guid><description>The media is full of stories about how phishing sites are moving rapidly to encryption using anonymous, free DV certificates they use to imitate login pages for popular sites, such as paypal.com.
As noted in the article PayPal Phishing Certificates Far More Prevalent than Previously Thought, more than 14,000 DV SSL certificates have been issued to PayPal phishing sites since the start of 2016. Based on a random sample, 96.</description></item><item><title>Google Certificate Transparency (CT) to Expand to All Certificates Types</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/11/08/google-certificate-transparency-ct-to-expand-to-all-certificates-types/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 17:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/11/08/google-certificate-transparency-ct-to-expand-to-all-certificates-types/</guid><description>The policy change goes into effect October 2017 A recent Google announcement stated that all publicly trusted SSL/TLS certificates issued in October 2017 or later will be expected to comply with Chrome’s Certificate Transparency (CT) policy or be untrusted by the browser.
Since January 2015, Chrome has required Extended Validation (EV) certificates to comply with CT. With this policy change, the Chrome CT policy will also apply to Domain Validated (DV) and Organization Validated (OV) certificates.</description></item><item><title>Why Is Certificate Expiration Necessary?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/10/19/why-is-certificate-expiration-necessary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 16:26:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/10/19/why-is-certificate-expiration-necessary/</guid><description>The Long Life Certificate – Why It Doesn’t Exist Why is certificate expiration even necessary? Wouldn’t it be better if I could just buy a certificate with a long life before expiration? It would really simplify certificate management if it could be installed and forgotten. Simple, no management required, just file-and-forget.
Imagine, I’ve been in business, starting say 10 to 15 years ago. I roll out my web pages and secure them with a 20-year-validity SSL certificate.</description></item><item><title>Trust Indication Change in Google Chrome</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/08/24/trust-indication-change-in-google-chrome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 15:52:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/08/24/trust-indication-change-in-google-chrome/</guid><description>Google is making security icon changes in the Chrome status bar. The changes are based on a research paper prepared by members of Google and University of California, Berkeley. The research evaluated forty icons, seven complementary strings and surveyed 1,329 people.
The goal is to make it easier for browser users to determine how secure their connection to a site is and indicate if the site is dangerous or deceptive. In addition, the icons are to indicate to people that HTTP is less secure than HTTPS.</description></item><item><title>TLS Certificates on the Web – The Good, The Bad and The Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/05/17/tls-certificates-on-the-web-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/05/17/tls-certificates-on-the-web-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>It might be hard to believe, but the SSL/TLS Ecosystem is nearly 20 years old. It’s time to take stock and see how we’re doing with regards to TLS certificates. In this article, we’ll primarily discuss certificates themselves and not web server configuration, although that is often a source of problems.
In the last few years, we’ve endured three major certificate-based migrations:
Away from the MD2 and MD5 hash algorithms to SHA-1 Away from small RSA keys to 2048-bit keys or larger Away from the SHA-1 hash algorithm to SHA-256 What’s driving these migrations?</description></item><item><title>What Kind of SSL/TLS Certificate do You Need?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/05/12/what-kind-of-ssl/tls-certificate-do-you-need/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/05/12/what-kind-of-ssl/tls-certificate-do-you-need/</guid><description>In previous blog posts we have discussed the differences among the various types of SSL/TLS certificates available. In this blog post we introduce you to a new infographic that has a decision tree to help you select the right kind of certificate for your needs. In most cases you will need a publicly trusted certificate, but the decision tree notes that one type of certificate is the private trust certificate, which can be obtained and used in situations where a publicly trusted certificate cannot be used.</description></item><item><title>Stay Safe This Tax Season by Looking for SSL/TLS Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/03/30/stay-safe-this-tax-season-by-looking-for-ssl/tls-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 16:05:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/03/30/stay-safe-this-tax-season-by-looking-for-ssl/tls-certificates/</guid><description>It’s tax filing season again, and you need to be aware of scams that tried to steal your sensitive information or even your tax refund. During 2015 the IRS blocked over 4.3 million suspicious returns and more than 1.4 million confirmed identity theft returns. https://www.irs.gov/uac/Newsroom/IRS,-States-and-Tax-Industry-Combat-Identity-Theft-and-Refund-Fraud-on-Many-Fronts.
Phishing emails, account compromise, identity theft, and fake websites are a few approaches used by cyber criminals this time of year. Good computer security hygiene will usually protect you from someone else filing a tax return in your name.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Report: Consumers Don’t Know Much About Security, But They Trust the Padlock and Green Bar When Shopping Online</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/13/ca-security-council-report-consumers-dont-know-much-about-security-but-they-trust-the-padlock-and-green-bar-when-shopping-online/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/13/ca-security-council-report-consumers-dont-know-much-about-security-but-they-trust-the-padlock-and-green-bar-when-shopping-online/</guid><description>San Francisco – April 13, 2015 – The CA Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of the security of websites and online transactions, today released its 2015 Consumer Trust Survey which found that validation matters. While consumers are confused about some aspects of security, they recognize and trust the security that SSL brings to e-commerce sites. Fifty-three percent of respondents identify the padlock as adding confidence in an e-commerce site, with 42 percent associating the green bar and organization name in the URL with greater safety.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Deploys Certificate Reputation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/09/microsoft-deploys-certificate-reputation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 19:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/09/microsoft-deploys-certificate-reputation/</guid><description>As we have stated previously, website owners have a concern that an attacker can have a certificate issued for their domain name. We now have two systems which will help monitor certificates for domains: Certificate Transparency (CT) and Certificate Reputation.
At the start of 2015, most certification authorities (CAs) support CT as requested by Google. CT works for extended validation (EV) SSL certificates and will allow all EV certificates to be monitored.</description></item><item><title>My Website’s SSL Certificate is Fine; Why Do Browsers Downgrade the Security Indicators For My Site?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/01/my-websites-ssl-certificate-is-fine-why-do-browsers-downgrade-the-security-indicators-for-my-site/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 16:19:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/01/my-websites-ssl-certificate-is-fine-why-do-browsers-downgrade-the-security-indicators-for-my-site/</guid><description>All the major browsers provide “security user interface”, meaning visual elements to inform the user of the security of their connection to the web page they’re visiting. Up until now, those interface elements were tied to the use of SSL/TLS certificates served by the web site. For example, if you went to http://www.example.com, no special elements would be displayed, but if you visited https://www.example.com, you would see a lock icon indicating the presence of a trusted SSL/TLS certificate.</description></item><item><title>2015 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2014 End of 1024-Bit Security In 2014, the SSL industry moved to issuing a minimum security of 2048-bit RSA certificates. Keys smaller than 2048 are no longer allowed in server certificates. In addition, Microsoft and Mozilla started to remove 1024-bit roots from their certificate stores. Hopefully, the key size change will support users through to 2030.
Push to Perfect Forward Secrecy Following the Edward Snowden revelations of pervasive surveillance, there was a big push to configure web servers to support Perfect Forward Secrecy.</description></item><item><title>Who Sets the Rules Governing Certification Authorities?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 15:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</guid><description>Every time something positive is published about SSL and encryption,such as Google’s recent decision making use of https encryption a favorable rating factor for a website, or negative, such as the Heartbleed issue – bloggers and others always post questions about public Certification Authorities (CAs), including general questions on who sets the rules that govern CAs. Some bloggers seem to assume there are no rules or standards, and that CAs can operate without any requirements or limitations at all — that’s incorrect.</description></item><item><title>When to Choose an Extended Validation Certificate</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/25/when-to-choose-an-extended-validation-certificate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/25/when-to-choose-an-extended-validation-certificate/</guid><description>In our last post, we made a case for using Organizationally Validated (OV) or Extended Validation (EV) certificates for e-commerce, but we didn’t go into detail about the differences between OV and EV. EV certificates provide the highest level of assurance about your business, and they visually indicate this to your site’s visitors.
The telltale sign that a business has obtained an EV certificate for their website is commonly referred to as the “green bar” displayed in the browser.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Members Presentation at RSA 2014 Conference: New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</guid><description>CA Security Council (CASC) members Trend Micro, Go Daddy, and Symantec participated in a discussion panel at the 2014 RSA Conference in San Francisco on February 24 entitled “New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet.” Panel members included Kirk Hall of Trend Micro (Moderator), Wayne Thayer of GoDaddy (Panelist), and Rick Andrews of Symantec (Panelist).
Introduction to the Topic Hall began by introducing the topic – all three alternative technologies (Certificate Transparency or CT, Certificate Authority Authorization or CAA, and Certificate Pinning) are intended to make the internet safer by dealing with mis-issued digital certificates, including so-called “rogue” certs like those obtained by a hacker from the now-defunct Diginotar Certification Authority (CA).</description></item><item><title>Think Twice Before Using DV for E-Commerce</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/12/think-twice-before-using-dv-for-e-commerce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 19:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/12/think-twice-before-using-dv-for-e-commerce/</guid><description>In a previous blog (What Are the Different Types of SSL Certificates?), we described the various types of SSL certificates available from publicly trusted Certificate Authorities (CAs). CAs are often asked by their customers which certificate type should be used for websites conducting E-Commerce, rather than for just encryption of sensitive data. For the latter case, a Domain Validated (DV) certificate will work fine. A DV cert allows for encryption to take place between the browser and the server.</description></item><item><title>CA Day in Berlin</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/24/ca-day-in-berlin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 18:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/24/ca-day-in-berlin/</guid><description>“CA Day” (also known as CA Conformity Assessment) was hosted by the German company TuVIT in Berlin on January 16, 2014. In attendance were approximately 100 people from mostly European CAs. Under the European regulatory framework, CAs are included in a group referred to as “Trust Service Providers” or “TSPs.” CASC members in attendance at CA Day were Symantec, Digicert and Comodo. The dominant theme for this CA Day was the draft Regulation on Electronic identification and trust services for electronic transactions in the internal market (eIDAS) and upcoming changes in EU regulations for Qualified Certificates, which was briefed by Gerard Galler from the European Commission and discussed in greater detail by several European TSPs.</description></item><item><title>How Organizations Are Authenticated for SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/22/how-organizations-are-authenticated-for-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/22/how-organizations-are-authenticated-for-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Certification Authorities (CAs) are trusted third parties that authenticate customers before issuing SSL certificates to secure their servers.
Exactly how do CAs authenticate these organizations? And where are the rules that determine what CAs must do during authentication?
The Rules on Customer Authentication In the past, there were no common rules applicable to CAs as to minimum steps required to authenticate a customer before issuing an SSL certificate. Instead, each CA was permitted to create its own authentication processes, and was only required to describe the process in general terms in its public Certification Practice Statement (CPS).</description></item><item><title>Certificate Authority Audits and Browser Root Program Requirements</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/10/15/certificate-authority-audits-and-browser-root-program-requirements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/10/15/certificate-authority-audits-and-browser-root-program-requirements/</guid><description>Recent news stories have highlighted the need for strong security in online communications, and use of SSL certificates issued by a publicly trusted Certification Authority (CA) is perhaps the best way to achieve that. But why should the public trust SSL certificates issued from commercial CA roots, which are embedded as trust anchors in web browsers?
One answer is because of the multiple layers of standards and tough requirements that all commercial CAs must meet – and for which they are audited every year.</description></item><item><title>Firefox 23 Blocks Mixed Content</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/08/13/firefox-23-blocks-mixed-content/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 17:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/08/13/firefox-23-blocks-mixed-content/</guid><description>The latest version of the Firefox Web browser from Mozilla was released on August 6th with a great new security feature called a “mixed content blocker”. In a nutshell, this feature ensures that all of the parts of a secure Website are indeed encrypted via SSL certificates. All of the data on the website is prevented from being intercepted, and it becomes more difficult to add malware into the site’s content.</description></item></channel></rss>