<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Forward Secrecy on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/forward-secrecy/</link><description>Recent content in Forward Secrecy on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/forward-secrecy/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>2019 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2018 2018 was an active year for SSL/TLS. We saw the SSL/TLS certificate validity period drop to 825-days and the mass deployment of Certificate Transparency (CT). TLS 1.3 protocol was finally completed and published; and Chrome status bar security indicators changing to remove “secure” and to concentrate on “not secure.” The CA/Browser Forum has been reformed, the London Protocol was announced and the nearly full distrust of Symantec SSL completed.</description></item><item><title>TLS 1.3 Includes Improvements to Security and Performance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/04/10/tls-1.3-includes-improvements-to-security-and-performance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 17:55:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/04/10/tls-1.3-includes-improvements-to-security-and-performance/</guid><description>Last month saw the final adoption, after 4 years of work, of TLS version 1.3 by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF). This latest iteration of the protocol for secure communications on the internet boasts several noteworthy improvements to both security and performance:
Security All cipher suites that do not provide forward secrecy have been eliminated from TLS 1.3. This is a very important security property, because without forward secrecy, if a server’s private key is compromised today, any previously-recorded conversations with that server dating back as long as the key was in use could be decrypted.</description></item><item><title>Stricter Standards for SSL Server Test Coming in 2017</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/13/stricter-standards-for-ssl-server-test-coming-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 16:32:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/13/stricter-standards-for-ssl-server-test-coming-in-2017/</guid><description>This is a good time to offer a reminder that the CASC has a great tool for secure server testing, the SSL Server Test. The tool grades your server installation and reviews the: certificate, protocol support, key exchange and cipher strength for security against standards and known vulnerabilities.
The grading tool also provides feedback on handshake simulations with various versions of browsers and operating systems. This lets the server administrator know which implementations are supported.</description></item><item><title>HTTP/2 Is Speedy and Secure</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/20/http/2-is-speedy-and-secure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/20/http/2-is-speedy-and-secure/</guid><description>Since we last wrote about SSL/TLS performance, there has been a lot of activity in the IETF HTTP Working Group, resulting in the February announcement that the next version of HTTP has been approved. This is big news because it means that major SSL/TLS performance improvements are on the way.
Background When your browser connects to a website today, it most likely uses the HTTP/1.1 protocol that was defined in 1999 in RFC 2616.</description></item><item><title>Is Your SSL Server Vulnerable to a FREAK Attack?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/03/11/is-your-ssl-server-vulnerable-to-a-freak-attack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 16:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/03/11/is-your-ssl-server-vulnerable-to-a-freak-attack/</guid><description>FREAK is a new man-in-the-middle (MITM) vulnerability discovered by a group of cryptographers at INRIA, Microsoft Research and IMDEA. FREAK stands for “Factoring RSA-EXPORT Keys.”
The vulnerability dates back to the 1990s, when the US government banned selling crypto software overseas, unless it used export cipher suites which involved encryption keys no longer than 512-bits.
The issue is there are still some clients who let crypto be degraded from “strong RSA” to “export grade RSA”.</description></item><item><title>2015 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2014 End of 1024-Bit Security In 2014, the SSL industry moved to issuing a minimum security of 2048-bit RSA certificates. Keys smaller than 2048 are no longer allowed in server certificates. In addition, Microsoft and Mozilla started to remove 1024-bit roots from their certificate stores. Hopefully, the key size change will support users through to 2030.
Push to Perfect Forward Secrecy Following the Edward Snowden revelations of pervasive surveillance, there was a big push to configure web servers to support Perfect Forward Secrecy.</description></item><item><title>Extra Trips are for Frequent Flyers, Not SSL/TLS Performance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/10/30/extra-trips-are-for-frequent-flyers-not-ssl/tls-performance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 16:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/10/30/extra-trips-are-for-frequent-flyers-not-ssl/tls-performance/</guid><description>TLS is quickly becoming a de facto requirement for every website due to increased concerns about spying and Google’s recent move to use HTTPS as a factor in search engine ranking. In a recent article we explained how HSTS helps website operators to ensure that their site is always using TLS, but now we want to ensure that your performance isn’t sacrificed in the name of enhanced security. While the myth that TLS slows down a website has been debunked, some basic settings can make a site using TLS even faster.</description></item><item><title>Perfect Forward Secrecy</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/11/perfect-forward-secrecy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/11/perfect-forward-secrecy/</guid><description>Recent revelations from Edward Snowden about pervasive government surveillance have led to many questions about the safety of communications using the SSL/TLS protocol. Such communications are generally safe from eavesdroppers, as long as certain precautions are observed. For example, configuring your web server to avoid using SSL2 and SSL3, favoring newer versions of TLS like TLS 1.2, selecting strong ciphersuites, etc.
But even if your server is configured properly, you still must secure the private key associated with your SSL certificate.</description></item><item><title>Reducing the Impact of Government Spying</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/04/reducing-the-impact-of-government-spying/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/04/reducing-the-impact-of-government-spying/</guid><description>Last year, Edward Snowden, an American computer-specialist working as a contractor for the National Security Agency (“NSA”), shocked web-users around the world by publicizing documents showing that the NSA was gathering intelligence on Internet users. The realization that the US government was gathering sensitive information has led to a worldwide demand for better protection of online communication and data and a general worry about the effectiveness of existing infrastructures. Specifically, some entities have asked whether PKI is still a robust way to protect online information.</description></item><item><title>2014 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 20:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2013 Protocol Attacks The year started with a couple of SSL/TLS protocol attacks: Lucky Thirteen and RC4 attack. Lucky Thirteen allows the decryption of sensitive information, such as passwords and cookies, when using the CBC-mode cipher suite. Lucky Thirteen can be mitigated by implementing software patches or preferring the cipher suite RC4.
That being said, RC4 was also attacked, where through 16 million sessions a small amount of plaintext can be recovered.</description></item><item><title>IETF 88 – Pervasive Surveillance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/26/ietf-88-pervasive-surveillance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 19:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/26/ietf-88-pervasive-surveillance/</guid><description>Internet Surveillance The big news at IETF 88 in Vancouver was the technical plenary on Hardening the Internet which discussed the issue of pervasive surveillance. Pervasive surveillance is a mass surveillance of an entire or a substantial fraction of a population. The surveillance is usually carried out by government, is not targeted and its occurrence may not be overt. It was noted that pervasive surveillance, of the kind revealed in the Snowden-sourced documents, constitutes a misguided and damaging attack on civic society in general and the Internet in particular.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2: Configuration</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 01:19:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</guid><description>They say the most complicated skill is to be simple; despite SSL and HTTPS having been around for a long time, they still are not as simple as they could be.
One of the reasons for this is that the security industry is constantly learning more about how to design and build secure systems; as a result, the protocols and software used to secure online services need to continuously evolve to keep up with the latest risks.</description></item></channel></rss>