<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tim Callan on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/authors/tim-callan/</link><description>Recent content in Tim Callan on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:48:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/authors/tim-callan/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Are You Removing Website Identity, Google and Mozilla?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/27/why-are-you-removing-website-identity-google-and-mozilla/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/27/why-are-you-removing-website-identity-google-and-mozilla/</guid><description>You can’t have consumer privacy without having strong website identity Today there’s a huge wave toward protecting consumer privacy – in Congress, with the GDPR, etc. – but how can we protect user privacy on the web without establishing the identity of the websites that are asking for consumer passwords and credit card numbers? Extended Validation (EV) certificates provide this information and can be very useful for consumers.
Recently, Google and Mozilla have announced plan to eliminate the distinctive indicators in the Chrome and Firefox browsers that let consumers know that they are looking at a site authenticated with an EV certificate.</description></item><item><title>9 Common Myths About CAs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</guid><description>Over the years misconceptions about CAs and the SSL infrastructure have arisen. Below is a list of common myths related to SSL and CAs.
Myth #1: CAs are not regulated Fact: CAs are subject to various checks and balances, including third-party qualified audits through WebTrust or ETSI and strict criteria set forth by leading browsers, before they are accepted in browser root stores. Similarly, the CA/Browser Forum’s Baseline Requirements and Network Security Guidelines establish global standards for certificate issuance and CA controls that will soon be included in third-party auditing standards.</description></item><item><title>What the Latest Firefox Update Means for SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/14/what-the-latest-firefox-update-means-for-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 18:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/14/what-the-latest-firefox-update-means-for-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Last month marked the release of Firefox 66, the newest iteration of the ever-popular web browser. The update adds a number of interesting new features, including improvements to content loading and extension storage, auto-play sound blocking, and support for the AV1 codec (on the Windows version at least). The search feature has also been improved, and, as is typical of browser updates, a number of known security vulnerabilities have been patched.</description></item></channel></rss>