<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DV on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/dv/</link><description>Recent content in DV on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/dv/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Year Certs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</guid><description>Starting on September 1st, SSL/TLS certificates cannot be issued for longer than 13 months (397 days). This change was first announced by Apple at the CA/Browser Forum Spring Face-to-Face event in Bratislava back in March.</description></item><item><title>The Insecure Elephant in the Room</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/10/10/the-insecure-elephant-in-the-room/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:52:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/10/10/the-insecure-elephant-in-the-room/</guid><description>The purpose of this article The purpose of this article is to demonstrate why I believe browser-based UI for website identity can make the web safer for everyone. I explain in great detail, the reasons why the UI and UX didn’t work in the past. And what’s left is only making the problem worse instead of better.
Some people seem to find it difficult to consume my thoughts about the enforcement of “HTTPS EVERYWHERE”, free DV certs and the browser padlock.</description></item><item><title>Why Are You Removing Website Identity, Google and Mozilla?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/27/why-are-you-removing-website-identity-google-and-mozilla/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/27/why-are-you-removing-website-identity-google-and-mozilla/</guid><description>You can’t have consumer privacy without having strong website identity Today there’s a huge wave toward protecting consumer privacy – in Congress, with the GDPR, etc. – but how can we protect user privacy on the web without establishing the identity of the websites that are asking for consumer passwords and credit card numbers? Extended Validation (EV) certificates provide this information and can be very useful for consumers.
Recently, Google and Mozilla have announced plan to eliminate the distinctive indicators in the Chrome and Firefox browsers that let consumers know that they are looking at a site authenticated with an EV certificate.</description></item><item><title>2019 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2018 2018 was an active year for SSL/TLS. We saw the SSL/TLS certificate validity period drop to 825-days and the mass deployment of Certificate Transparency (CT). TLS 1.3 protocol was finally completed and published; and Chrome status bar security indicators changing to remove “secure” and to concentrate on “not secure.” The CA/Browser Forum has been reformed, the London Protocol was announced and the nearly full distrust of Symantec SSL completed.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 18:07:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>As the legendary coach of the NY Yankees Yogi Berra allegedly said, “It’s difficult to make predictions, especially about the future.” But we’re going to try.
Here are the CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly.
The Good Prediction: By the end of 2019, over 90% of the world’s http traffic will be secured over SSL/TLS
Encryption boosts user security and privacy, and the combined efforts of browsers and Certification Authorities (CAs) over the past few years have moved us rapidly to a world approaching 100% encryption.</description></item><item><title>CASC Announces Launch of London Protocol to Improve Identity Assurance and Minimize Phishing on Identity Websites</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</guid><description>LONDON – (June 27, 2018) – The Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of the security of websites and online transactions, announced at the CA/Browser Forum event in London the launch of the London Protocol – an initiative to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted with organization validated (OV) and extended validation (EV) certificates, which contain organization identity information (Identity Certificates).</description></item><item><title>The London Protocol</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/the-london-protocol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/the-london-protocol/</guid><description>The objective of The London Protocol is to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted by OV (organization validated) and EV (extended validation) certificates (together referred to as “Identity Websites”). The London Protocol reinforces the distinction between Identity Websites making them even more secure for users than websites encrypted by DV (domain validated) certificates. That security feature can then be utilized by others for their own security purposes, including informing users as to the type of website they are visiting and use by antiphishing engines and browser filters in their security algorithms.</description></item><item><title>How Browser Security Indicators Can Protect You from Phishing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/06/06/how-browser-security-indicators-can-protect-you-from-phishing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 14:04:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/06/06/how-browser-security-indicators-can-protect-you-from-phishing/</guid><description>The media is full of stories about how phishing sites are moving rapidly to encryption using anonymous, free DV certificates they use to imitate login pages for popular sites, such as paypal.com.
As noted in the article PayPal Phishing Certificates Far More Prevalent than Previously Thought, more than 14,000 DV SSL certificates have been issued to PayPal phishing sites since the start of 2016. Based on a random sample, 96.</description></item><item><title>Google Certificate Transparency (CT) to Expand to All Certificates Types</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/11/08/google-certificate-transparency-ct-to-expand-to-all-certificates-types/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 17:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/11/08/google-certificate-transparency-ct-to-expand-to-all-certificates-types/</guid><description>The policy change goes into effect October 2017 A recent Google announcement stated that all publicly trusted SSL/TLS certificates issued in October 2017 or later will be expected to comply with Chrome’s Certificate Transparency (CT) policy or be untrusted by the browser.
Since January 2015, Chrome has required Extended Validation (EV) certificates to comply with CT. With this policy change, the Chrome CT policy will also apply to Domain Validated (DV) and Organization Validated (OV) certificates.</description></item><item><title>What Kind of SSL/TLS Certificate do You Need?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/05/12/what-kind-of-ssl/tls-certificate-do-you-need/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/05/12/what-kind-of-ssl/tls-certificate-do-you-need/</guid><description>In previous blog posts we have discussed the differences among the various types of SSL/TLS certificates available. In this blog post we introduce you to a new infographic that has a decision tree to help you select the right kind of certificate for your needs. In most cases you will need a publicly trusted certificate, but the decision tree notes that one type of certificate is the private trust certificate, which can be obtained and used in situations where a publicly trusted certificate cannot be used.</description></item><item><title>Who Sets the Rules Governing Certification Authorities?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 15:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</guid><description>Every time something positive is published about SSL and encryption,such as Google’s recent decision making use of https encryption a favorable rating factor for a website, or negative, such as the Heartbleed issue – bloggers and others always post questions about public Certification Authorities (CAs), including general questions on who sets the rules that govern CAs. Some bloggers seem to assume there are no rules or standards, and that CAs can operate without any requirements or limitations at all — that’s incorrect.</description></item><item><title>Think Twice Before Using DV for E-Commerce</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/12/think-twice-before-using-dv-for-e-commerce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 19:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/12/think-twice-before-using-dv-for-e-commerce/</guid><description>In a previous blog (What Are the Different Types of SSL Certificates?), we described the various types of SSL certificates available from publicly trusted Certificate Authorities (CAs). CAs are often asked by their customers which certificate type should be used for websites conducting E-Commerce, rather than for just encryption of sensitive data. For the latter case, a Domain Validated (DV) certificate will work fine. A DV cert allows for encryption to take place between the browser and the server.</description></item><item><title>How Organizations Are Authenticated for SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/22/how-organizations-are-authenticated-for-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/22/how-organizations-are-authenticated-for-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Certification Authorities (CAs) are trusted third parties that authenticate customers before issuing SSL certificates to secure their servers.
Exactly how do CAs authenticate these organizations? And where are the rules that determine what CAs must do during authentication?
The Rules on Customer Authentication In the past, there were no common rules applicable to CAs as to minimum steps required to authenticate a customer before issuing an SSL certificate. Instead, each CA was permitted to create its own authentication processes, and was only required to describe the process in general terms in its public Certification Practice Statement (CPS).</description></item><item><title>What Are the Different Types of SSL Certificates?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/08/07/what-are-the-different-types-of-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 18:18:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/08/07/what-are-the-different-types-of-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Domain Validation (DV) A Domain Validated SSL certificate is issued after proof that the owner has the right to use their domain is established. This is typically done by the CA sending an email to the domain owner (as listed in a WHOIS database). Once the owner responds, the certificate is issued. Many CAs perform additional fraud checks to minimize issuance of a certificate to a domain which may be similar to a high value domain (i.</description></item><item><title>Self-Signed Certificates Don’t Deliver Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/02/self-signed-certificates-dont-deliver-trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 20:48:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/02/self-signed-certificates-dont-deliver-trust/</guid><description>We’ve heard the argument that website operators could just use self-signed certificates. They are easy to issue and they are “free.” Before issuing self-signed certificates, it’s a good idea to examine the trust and security model. You should also compare self-signed certificates to the publicly trusted certification authority (CA) model; and then make your own decision.
Self-Signed Certificate Model Owner says who they are Owner issues on their own policy Owner is responsible for quality Owner may not follow industry guidelines Owner may not provide certificate status Compromised certificates may not be able to be revoked Owner is not audited Issuer of certificate may not be authorized by the domain owner Certificates may not be renewed if there are no reminders Self-signed certificate model does not provide trust and the browser provides a trust dialogue box to indicate such Publicly-Trusted CA-Signed Certificate Model CA verifies the owner of the domain and the certificate applicant CA operates to a policy in conformance with the requirements of the browser and operating system vendors.</description></item></channel></rss>