<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IETF on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/ietf/</link><description>Recent content in IETF on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:09:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/ietf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preparing for Quantum Computing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/04/21/preparing-for-quantum-computing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:09:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/04/21/preparing-for-quantum-computing/</guid><description>Quantum computing is advancing, and while experts are not sure when there will be a quantum computer powerful enough to break the RSA and ECC cryptographic algorithms that are currently in use, many are operating under the assumption that this can happen within a 10-15 year timeframe.</description></item><item><title>Public Key Pinning</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/08/28/public-key-pinning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 16:29:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/08/28/public-key-pinning/</guid><description>The current browser-certification authority (CA) trust model allows a website owner to obtain its SSL certificate from any one of a number of CAs. That flexibility also means that a certificate mis-issued by a CA other than the authorized CA chosen by the website owner, would also be accepted as trustworthy by browsers.
This problem was displayed most dramatically by the DigiNotar attack in 2011 and in a mistaken CA certificate issued by TURKTRUST in 2012.</description></item><item><title>Some Comments on Web Security</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/05/some-comments-on-web-security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 02:23:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/05/some-comments-on-web-security/</guid><description>Steve Johnson of the Mercury News posted an article on Web security and highlighted some of the issues.
The posted issues help to explain why we created the Certificate Authority Security Council. We want to determine the issues, have them addressed and provide awareness and education on the solutions. The CAs also work with the browsers and other experts in the industry to develop standards for all CAs to be audited against through the CA/Browser Forum.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to OCSP Multi-Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 21:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</guid><description>OCSP Stapling OCSP is a protocol used to check the validity of certificates to make sure they have not been revoked. OCSP is an alternative to Certificate Revocation Lists (CRLs). Since OCSP responses can be as small as a few hundred bytes, OCSP is particularly useful when the issuing CA has relatively big CRLs, as well as when the client has limited memory and processing power.
OCSP can also provide much more timely information than CRLs about the status of a certificate since the information is generally fetched more frequently.</description></item><item><title>IETF 86 – Web PKI Working Group</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:07:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</guid><description>At the IETF 86 meeting in Orlando last week, there was a working group meeting discussing the operations of the Web PKI. At the previous IETF 85 meeting a birds-of-a-feather was held to discuss the purpose of having such a group. The result of the meeting was an established group with the charter that states purposes such as:
Working group will work to improve the consistency of Web security behavior Address problems as seen by the end-users, certificate holders and CAs Describe how the Web PKI actually works Prepare documented deliverables as discussed below The meeting discussed the charter and the four following deliverables.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Revocation and OCSP Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</guid><description>Revocation As a body of global CAs, the CA Security Council is committed to educating server administrators, end-users and other interested parties about SSL enhancements and best practices that can better protect everyone. An important initiative that can make a practical difference right now is addressing easily implemented improvements to certificate status services that handle revocation of invalid or expired certificates, specifically the implementation of OCSP stapling.
What is certificate revocation?</description></item></channel></rss>