<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GDPR on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/gdpr/</link><description>Recent content in GDPR on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/gdpr/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>Why Are You Removing Website Identity, Google and Mozilla?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/27/why-are-you-removing-website-identity-google-and-mozilla/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/27/why-are-you-removing-website-identity-google-and-mozilla/</guid><description>You can’t have consumer privacy without having strong website identity Today there’s a huge wave toward protecting consumer privacy – in Congress, with the GDPR, etc. – but how can we protect user privacy on the web without establishing the identity of the websites that are asking for consumer passwords and credit card numbers? Extended Validation (EV) certificates provide this information and can be very useful for consumers.
Recently, Google and Mozilla have announced plan to eliminate the distinctive indicators in the Chrome and Firefox browsers that let consumers know that they are looking at a site authenticated with an EV certificate.</description></item></channel></rss>