<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code signing on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/code-signing/</link><description>Recent content in Code signing on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:18:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/code-signing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don’t ‘Compromise’ Your Code Amid Malware Mayhem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/05/12/dont-compromise-your-code-amid-malware-mayhem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:18:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/05/12/dont-compromise-your-code-amid-malware-mayhem/</guid><description>Code Signing Certificates demand a price premium in the underground online marketplace. This is no surprise considering that criminals sometimes use them to dupe their potential victims into installing malware in their machine.</description></item><item><title>Code Signing Baseline Requirements</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/10/20/code-signing-baseline-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/10/20/code-signing-baseline-requirements/</guid><description>Code signing certificates are used to sign software objects to authenticate that they originated from a verified source, allowing developers to avoid warnings commonly displayed by application software vendors such as Microsoft operating systems and Java. A fraudulent code signing certificate can wreak havoc on networks, spreading malware and adware without restraint. Certificate Authorities are tasked with ensuring that code signing applicants are legitimate entities and provide accountability for use of the certificate.</description></item><item><title>Securing Software Distribution with Digital Code Signing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/10/16/securing-software-distribution-with-digital-code-signing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 18:16:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/10/16/securing-software-distribution-with-digital-code-signing/</guid><description>Code signing certificates from publicly trusted Certification Authorities (CAs) fulfill a vital need for authentication of software distributed over the Internet in our interconnected world. As the commonly referred to “Internet of things” continues to grow, consumers have access to millions of applications for their desktops, laptops, and mobile devices. Creative software engineers provide us with applications to cover any of our potential needs or interests. Cybercriminals and others with malicious intent recognize this as an opportunity and seek to trick us into installing malicious software (malware) — programs that hijack our computers, steal our money, or try to inflict harm.</description></item></channel></rss>