<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>W3C on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/w3c/</link><description>Recent content in W3C on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:52:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/w3c/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Insecure Elephant in the Room</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/10/10/the-insecure-elephant-in-the-room/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:52:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/10/10/the-insecure-elephant-in-the-room/</guid><description>The purpose of this article The purpose of this article is to demonstrate why I believe browser-based UI for website identity can make the web safer for everyone. I explain in great detail, the reasons why the UI and UX didn’t work in the past. And what’s left is only making the problem worse instead of better.
Some people seem to find it difficult to consume my thoughts about the enforcement of “HTTPS EVERYWHERE”, free DV certs and the browser padlock.</description></item><item><title>Fortify Allows Users to Generate X.509 Certificates in Their Browser</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-allows-users-to-generate-x.509-certificates-in-their-browser/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-allows-users-to-generate-x.509-certificates-in-their-browser/</guid><description>Fortify, an open source application sponsored by Certificate Authorities through the CA Security Council, is now available for Windows and Mac. The Fortify app, which is free for all users, connects a user’s web browsers to smart cards, security tokens, and certificates on a user’s local machine. This can allow users to generate X.509 certificates in their browser, replacing the need for the deprecated &amp;lt;keygen&amp;gt; functionality.
Certificate Generation In The Browser The Web Cryptography API, also known as Web Crypto, provides a set of cryptographic capabilities for web browsers through a set of JavaScript APIs.</description></item><item><title>Moving to Always on HTTPS, Part 2 of 2; Upgrading to HTTP Strict Transport Security</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/02/18/moving-to-always-on-https-part-2-of-2-upgrading-to-http-strict-transport-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 16:15:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/02/18/moving-to-always-on-https-part-2-of-2-upgrading-to-http-strict-transport-security/</guid><description>Part 1 of this blog post discussed browser security indicators and how to avoid getting warnings about mixed content on your website. (Mixed content leaves a door open that allows an attacker to snoop or inject malicious content during the browsing session.) This Part 2 discusses other technical measures to implement Always on HTTPS. As I noted previously, one of the difficulties with implementing Always on HTTPS is that content is often provided by third parties.</description></item></channel></rss>