<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DTLS on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/dtls/</link><description>Recent content in DTLS on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 20:14:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/dtls/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenSSL High Severity Vulnerability</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/07/10/openssl-high-severity-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 20:14:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/07/10/openssl-high-severity-vulnerability/</guid><description>OpenSSL has announced a high severity vulnerability, CVE-2015-1793 which will require an upgrade to some OpenSSL installations.
The vulnerability was discovered by Google personnel Adam Langley and David Benjamin on June 24, 2015. Google has been working on an alternative to OpenSSL called BoringSSL. This has allowed Google to reduce vulnerabilities in their installations, but is also a benefit to OpenSSL as issues have been reported. Note that BoringSSL is not impacted.</description></item><item><title>Heartbleed Bug Vulnerability: Discovery, Impact and Solution</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/09/heartbleed-bug-vulnerability-discovery-impact-and-solution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 19:30:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/09/heartbleed-bug-vulnerability-discovery-impact-and-solution/</guid><description>On April 7, 2014, a vulnerability in the OpenSSL cryptographic library was announced to the Internet community. Aptly labeled as the Heartbleed bug, this vulnerability affects OpenSSL versions 1.0.1 through 1.0.1f (inclusive). The Heartbleed bug is not a flaw in the SSL or TLS protocols; rather, it is a flaw in the OpenSSL implementation of the TLS/DTLS heartbeat functionality. The flaw is not related or introduced by publicly trusted certificates and is instead a problem with server software.</description></item></channel></rss>