<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FIPS on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/fips/</link><description>Recent content in FIPS on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:18:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/fips/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don’t ‘Compromise’ Your Code Amid Malware Mayhem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/05/12/dont-compromise-your-code-amid-malware-mayhem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:18:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/05/12/dont-compromise-your-code-amid-malware-mayhem/</guid><description>Code Signing Certificates demand a price premium in the underground online marketplace. This is no surprise considering that criminals sometimes use them to dupe their potential victims into installing malware in their machine.</description></item><item><title>Leading Certificate Authorities and Microsoft Introduce New Standards to Protect Consumers Online</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 21:05:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</guid><description>San Francisco –December 8, 2016 – the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement web security, today announced the Code Signing Working Group has released new Minimum Requirements for Code Signing for use by all Certificate Authorities (CA). These requirements represent the first-ever standardized code signing guidelines. Code signing is the method of using a certificate-based digital signature to sign executables and scripts in order to verify the author’s identity and ensure that the code has not been changed or corrupted.</description></item><item><title>Minimum Requirements for Code Signing Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/07/20/minimum-requirements-for-code-signing-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 20:47:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/07/20/minimum-requirements-for-code-signing-certificates/</guid><description>It is time for an update on the Baseline Requirements for Code Signing.
First the bad news, the new standard was not approved by the CA/Browser Forum due to philosophical differences among some forum members who felt code signing was not in scope with the Forum’s charter.
The good news is the document was created in a multi-stakeholder environment and substantially improves the current management processes. As such, it was decided to bring the document outside of the forum and finalize it as part of the CA Security Council.</description></item></channel></rss>