<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TSP on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/tsp/</link><description>Recent content in TSP on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 17:00:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/tsp/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Trust Is Elusive – Are Qualified Trust Services A Solution?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/05/01/digital-trust-is-elusive-are-qualified-trust-services-a-solution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/05/01/digital-trust-is-elusive-are-qualified-trust-services-a-solution/</guid><description>A popular saying goes: “Trust takes years to build, seconds to break, and forever to repair.”
While I wouldn’t completely agree, the idea isn’t wrong. In real life trust between two parties is established over some period of time, depending on a variety of factors. Have you ever wondered why you initially trust some people more and others less, even if you’ve never met them before? There are a complicated multitude of factors that influence our thoughts: the person’s appearance, tone of voice, title or rank, etc.</description></item><item><title>CA Day in Berlin</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/24/ca-day-in-berlin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 18:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/24/ca-day-in-berlin/</guid><description>“CA Day” (also known as CA Conformity Assessment) was hosted by the German company TuVIT in Berlin on January 16, 2014. In attendance were approximately 100 people from mostly European CAs. Under the European regulatory framework, CAs are included in a group referred to as “Trust Service Providers” or “TSPs.” CASC members in attendance at CA Day were Symantec, Digicert and Comodo. The dominant theme for this CA Day was the draft Regulation on Electronic identification and trust services for electronic transactions in the internal market (eIDAS) and upcoming changes in EU regulations for Qualified Certificates, which was briefed by Gerard Galler from the European Commission and discussed in greater detail by several European TSPs.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at NIST</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</guid><description>This week members of the CASC will be attending and speaking at the NIST Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace. You can also follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Even if you can’t make it to Maryland, you can still watch the event via the live webcast. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item></channel></rss>