<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web PKI on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/web-pki/</link><description>Recent content in Web PKI on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/web-pki/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>How Does the ROCA Attack Work?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/11/09/how-does-the-roca-attack-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 19:08:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/11/09/how-does-the-roca-attack-work/</guid><description>On October 17th, a group of Czech researchers announced they had found a way to factor the moduli of many RSA public keys generated by hardware produced by Infineon Technologies AG. The technical details were presented in a paper at the 2017 Computer and Communications Security conference, hosted by the Association for Computing Machinery on November 2nd.
The technique only works against the key pairs produced by Infineon’s library, because it exploits the unique method they use to generate RSA primes.</description></item><item><title>Quantum Computing: Real or Exaggerated Threat to the Web PKI?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/08/30/quantum-computing-real-or-exaggerated-threat-to-the-web-pki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 20:14:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/08/30/quantum-computing-real-or-exaggerated-threat-to-the-web-pki/</guid><description>Twenty years ago, paying your phone or electric bill involved receiving it in the mail, writing a check and mailing it back to the company. Today, that has largely been replaced by email and web-based payment submittals. All of this is secured by digital certificates and encryption, which provide privacy and authentication of information transiting the open Internet (aka Web PKI).
The web PKI is predominantly secured by RSA encryption algorithms; mathematical theorems which have been improved over time.</description></item><item><title>IETF 88 – Pervasive Surveillance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/26/ietf-88-pervasive-surveillance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 19:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/26/ietf-88-pervasive-surveillance/</guid><description>Internet Surveillance The big news at IETF 88 in Vancouver was the technical plenary on Hardening the Internet which discussed the issue of pervasive surveillance. Pervasive surveillance is a mass surveillance of an entire or a substantial fraction of a population. The surveillance is usually carried out by government, is not targeted and its occurrence may not be overt. It was noted that pervasive surveillance, of the kind revealed in the Snowden-sourced documents, constitutes a misguided and damaging attack on civic society in general and the Internet in particular.</description></item><item><title>IETF 86 – Web PKI Working Group</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:07:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</guid><description>At the IETF 86 meeting in Orlando last week, there was a working group meeting discussing the operations of the Web PKI. At the previous IETF 85 meeting a birds-of-a-feather was held to discuss the purpose of having such a group. The result of the meeting was an established group with the charter that states purposes such as:
Working group will work to improve the consistency of Web security behavior Address problems as seen by the end-users, certificate holders and CAs Describe how the Web PKI actually works Prepare documented deliverables as discussed below The meeting discussed the charter and the four following deliverables.</description></item></channel></rss>