<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>S/MIME on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/s/mime/</link><description>Recent content in S/MIME on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/s/mime/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Are Subordinate CAs and Why Would You Want Your Own?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</guid><description>Digital certificate and PKI adoption has changed quite a bit in recent years. Gone are the days where certificates were only synonymous with SSL/TLS; compliance drivers like stronger authentication requirements and digital signature regulations (e.g. eIDAS) have greatly expanded the role of PKI within the enterprise.
As PKI usage has expanded, conversation has moved beyond just the number and type of certificates needed and onto deeper dialogue about custom PKI deployments.</description></item><item><title>Fortify Allows Users to Generate X.509 Certificates in Their Browser</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-allows-users-to-generate-x.509-certificates-in-their-browser/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-allows-users-to-generate-x.509-certificates-in-their-browser/</guid><description>Fortify, an open source application sponsored by Certificate Authorities through the CA Security Council, is now available for Windows and Mac. The Fortify app, which is free for all users, connects a user’s web browsers to smart cards, security tokens, and certificates on a user’s local machine. This can allow users to generate X.509 certificates in their browser, replacing the need for the deprecated &amp;lt;keygen&amp;gt; functionality.
Certificate Generation In The Browser The Web Cryptography API, also known as Web Crypto, provides a set of cryptographic capabilities for web browsers through a set of JavaScript APIs.</description></item><item><title>Fortify Provides a More Secure Web Experience for Certificates and Smart Cards</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-provides-a-more-secure-web-experience-for-certificates-and-smart-cards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-provides-a-more-secure-web-experience-for-certificates-and-smart-cards/</guid><description>San Francisco – June 19, 2018 – The Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of web security, today announced that Fortify, an open source application sponsored by the Council, is now available for Windows and Mac. Fortify, a free app, connects a user’s web browsers to smart cards, security tokens, and certificates on a user’s local machine. This allows users to generate X.509 certificates in their browser, replacing the loss of key generation functionality.</description></item><item><title>CA/Browser Forum Governance Reform</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/05/18/ca/browser-forum-governance-reform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 12:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/05/18/ca/browser-forum-governance-reform/</guid><description>In March 2016, the CA/Browser Forum formed a working group to review potential ways to restructure the forum. The primary goal was to examine ideas so the Forum could work on other types of standards besides TLS. Ben Wilson and I chaired this group with excellent participation from a cross functional team of browser and certificate authority representatives as well as interested parties. After 2 years of efforts, the working group produced Ballot 206 which passed in April 2017.</description></item></channel></rss>