<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TLS 1.3 on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/tls-1.3/</link><description>Recent content in TLS 1.3 on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/tls-1.3/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>2019 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2018 2018 was an active year for SSL/TLS. We saw the SSL/TLS certificate validity period drop to 825-days and the mass deployment of Certificate Transparency (CT). TLS 1.3 protocol was finally completed and published; and Chrome status bar security indicators changing to remove “secure” and to concentrate on “not secure.” The CA/Browser Forum has been reformed, the London Protocol was announced and the nearly full distrust of Symantec SSL completed.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 18:07:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>As the legendary coach of the NY Yankees Yogi Berra allegedly said, “It’s difficult to make predictions, especially about the future.” But we’re going to try.
Here are the CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly.
The Good Prediction: By the end of 2019, over 90% of the world’s http traffic will be secured over SSL/TLS
Encryption boosts user security and privacy, and the combined efforts of browsers and Certification Authorities (CAs) over the past few years have moved us rapidly to a world approaching 100% encryption.</description></item><item><title>TLS 1.3 Includes Improvements to Security and Performance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/04/10/tls-1.3-includes-improvements-to-security-and-performance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 17:55:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/04/10/tls-1.3-includes-improvements-to-security-and-performance/</guid><description>Last month saw the final adoption, after 4 years of work, of TLS version 1.3 by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF). This latest iteration of the protocol for secure communications on the internet boasts several noteworthy improvements to both security and performance:
Security All cipher suites that do not provide forward secrecy have been eliminated from TLS 1.3. This is a very important security property, because without forward secrecy, if a server’s private key is compromised today, any previously-recorded conversations with that server dating back as long as the key was in use could be decrypted.</description></item><item><title>2018 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2017 2017 saw the end of SHA-1 in public trust SSL/TLS certificates and the start of Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) allowing domain owners to authorize their CA. A “Not secure” browser indication was propagated to push more websites to support HTTPS. There was also a change in the certification authority (CA) ownership with DigiCert acquiring Symantec’s SSL and related PKI business and Francisco Partners buying Comodo’s CA.</description></item><item><title>2017 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 21:11:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2016 Fortunately, 2016 was not a year full of SSL/TLS vulnerabilities. Although some researchers did prove old cryptography algorithms should be put out to pasture. The year showed the end of public-trusted SHA-1 SSL/TLS certificates. It also showed more transparency should be considered due to issues discovered with a few certification authorities (CAs). The great news is HTTPS is no longer the minority — after 20 years, connections using HTTPS has surpassed HTTP.</description></item><item><title>Stricter Standards for SSL Server Test Coming in 2017</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/13/stricter-standards-for-ssl-server-test-coming-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 16:32:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/13/stricter-standards-for-ssl-server-test-coming-in-2017/</guid><description>This is a good time to offer a reminder that the CASC has a great tool for secure server testing, the SSL Server Test. The tool grades your server installation and reviews the: certificate, protocol support, key exchange and cipher strength for security against standards and known vulnerabilities.
The grading tool also provides feedback on handshake simulations with various versions of browsers and operating systems. This lets the server administrator know which implementations are supported.</description></item><item><title>2016 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2015 A number of new tactics proved 2015 was no exception to an active year defending against ever increasing security issues. Vendors found new and creative ways to provide vulnerabilities including the now popular man-in-the-middle (MitM) attacks. MitM as well as a host of other new vulnerabilities caused browsers to rethink their security requirements. This article gives a flashback of the exploits and industry changes from 2015 and looks ahead at the latest security requirements and how it impacts IT security teams.</description></item><item><title>2015 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2014 End of 1024-Bit Security In 2014, the SSL industry moved to issuing a minimum security of 2048-bit RSA certificates. Keys smaller than 2048 are no longer allowed in server certificates. In addition, Microsoft and Mozilla started to remove 1024-bit roots from their certificate stores. Hopefully, the key size change will support users through to 2030.
Push to Perfect Forward Secrecy Following the Edward Snowden revelations of pervasive surveillance, there was a big push to configure web servers to support Perfect Forward Secrecy.</description></item><item><title>A Follow-up on POODLE and SSL 3.0</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/11/21/a-follow-up-on-poodle-and-ssl-3.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:15:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/11/21/a-follow-up-on-poodle-and-ssl-3.0/</guid><description>In October 2014, Google announced POODLE, an SSL 3.0 protocol attack.
To bring you up to speed, the SSL/TLS protocol is the most important and popular security protocol on the Internet. The Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol was developed by Netscape. They quickly moved from SSL 1.0 to 2.0 and finalized with SSL 3.0 in 1996.
This protocol was then picked up by the IETF, who released it under the name of Transport Layer Security (TLS).</description></item></channel></rss>