<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MITM on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/mitm/</link><description>Recent content in MITM on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 21:11:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/mitm/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2017 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 21:11:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2016 Fortunately, 2016 was not a year full of SSL/TLS vulnerabilities. Although some researchers did prove old cryptography algorithms should be put out to pasture. The year showed the end of public-trusted SHA-1 SSL/TLS certificates. It also showed more transparency should be considered due to issues discovered with a few certification authorities (CAs). The great news is HTTPS is no longer the minority — after 20 years, connections using HTTPS has surpassed HTTP.</description></item><item><title>2016 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2015 A number of new tactics proved 2015 was no exception to an active year defending against ever increasing security issues. Vendors found new and creative ways to provide vulnerabilities including the now popular man-in-the-middle (MitM) attacks. MitM as well as a host of other new vulnerabilities caused browsers to rethink their security requirements. This article gives a flashback of the exploits and industry changes from 2015 and looks ahead at the latest security requirements and how it impacts IT security teams.</description></item><item><title>OpenSSL High Severity Vulnerability</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/07/10/openssl-high-severity-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 20:14:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/07/10/openssl-high-severity-vulnerability/</guid><description>OpenSSL has announced a high severity vulnerability, CVE-2015-1793 which will require an upgrade to some OpenSSL installations.
The vulnerability was discovered by Google personnel Adam Langley and David Benjamin on June 24, 2015. Google has been working on an alternative to OpenSSL called BoringSSL. This has allowed Google to reduce vulnerabilities in their installations, but is also a benefit to OpenSSL as issues have been reported. Note that BoringSSL is not impacted.</description></item><item><title>The Insecurity of Mobile Applications</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/06/11/the-insecurity-of-mobile-applications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 18:30:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/06/11/the-insecurity-of-mobile-applications/</guid><description>Recently, we read about lots of SSL/TLS-related vulnerabilities found in mobile apps, which should come as no surprise. We were warned about this back in 2012 (see these studies). More warnings came in 2014 from CERT and FireEye. The Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) listed “insufficient transport layer protection” as number three (#3) in its top 10 list of mobile security problems of 2014. Apps that don’t use SSL/TLS are particularly vulnerable, given the ease of reading and modifying unsecured traffic at Wi-Fi hot spots, for example.</description></item><item><title>Server Name Indication and Fewer IP Addresses</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/06/02/server-name-indication-and-fewer-ip-addresses/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 17:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/06/02/server-name-indication-and-fewer-ip-addresses/</guid><description>You have a dilemma. You want to continue to deploy your web service but are running out of IPv4 addresses. You consider deploying multiple virtual servers that will use the same IP address. However, your thought is that you can only have one SSL certificate per IP address. How will you make your service secure?
Server Name Indication (SNI) is an extension to the SSL/TLS protocol that allows the browser or client software to indicate which hostname it is attempting to connect.</description></item><item><title>Practical Steps to Counter the Logjam Attack</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/05/26/practical-steps-to-counter-the-logjam-attack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/05/26/practical-steps-to-counter-the-logjam-attack/</guid><description>Another flaw has been found in the basic encryption algorithms that secure the Internet. This flaw, named the Logjam attack by its discoverers (researchers from various universities and companies), allows an attacker that can carry out man-in-the-middle (MitM) attacks to weaken the encryption used in secure connections (such as HTTPS, SSH, and VPNs). In theory, this means that an attacker (with sufficient resources) can break the encryption and read the “secure” traffic.</description></item><item><title>Fighting the Good Fight for Online Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:47:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</guid><description>Once again Browsers and Certificate Authorities are in the news over the reported mis-issuance of an SSL server certificate to a google.com domain. Discovered by Google most likely via technology known as key pinning and discussed by Google’s Adam Langley in this blog, a Chinese certificate authority, CNNIC (Chinese Internet Network Information Center), apparently issued an intermediate certificate to an Egyptian company called MCS Holdings. Because the CNNIC root certificate is included in the root store of most major browsers, users would not see any warnings on sites that have certificates issued by CNNIC or MCS Holdings.</description></item><item><title>Is Your SSL Server Vulnerable to a FREAK Attack?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/03/11/is-your-ssl-server-vulnerable-to-a-freak-attack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 16:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/03/11/is-your-ssl-server-vulnerable-to-a-freak-attack/</guid><description>FREAK is a new man-in-the-middle (MITM) vulnerability discovered by a group of cryptographers at INRIA, Microsoft Research and IMDEA. FREAK stands for “Factoring RSA-EXPORT Keys.”
The vulnerability dates back to the 1990s, when the US government banned selling crypto software overseas, unless it used export cipher suites which involved encryption keys no longer than 512-bits.
The issue is there are still some clients who let crypto be degraded from “strong RSA” to “export grade RSA”.</description></item><item><title>Lenovo Enables Man-in-the-Middle Attacks Via Superfish Adware</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/02/20/lenovo-enables-man-in-the-middle-attacks-via-superfish-adware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 22:27:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/02/20/lenovo-enables-man-in-the-middle-attacks-via-superfish-adware/</guid><description>Lenovo is selling computers that contain the Superfish application which “supplements” the user’s SSL sessions to enable their adware application to deliver content transparently; however, due to poor security design this leaves users vulnerable to man-in-the-middle attacks.
How it was supposed to work Superfish uses the program “Visual Discovery” to process images in browser content and then displays ads for similar goods and services. This sounds like any other adware application, but in order to maintain SSL sessions and not alert users with security warnings, Superfish is serving up these images over https.</description></item><item><title>Gogo Found Spoofing Google SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/01/08/gogo-found-spoofing-google-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 19:17:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/01/08/gogo-found-spoofing-google-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>It was recently disclosed that Gogo, a provider of Wi-Fi Internet services on commercial aircraft, has been issuing spoofed SSL certificates for Google sites that were viewed by customers of Gogo’s service. It appears that Gogo Inflight Internet was acting as an SSL Man-in-the-middle (MITM), a technique used within some enterprises to allow themselves to inspect and control all web traffic, even traffic to secure web sites. To understand what this means, let me explain MITM in a bit more detail.</description></item><item><title>2015 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2014 End of 1024-Bit Security In 2014, the SSL industry moved to issuing a minimum security of 2048-bit RSA certificates. Keys smaller than 2048 are no longer allowed in server certificates. In addition, Microsoft and Mozilla started to remove 1024-bit roots from their certificate stores. Hopefully, the key size change will support users through to 2030.
Push to Perfect Forward Secrecy Following the Edward Snowden revelations of pervasive surveillance, there was a big push to configure web servers to support Perfect Forward Secrecy.</description></item><item><title>What To Do When You Rely on Internal Names in TLS/SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/18/what-to-do-when-you-rely-on-internal-names-in-tls/ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 18:20:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/18/what-to-do-when-you-rely-on-internal-names-in-tls/ssl-certificates/</guid><description>A deadline set by the CA/Browser Forum for the use of Internal Names is quickly approaching, and many system administrators need to understand how best to adapt to this change. At the same time, hundreds of new top-level domains are being launched, which redefines what constitutes an Internal Name. In this post we’ll explain what the changes are, why they’re being made, and how you can update your systems in response to the problem.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Reputation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/28/certificate-reputation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/28/certificate-reputation/</guid><description>One of the advantages of having multiple certification authorities (CAs) from which to choose an SSL certificate is that customers have flexibility to choose a CA that meets their specific needs, or even use a number of CAs for redundancy or to have access to a broader toolset. The disadvantage for end users, however, is that they often may not know if a particular CA was authorized to issue the certificate, and there could be a chance that the certificate was fraudulently obtained.</description></item><item><title>Bogus SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/02/20/bogus-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 22:30:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/02/20/bogus-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Netcraft has published an article stating they have found many bogus SSL certificates. In this case, a bogus certificate is self-signed (i.e., not issued from a legitimate certification authority) and replicates an SSL certificate of a large, popular website.
This type of bogus SSL certificate could be used for a man-in-the-middle (MITM) attack. In this scenario, the attacker needs to gain a position that will allow them to intercept traffic and make you to go to their site instead of the real site.</description></item><item><title>Intermediate CA Certificates and Their Potential For Misuse For Man-In-The-Middle Attacks</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/09/intermediate-ca-certificates-and-their-potential-for-misuse-for-man-in-the-middle-attacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 21:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/09/intermediate-ca-certificates-and-their-potential-for-misuse-for-man-in-the-middle-attacks/</guid><description>We have seen recently that Google detected that publicly trusted TLS/(SSL) certificates had been created for Google domains without having been requested by Google themselves.
The existence of such certificates might usually be taken as an indication of misissuance by the issuing CA (i.e. a failure or mistake by the CA which allowed the issuance of an end-entity certificate otherwise than in accordance with their policy) or as an indication of compromise of the issuing CA.</description></item><item><title>2014 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 20:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2013 Protocol Attacks The year started with a couple of SSL/TLS protocol attacks: Lucky Thirteen and RC4 attack. Lucky Thirteen allows the decryption of sensitive information, such as passwords and cookies, when using the CBC-mode cipher suite. Lucky Thirteen can be mitigated by implementing software patches or preferring the cipher suite RC4.
That being said, RC4 was also attacked, where through 16 million sessions a small amount of plaintext can be recovered.</description></item><item><title>ICANN’s Accelerated gTLD Delegation Process and How This Impacts Your Organization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</guid><description>After the CASC’s previous letter addressing ICANN’s proposal to delegate nearly 2000 new gTLDs for use on the public Internet, ICANN identified and initiated an extensive study on two significant security issues. Now, based on the conclusions of the studies, ICANN is moving forward quickly with the delegation process, delegating more than 30 in the last two months alone. With ICANN ramping up the delegation process, nearly all 2000 will be delegated under the new rules, with only .</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 3: Optimization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/07/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-3-optimization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 15:03:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/07/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-3-optimization/</guid><description>To get the most out of SSL/TLS, you need to do a bit more than just configure your web server with an SSL certificate. The information below will help you optimize your website’s use of SSL. Making the changes suggested below will also help move your site towards “Always On SSL” (https://otalliance.org/resources/AOSSL/index.html), a best practice in which you serve the entire contents of your website over SSL/TLS.
Changes to the content of your website Some HTML tags can include attributes that are links or paths to other pages on your site.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Checking for Certificate Revocation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/09/the-importance-of-checking-for-certificate-revocation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 03:50:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/09/the-importance-of-checking-for-certificate-revocation/</guid><description>Certificates are typically valid for one to three years, and during that time it’s possible that the web site owner or the CA realizes that end users should not trust the certificate. There are several cases in which this might happen, including these:
The web site owner ceases doing business, no longer owns the domain name used in the certificate, has changed their organization name, or wishes to shut down the web server.</description></item></channel></rss>