<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ISO on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/iso/</link><description>Recent content in ISO on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 13:38:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/iso/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5 Ways to Keep Up with Authentication Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/02/24/5-ways-to-keep-up-with-authentication-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 13:38:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/02/24/5-ways-to-keep-up-with-authentication-certificates/</guid><description>When it comes to protecting an organization’s data and users, CISOs have no shortage of hurdles. Identity attacks have become sophisticated and convincing, thanks to ransomware, phishing and deep fakes. CISOs have long known the importance of strong identification and authentication controls, but with threats constantly changing and intensifying, having these controls in place is just one piece of the puzzle; they must be managed correctly in order to do their job.</description></item><item><title>Trust Indication Change in Google Chrome</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/08/24/trust-indication-change-in-google-chrome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 15:52:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/08/24/trust-indication-change-in-google-chrome/</guid><description>Google is making security icon changes in the Chrome status bar. The changes are based on a research paper prepared by members of Google and University of California, Berkeley. The research evaluated forty icons, seven complementary strings and surveyed 1,329 people.
The goal is to make it easier for browser users to determine how secure their connection to a site is and indicate if the site is dangerous or deceptive. In addition, the icons are to indicate to people that HTTP is less secure than HTTPS.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Authority Audits and Browser Root Program Requirements</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/10/15/certificate-authority-audits-and-browser-root-program-requirements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/10/15/certificate-authority-audits-and-browser-root-program-requirements/</guid><description>Recent news stories have highlighted the need for strong security in online communications, and use of SSL certificates issued by a publicly trusted Certification Authority (CA) is perhaps the best way to achieve that. But why should the public trust SSL certificates issued from commercial CA roots, which are embedded as trust anchors in web browsers?
One answer is because of the multiple layers of standards and tough requirements that all commercial CAs must meet – and for which they are audited every year.</description></item></channel></rss>