<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ECDSA on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/ecdsa/</link><description>Recent content in ECDSA on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 18:15:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/ecdsa/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Directions for Elliptic Curve Cryptography in Internet Protocols</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/06/24/new-directions-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-in-internet-protocols/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 18:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/06/24/new-directions-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-in-internet-protocols/</guid><description>Last week I attended and presented at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Workshop on Elliptic Curve Cryptography Standards. In NIST’s words, “The workshop is to provide a venue to engage the crypto community, including academia, industry, and government users to discuss possible approaches to promote the adoption of secure, interoperable and efficient elliptic curve mechanisms.”
We began by discussing the reasons for holding this workshop. Speakers acknowledged that although there are no known issues with the current set of NIST curves, in some circles they are widely distrusted.</description></item><item><title>Benefits of Elliptic Curve Cryptography</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/06/10/benefits-of-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/06/10/benefits-of-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</guid><description>Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) has existed since the mid-1980s, but it is still looked on as the newcomer in the world of SSL, and has only begun to gain adoption in the past few years. ECC is a fundamentally different mathematical approach to encryption than the venerable RSA algorithm. An elliptic curve is an algebraic function (y2 = x3 + ax + b) which looks like a symmetrical curve parallel to the x axis when plotted.</description></item></channel></rss>