<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hash Function on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/hash-function/</link><description>Recent content in Hash Function on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 16:26:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/hash-function/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Is Certificate Expiration Necessary?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/10/19/why-is-certificate-expiration-necessary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 16:26:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/10/19/why-is-certificate-expiration-necessary/</guid><description>The Long Life Certificate – Why It Doesn’t Exist Why is certificate expiration even necessary? Wouldn’t it be better if I could just buy a certificate with a long life before expiration? It would really simplify certificate management if it could be installed and forgotten. Simple, no management required, just file-and-forget.
Imagine, I’ve been in business, starting say 10 to 15 years ago. I roll out my web pages and secure them with a 20-year-validity SSL certificate.</description></item><item><title>TLS Certificates on the Web – The Good, The Bad and The Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/05/17/tls-certificates-on-the-web-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/05/17/tls-certificates-on-the-web-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>It might be hard to believe, but the SSL/TLS Ecosystem is nearly 20 years old. It’s time to take stock and see how we’re doing with regards to TLS certificates. In this article, we’ll primarily discuss certificates themselves and not web server configuration, although that is often a source of problems.
In the last few years, we’ve endured three major certificate-based migrations:
Away from the MD2 and MD5 hash algorithms to SHA-1 Away from small RSA keys to 2048-bit keys or larger Away from the SHA-1 hash algorithm to SHA-256 What’s driving these migrations?</description></item><item><title>2016 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2015 A number of new tactics proved 2015 was no exception to an active year defending against ever increasing security issues. Vendors found new and creative ways to provide vulnerabilities including the now popular man-in-the-middle (MitM) attacks. MitM as well as a host of other new vulnerabilities caused browsers to rethink their security requirements. This article gives a flashback of the exploits and industry changes from 2015 and looks ahead at the latest security requirements and how it impacts IT security teams.</description></item><item><title>Who Sets the Rules Governing Certification Authorities?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 15:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</guid><description>Every time something positive is published about SSL and encryption,such as Google’s recent decision making use of https encryption a favorable rating factor for a website, or negative, such as the Heartbleed issue – bloggers and others always post questions about public Certification Authorities (CAs), including general questions on who sets the rules that govern CAs. Some bloggers seem to assume there are no rules or standards, and that CAs can operate without any requirements or limitations at all — that’s incorrect.</description></item><item><title>RSA Recap – Securing Your Site</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/08/rsa-recap-securing-your-site/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/08/rsa-recap-securing-your-site/</guid><description>At RSA last week a few of us participated in panel discussions that focused on SSL/TLS. During the panel that I moderated on Friday, one theme we addressed was secure server configuration. One of CASC’s goals is to help harden existing SSL/TLS implementations against vulnerabilities—because most SSL/TLS exploits arise from suboptimal website configurations. These vulnerabilities and attacks can be mitigated or even eliminated with proper server configuration and good website design.</description></item></channel></rss>