<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ryan Hurst on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/authors/ryan-hurst/</link><description>Recent content in Ryan Hurst on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 18:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/authors/ryan-hurst/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Certificate Chains, Key Management and the Number of CAs Counted by Web Crawlers – Oh My</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/04/certificate-chains-key-management-and-the-number-of-cas-counted-by-web-crawlers-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/04/certificate-chains-key-management-and-the-number-of-cas-counted-by-web-crawlers-oh-my/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why your web server certificate has a “chain” of other certificates associated with it?
The main reason is so that browsers can tell if your certificate was issued by an organization that has been verified to meet the security, policy and operational practices that all Publicly Trusted Certificate Authorities are mandated to meet. That certificate at the top of the chain is commonly called the “root.” It’s signature on a certificate below it indicates that the organization operating the root believes that practices of the CA below it meets that same high bar.</description></item><item><title>The (Soon to Be) Not-So Common Name</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/10/08/the-soon-to-be-not-so-common-name/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/10/08/the-soon-to-be-not-so-common-name/</guid><description>If you are reading this post you are probably already familiar with the use of digital certificates and SSL even if you may not be familiar with the history. Before exploring the history of SSL, let’s review at its core what a digital certificate actually is. Fundamentally, a digital certificate is the binding of entitlements and constraints to a key, in other words a digital certificate would dictate the following, “The holder of the private key associated with this certificate can rightfully use the name John Smith when signing emails.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 3: Optimization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/07/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-3-optimization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 15:03:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/07/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-3-optimization/</guid><description>To get the most out of SSL/TLS, you need to do a bit more than just configure your web server with an SSL certificate. The information below will help you optimize your website’s use of SSL. Making the changes suggested below will also help move your site towards “Always On SSL” (https://otalliance.org/resources/AOSSL/index.html), a best practice in which you serve the entire contents of your website over SSL/TLS.
Changes to the content of your website Some HTML tags can include attributes that are links or paths to other pages on your site.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2: Configuration</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 01:19:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</guid><description>They say the most complicated skill is to be simple; despite SSL and HTTPS having been around for a long time, they still are not as simple as they could be.
One of the reasons for this is that the security industry is constantly learning more about how to design and build secure systems; as a result, the protocols and software used to secure online services need to continuously evolve to keep up with the latest risks.</description></item></channel></rss>