<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OCSP on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/ocsp/</link><description>Recent content in OCSP on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/ocsp/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Are Subordinate CAs and Why Would You Want Your Own?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</guid><description>Digital certificate and PKI adoption has changed quite a bit in recent years. Gone are the days where certificates were only synonymous with SSL/TLS; compliance drivers like stronger authentication requirements and digital signature regulations (e.g. eIDAS) have greatly expanded the role of PKI within the enterprise.
As PKI usage has expanded, conversation has moved beyond just the number and type of certificates needed and onto deeper dialogue about custom PKI deployments.</description></item><item><title>Why Is Certificate Expiration Necessary?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/10/19/why-is-certificate-expiration-necessary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 16:26:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/10/19/why-is-certificate-expiration-necessary/</guid><description>The Long Life Certificate – Why It Doesn’t Exist Why is certificate expiration even necessary? Wouldn’t it be better if I could just buy a certificate with a long life before expiration? It would really simplify certificate management if it could be installed and forgotten. Simple, no management required, just file-and-forget.
Imagine, I’ve been in business, starting say 10 to 15 years ago. I roll out my web pages and secure them with a 20-year-validity SSL certificate.</description></item><item><title>Extra Trips are for Frequent Flyers, Not SSL/TLS Performance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/10/30/extra-trips-are-for-frequent-flyers-not-ssl/tls-performance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 16:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/10/30/extra-trips-are-for-frequent-flyers-not-ssl/tls-performance/</guid><description>TLS is quickly becoming a de facto requirement for every website due to increased concerns about spying and Google’s recent move to use HTTPS as a factor in search engine ranking. In a recent article we explained how HSTS helps website operators to ensure that their site is always using TLS, but now we want to ensure that your performance isn’t sacrificed in the name of enhanced security. While the myth that TLS slows down a website has been debunked, some basic settings can make a site using TLS even faster.</description></item><item><title>Who Sets the Rules Governing Certification Authorities?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 15:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</guid><description>Every time something positive is published about SSL and encryption,such as Google’s recent decision making use of https encryption a favorable rating factor for a website, or negative, such as the Heartbleed issue – bloggers and others always post questions about public Certification Authorities (CAs), including general questions on who sets the rules that govern CAs. Some bloggers seem to assume there are no rules or standards, and that CAs can operate without any requirements or limitations at all — that’s incorrect.</description></item><item><title>In the Wake of Unauthorized Certificate Issuance by the Indian CA NIC, can Government CAs Still be Considered “Trusted Third Parties”?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</guid><description>Short answer: Government CAs can still be considered “trusted third parties,” provided that they follow the rules applicable to commercial CAs.
Introduction On July 8 Google announced that it had discovered several unauthorized Google certificates issued by the National Informatics Centre of India. It noted that the Indian government CA’s certificates were in the Microsoft Root Store and used by programs on the Windows platform. The Firefox browser on Windows uses its own root store and didn’t have these CA certificates.</description></item><item><title>CASC Heartbleed Response</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/05/08/casc-heartbleed-response/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 15:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/05/08/casc-heartbleed-response/</guid><description>The recent Heartbleed issue has reawakened interest in SSL certificate revocation (see Adam Langley’s blog, Larry Seltzer’s articles here and here, and Steve Gibson’s web pages)
Several years ago, the CA Browser Forum convened a special Revocation Working Group to explore issues and solutions. Leading CAs were actively involved in that group, and many of them invested in moving their OCSP responders to high-performance, high-availability Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) to respond to browser vendors’ requests for increased performance and reliability.</description></item><item><title>Revocation – A Cure For the Common Heartbleed</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/28/revocation-a-cure-for-the-common-heartbleed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 21:47:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/28/revocation-a-cure-for-the-common-heartbleed/</guid><description>The Heartbleed bug spurred server administrators worldwide to work closely with Certification Authorities (CAs) in rekeying and reissuing potentially vulnerable SSL certificates. Part of this effort included revoking existing certificates used on vulnerable servers to ensure obtained private keys are not later used in a man-in-the-middle attack against the website. Unfortunately, in recent days, certain news reports and blogs addressing certificate revocation and checking for revoked certificates online have failed to discuss the benefits of revocation, instead focusing on the minority of circumstances where widely deployed revocation is not perfect.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Reputation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/28/certificate-reputation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/28/certificate-reputation/</guid><description>One of the advantages of having multiple certification authorities (CAs) from which to choose an SSL certificate is that customers have flexibility to choose a CA that meets their specific needs, or even use a number of CAs for redundancy or to have access to a broader toolset. The disadvantage for end users, however, is that they often may not know if a particular CA was authorized to issue the certificate, and there could be a chance that the certificate was fraudulently obtained.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Members Presentation at RSA 2014 Conference: New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</guid><description>CA Security Council (CASC) members Trend Micro, Go Daddy, and Symantec participated in a discussion panel at the 2014 RSA Conference in San Francisco on February 24 entitled “New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet.” Panel members included Kirk Hall of Trend Micro (Moderator), Wayne Thayer of GoDaddy (Panelist), and Rick Andrews of Symantec (Panelist).
Introduction to the Topic Hall began by introducing the topic – all three alternative technologies (Certificate Transparency or CT, Certificate Authority Authorization or CAA, and Certificate Pinning) are intended to make the internet safer by dealing with mis-issued digital certificates, including so-called “rogue” certs like those obtained by a hacker from the now-defunct Diginotar Certification Authority (CA).</description></item><item><title>Certificate Chains, Key Management and the Number of CAs Counted by Web Crawlers – Oh My</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/04/certificate-chains-key-management-and-the-number-of-cas-counted-by-web-crawlers-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/04/certificate-chains-key-management-and-the-number-of-cas-counted-by-web-crawlers-oh-my/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why your web server certificate has a “chain” of other certificates associated with it?
The main reason is so that browsers can tell if your certificate was issued by an organization that has been verified to meet the security, policy and operational practices that all Publicly Trusted Certificate Authorities are mandated to meet. That certificate at the top of the chain is commonly called the “root.” It’s signature on a certificate below it indicates that the organization operating the root believes that practices of the CA below it meets that same high bar.</description></item><item><title>It’s Time for TLS 1.2</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/19/its-time-for-tls-1.2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/19/its-time-for-tls-1.2/</guid><description>In a previous post titled Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2, we touched on the recommendation that Web servers be configured to prefer Transport Layer Security (TLS) version 1.2. With the planned release of Firefox 24 and recent release of Chrome 29 adding support for TLS 1.2, now is a great time for website administrators to make the switch.
Transport Layer Security was formerly called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and is the protocol that enables secure “https://” connections to websites.</description></item><item><title>What Is Certificate Transparency and How Does It Propose to Address Certificate Mis-Issuance?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/09/what-is-certificate-transparency-and-how-does-it-propose-to-address-certificate-mis-issuance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/09/what-is-certificate-transparency-and-how-does-it-propose-to-address-certificate-mis-issuance/</guid><description>As originally architected by Netscape and others in the mid-1990s, the certificate issuance process envisioned that the CA would present the certificate and its contents to the named subject who would review and accept the certificate first. Then the CA would publish the certificate to a repository. That process would establish that the certificate’s subject was aware of certificate issuance. (Otherwise, an unscrupulous CA could sign a subscriber’s public key and create a certificate for the subscriber without its knowledge.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to OCSP Multi-Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 21:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</guid><description>OCSP Stapling OCSP is a protocol used to check the validity of certificates to make sure they have not been revoked. OCSP is an alternative to Certificate Revocation Lists (CRLs). Since OCSP responses can be as small as a few hundred bytes, OCSP is particularly useful when the issuing CA has relatively big CRLs, as well as when the client has limited memory and processing power.
OCSP can also provide much more timely information than CRLs about the status of a certificate since the information is generally fetched more frequently.</description></item><item><title>Self-Signed Certificates Don’t Deliver Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/02/self-signed-certificates-dont-deliver-trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 20:48:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/02/self-signed-certificates-dont-deliver-trust/</guid><description>We’ve heard the argument that website operators could just use self-signed certificates. They are easy to issue and they are “free.” Before issuing self-signed certificates, it’s a good idea to examine the trust and security model. You should also compare self-signed certificates to the publicly trusted certification authority (CA) model; and then make your own decision.
Self-Signed Certificate Model Owner says who they are Owner issues on their own policy Owner is responsible for quality Owner may not follow industry guidelines Owner may not provide certificate status Compromised certificates may not be able to be revoked Owner is not audited Issuer of certificate may not be authorized by the domain owner Certificates may not be renewed if there are no reminders Self-signed certificate model does not provide trust and the browser provides a trust dialogue box to indicate such Publicly-Trusted CA-Signed Certificate Model CA verifies the owner of the domain and the certificate applicant CA operates to a policy in conformance with the requirements of the browser and operating system vendors.</description></item><item><title>IETF 86 – Web PKI Working Group</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:07:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</guid><description>At the IETF 86 meeting in Orlando last week, there was a working group meeting discussing the operations of the Web PKI. At the previous IETF 85 meeting a birds-of-a-feather was held to discuss the purpose of having such a group. The result of the meeting was an established group with the charter that states purposes such as:
Working group will work to improve the consistency of Web security behavior Address problems as seen by the end-users, certificate holders and CAs Describe how the Web PKI actually works Prepare documented deliverables as discussed below The meeting discussed the charter and the four following deliverables.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Revocation Checking Part 2: A Real World Example</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/11/the-importance-of-revocation-checking-part-2-a-real-world-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 16:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/11/the-importance-of-revocation-checking-part-2-a-real-world-example/</guid><description>Just last week, a new security incident related to certificate revocation checking made headlines. It was discovered that a legitimate website was hosting a malicious Java application that installed malware on the computers of people who visited the site. This comes after recent updates that introduced Security Level settings in Java, and then raised the default from Medium to High. At the high level, users are shown a warning before any unsigned Java code is executed.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Checking for Certificate Revocation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/09/the-importance-of-checking-for-certificate-revocation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 03:50:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/09/the-importance-of-checking-for-certificate-revocation/</guid><description>Certificates are typically valid for one to three years, and during that time it’s possible that the web site owner or the CA realizes that end users should not trust the certificate. There are several cases in which this might happen, including these:
The web site owner ceases doing business, no longer owns the domain name used in the certificate, has changed their organization name, or wishes to shut down the web server.</description></item><item><title>OCSP Stapling: Improved Performance and Security, a Win-Win</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/ocsp-stapling-improved-performance-and-security-a-win-win/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 16:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/ocsp-stapling-improved-performance-and-security-a-win-win/</guid><description>The launch of the CASC has given its members a unique platform through which we can educate users about online security and the best practices in utilizing SSL. That’s why we’ve decided to pair the group’s launch with a focused effort on OCSP stapling.
Why OCSP stapling? For one, stapling is already supported by IIS and the newest versions of Apache and nginx. Although server software does not enable OCSP by default, servers can be re-configured with a little education.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Revocation and OCSP Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</guid><description>Revocation As a body of global CAs, the CA Security Council is committed to educating server administrators, end-users and other interested parties about SSL enhancements and best practices that can better protect everyone. An important initiative that can make a practical difference right now is addressing easily implemented improvements to certificate status services that handle revocation of invalid or expired certificates, specifically the implementation of OCSP stapling.
What is certificate revocation?</description></item><item><title>World’s Leading Certificate Authorities Come Together to Advance Internet Security and the Trusted SSL Ecosystem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</guid><description>San Francisco, CA. – February 14, 2013 – Leading global certificate authorities announced the creation of the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group, committed to the exploration and promotion of best practices that advance the security of websites and online transactions. Through public education, collaboration, and advocacy, the CASC strives to improve understanding of critical policies and their potential impact on the internet infrastructure. Members of the CASC include Comodo, DigiCert, Entrust, GlobalSign, Go Daddy, Symantec, and Trend Micro.</description></item></channel></rss>