<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ROCA on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/roca/</link><description>Recent content in ROCA on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/roca/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2018 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2017 2017 saw the end of SHA-1 in public trust SSL/TLS certificates and the start of Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) allowing domain owners to authorize their CA. A “Not secure” browser indication was propagated to push more websites to support HTTPS. There was also a change in the certification authority (CA) ownership with DigiCert acquiring Symantec’s SSL and related PKI business and Francisco Partners buying Comodo’s CA.</description></item><item><title>How Does the ROCA Attack Work?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/11/09/how-does-the-roca-attack-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 19:08:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/11/09/how-does-the-roca-attack-work/</guid><description>On October 17th, a group of Czech researchers announced they had found a way to factor the moduli of many RSA public keys generated by hardware produced by Infineon Technologies AG. The technical details were presented in a paper at the 2017 Computer and Communications Security conference, hosted by the Association for Computing Machinery on November 2nd.
The technique only works against the key pairs produced by Infineon’s library, because it exploits the unique method they use to generate RSA primes.</description></item></channel></rss>