<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CASC on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/casc/</link><description>Recent content in CASC on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:00:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/casc/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CA Security Council Members Presentation at RSA 2014 Conference: New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</guid><description>CA Security Council (CASC) members Trend Micro, Go Daddy, and Symantec participated in a discussion panel at the 2014 RSA Conference in San Francisco on February 24 entitled “New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet.” Panel members included Kirk Hall of Trend Micro (Moderator), Wayne Thayer of GoDaddy (Panelist), and Rick Andrews of Symantec (Panelist).
Introduction to the Topic Hall began by introducing the topic – all three alternative technologies (Certificate Transparency or CT, Certificate Authority Authorization or CAA, and Certificate Pinning) are intended to make the internet safer by dealing with mis-issued digital certificates, including so-called “rogue” certs like those obtained by a hacker from the now-defunct Diginotar Certification Authority (CA).</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at NIST</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</guid><description>This week members of the CASC will be attending and speaking at the NIST Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace. You can also follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Even if you can’t make it to Maryland, you can still watch the event via the live webcast. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at RSA</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/25/casc-happenings-at-rsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 15:32:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/25/casc-happenings-at-rsa/</guid><description>We are excited to have members of the CASC attending and speaking at this year’s RSA Conference. The events and panels will cover various topics that revolve around the security of the Internet and CAs as a whole. You can follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item><item><title>World’s Leading Certificate Authorities Come Together to Advance Internet Security and the Trusted SSL Ecosystem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</guid><description>San Francisco, CA. – February 14, 2013 – Leading global certificate authorities announced the creation of the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group, committed to the exploration and promotion of best practices that advance the security of websites and online transactions. Through public education, collaboration, and advocacy, the CASC strives to improve understanding of critical policies and their potential impact on the internet infrastructure. Members of the CASC include Comodo, DigiCert, Entrust, GlobalSign, Go Daddy, Symantec, and Trend Micro.</description></item><item><title>CAs Unite</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/cas-unite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/cas-unite/</guid><description>Today marks an important day for internet security and future SSL enhancements, as the world’s seven largest publicly trusted Certificate Authorities are announcing the formation of the Certificate Authority Security Council.
While leading CAs have worked together for years to address security challenges and meet them with evolving and increasingly strict standards and best practices through the CA/Browser Forum and other industry venues, we’ve lacked a union where we can come together and speak with a unified CA voice.</description></item></channel></rss>