<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CASC on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/casc/</link><description>Recent content in CASC on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 15:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/casc/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>9 Common Myths About CAs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</guid><description>Over the years misconceptions about CAs and the SSL infrastructure have arisen. Below is a list of common myths related to SSL and CAs.
Myth #1: CAs are not regulated Fact: CAs are subject to various checks and balances, including third-party qualified audits through WebTrust or ETSI and strict criteria set forth by leading browsers, before they are accepted in browser root stores. Similarly, the CA/Browser Forum’s Baseline Requirements and Network Security Guidelines establish global standards for certificate issuance and CA controls that will soon be included in third-party auditing standards.</description></item><item><title>What the Latest Firefox Update Means for SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/14/what-the-latest-firefox-update-means-for-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 18:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/14/what-the-latest-firefox-update-means-for-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Last month marked the release of Firefox 66, the newest iteration of the ever-popular web browser. The update adds a number of interesting new features, including improvements to content loading and extension storage, auto-play sound blocking, and support for the AV1 codec (on the Windows version at least). The search feature has also been improved, and, as is typical of browser updates, a number of known security vulnerabilities have been patched.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 18:07:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>As the legendary coach of the NY Yankees Yogi Berra allegedly said, “It’s difficult to make predictions, especially about the future.” But we’re going to try.
Here are the CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly.
The Good Prediction: By the end of 2019, over 90% of the world’s http traffic will be secured over SSL/TLS
Encryption boosts user security and privacy, and the combined efforts of browsers and Certification Authorities (CAs) over the past few years have moved us rapidly to a world approaching 100% encryption.</description></item><item><title>CASC Announces Launch of London Protocol to Improve Identity Assurance and Minimize Phishing on Identity Websites</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</guid><description>LONDON – (June 27, 2018) – The Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of the security of websites and online transactions, announced at the CA/Browser Forum event in London the launch of the London Protocol – an initiative to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted with organization validated (OV) and extended validation (EV) certificates, which contain organization identity information (Identity Certificates).</description></item><item><title>Fortify Provides a More Secure Web Experience for Certificates and Smart Cards</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-provides-a-more-secure-web-experience-for-certificates-and-smart-cards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-provides-a-more-secure-web-experience-for-certificates-and-smart-cards/</guid><description>San Francisco – June 19, 2018 – The Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of web security, today announced that Fortify, an open source application sponsored by the Council, is now available for Windows and Mac. Fortify, a free app, connects a user’s web browsers to smart cards, security tokens, and certificates on a user’s local machine. This allows users to generate X.509 certificates in their browser, replacing the loss of key generation functionality.</description></item><item><title>Stricter Standards for SSL Server Test Coming in 2017</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/13/stricter-standards-for-ssl-server-test-coming-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 16:32:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/13/stricter-standards-for-ssl-server-test-coming-in-2017/</guid><description>This is a good time to offer a reminder that the CASC has a great tool for secure server testing, the SSL Server Test. The tool grades your server installation and reviews the: certificate, protocol support, key exchange and cipher strength for security against standards and known vulnerabilities.
The grading tool also provides feedback on handshake simulations with various versions of browsers and operating systems. This lets the server administrator know which implementations are supported.</description></item><item><title>Leading Certificate Authorities and Microsoft Introduce New Standards to Protect Consumers Online</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 21:05:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</guid><description>San Francisco –December 8, 2016 – the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement web security, today announced the Code Signing Working Group has released new Minimum Requirements for Code Signing for use by all Certificate Authorities (CA). These requirements represent the first-ever standardized code signing guidelines. Code signing is the method of using a certificate-based digital signature to sign executables and scripts in order to verify the author’s identity and ensure that the code has not been changed or corrupted.</description></item><item><title>Minimum Requirements for Code Signing Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/07/20/minimum-requirements-for-code-signing-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 20:47:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/07/20/minimum-requirements-for-code-signing-certificates/</guid><description>It is time for an update on the Baseline Requirements for Code Signing.
First the bad news, the new standard was not approved by the CA/Browser Forum due to philosophical differences among some forum members who felt code signing was not in scope with the Forum’s charter.
The good news is the document was created in a multi-stakeholder environment and substantially improves the current management processes. As such, it was decided to bring the document outside of the forum and finalize it as part of the CA Security Council.</description></item><item><title>Code Signing Baseline Requirements</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/11/30/code-signing-baseline-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 17:51:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/11/30/code-signing-baseline-requirements/</guid><description>You may have heard that the CA/Browser Forum is getting ready to approve Baseline Requirements for Code Signing certificates. But why is this important?
Let’s back up and get some background on code signing. Software code that is digitally signed indicates to the user that the code has not been tampered with since it was signed. It also provides authenticity as to who signed it and when. With the advent of malware, it’s important to insure that the code which was written by the developer is the same code which you downloaded and installed into your computer or mobile phone.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Report: Consumers Don’t Know Much About Security, But They Trust the Padlock and Green Bar When Shopping Online</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/13/ca-security-council-report-consumers-dont-know-much-about-security-but-they-trust-the-padlock-and-green-bar-when-shopping-online/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/13/ca-security-council-report-consumers-dont-know-much-about-security-but-they-trust-the-padlock-and-green-bar-when-shopping-online/</guid><description>San Francisco – April 13, 2015 – The CA Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of the security of websites and online transactions, today released its 2015 Consumer Trust Survey which found that validation matters. While consumers are confused about some aspects of security, they recognize and trust the security that SSL brings to e-commerce sites. Fifty-three percent of respondents identify the padlock as adding confidence in an e-commerce site, with 42 percent associating the green bar and organization name in the URL with greater safety.</description></item><item><title>Fighting the Good Fight for Online Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:47:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</guid><description>Once again Browsers and Certificate Authorities are in the news over the reported mis-issuance of an SSL server certificate to a google.com domain. Discovered by Google most likely via technology known as key pinning and discussed by Google’s Adam Langley in this blog, a Chinese certificate authority, CNNIC (Chinese Internet Network Information Center), apparently issued an intermediate certificate to an Egyptian company called MCS Holdings. Because the CNNIC root certificate is included in the root store of most major browsers, users would not see any warnings on sites that have certificates issued by CNNIC or MCS Holdings.</description></item><item><title>Code Signing Baseline Requirements</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/10/20/code-signing-baseline-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/10/20/code-signing-baseline-requirements/</guid><description>Code signing certificates are used to sign software objects to authenticate that they originated from a verified source, allowing developers to avoid warnings commonly displayed by application software vendors such as Microsoft operating systems and Java. A fraudulent code signing certificate can wreak havoc on networks, spreading malware and adware without restraint. Certificate Authorities are tasked with ensuring that code signing applicants are legitimate entities and provide accountability for use of the certificate.</description></item><item><title>Google Plans to Deprecate SHA-1 Certificates – Updated</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/09/24/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates-updated/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 18:26:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/09/24/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates-updated/</guid><description>UPDATED September 23, 2014: The following blog post has been updated with action taken in recent weeks, as well as to reflect helpful user comments left on our August 28 blog post on this topic.
On August 19, Google announced a new policy that accelerates the deprecation of SHA-1 certificates, potentially causing websites using SHA-1 certificates to display warnings in the near future. While keeping with an earlier Microsoft announcement to accept SHA-1 certificates with an expiration date before Jan.</description></item><item><title>Google Plans to Deprecate SHA-1 Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/28/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 14:07:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/28/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates/</guid><description>On August 19, Google announced a new policy that accelerates the deprecation of SHA-1 certificates, potentially causing websites using SHA-1 certificates to display warnings in the near future. With the change, Chrome 39 will show a warning for sites that have a SHA-1 certificate expiring in 2016 and require a click through warning for sites with a SHA-1 certificate expiring in 2017 or later. This proposal is scheduled for Chrome 39, which could be released as early as 12 weeks from now.</description></item><item><title>In the Wake of Unauthorized Certificate Issuance by the Indian CA NIC, can Government CAs Still be Considered “Trusted Third Parties”?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</guid><description>Short answer: Government CAs can still be considered “trusted third parties,” provided that they follow the rules applicable to commercial CAs.
Introduction On July 8 Google announced that it had discovered several unauthorized Google certificates issued by the National Informatics Centre of India. It noted that the Indian government CA’s certificates were in the Microsoft Root Store and used by programs on the Windows platform. The Firefox browser on Windows uses its own root store and didn’t have these CA certificates.</description></item><item><title>CASC Heartbleed Response</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/05/08/casc-heartbleed-response/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 15:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/05/08/casc-heartbleed-response/</guid><description>The recent Heartbleed issue has reawakened interest in SSL certificate revocation (see Adam Langley’s blog, Larry Seltzer’s articles here and here, and Steve Gibson’s web pages)
Several years ago, the CA Browser Forum convened a special Revocation Working Group to explore issues and solutions. Leading CAs were actively involved in that group, and many of them invested in moving their OCSP responders to high-performance, high-availability Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) to respond to browser vendors’ requests for increased performance and reliability.</description></item><item><title>Revocation – A Cure For the Common Heartbleed</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/28/revocation-a-cure-for-the-common-heartbleed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 21:47:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/28/revocation-a-cure-for-the-common-heartbleed/</guid><description>The Heartbleed bug spurred server administrators worldwide to work closely with Certification Authorities (CAs) in rekeying and reissuing potentially vulnerable SSL certificates. Part of this effort included revoking existing certificates used on vulnerable servers to ensure obtained private keys are not later used in a man-in-the-middle attack against the website. Unfortunately, in recent days, certain news reports and blogs addressing certificate revocation and checking for revoked certificates online have failed to discuss the benefits of revocation, instead focusing on the minority of circumstances where widely deployed revocation is not perfect.</description></item><item><title>Heartbleed Bug Vulnerability: Discovery, Impact and Solution</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/09/heartbleed-bug-vulnerability-discovery-impact-and-solution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 19:30:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/09/heartbleed-bug-vulnerability-discovery-impact-and-solution/</guid><description>On April 7, 2014, a vulnerability in the OpenSSL cryptographic library was announced to the Internet community. Aptly labeled as the Heartbleed bug, this vulnerability affects OpenSSL versions 1.0.1 through 1.0.1f (inclusive). The Heartbleed bug is not a flaw in the SSL or TLS protocols; rather, it is a flaw in the OpenSSL implementation of the TLS/DTLS heartbeat functionality. The flaw is not related or introduced by publicly trusted certificates and is instead a problem with server software.</description></item><item><title>Reducing the Impact of Government Spying</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/04/reducing-the-impact-of-government-spying/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/04/reducing-the-impact-of-government-spying/</guid><description>Last year, Edward Snowden, an American computer-specialist working as a contractor for the National Security Agency (“NSA”), shocked web-users around the world by publicizing documents showing that the NSA was gathering intelligence on Internet users. The realization that the US government was gathering sensitive information has led to a worldwide demand for better protection of online communication and data and a general worry about the effectiveness of existing infrastructures. Specifically, some entities have asked whether PKI is still a robust way to protect online information.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Members Presentation at RSA 2014 Conference: New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</guid><description>CA Security Council (CASC) members Trend Micro, Go Daddy, and Symantec participated in a discussion panel at the 2014 RSA Conference in San Francisco on February 24 entitled “New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet.” Panel members included Kirk Hall of Trend Micro (Moderator), Wayne Thayer of GoDaddy (Panelist), and Rick Andrews of Symantec (Panelist).
Introduction to the Topic Hall began by introducing the topic – all three alternative technologies (Certificate Transparency or CT, Certificate Authority Authorization or CAA, and Certificate Pinning) are intended to make the internet safer by dealing with mis-issued digital certificates, including so-called “rogue” certs like those obtained by a hacker from the now-defunct Diginotar Certification Authority (CA).</description></item><item><title>ICANN’s Accelerated gTLD Delegation Process and How This Impacts Your Organization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</guid><description>After the CASC’s previous letter addressing ICANN’s proposal to delegate nearly 2000 new gTLDs for use on the public Internet, ICANN identified and initiated an extensive study on two significant security issues. Now, based on the conclusions of the studies, ICANN is moving forward quickly with the delegation process, delegating more than 30 in the last two months alone. With ICANN ramping up the delegation process, nearly all 2000 will be delegated under the new rules, with only .</description></item><item><title>Securing Software Distribution with Digital Code Signing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/10/16/securing-software-distribution-with-digital-code-signing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 18:16:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/10/16/securing-software-distribution-with-digital-code-signing/</guid><description>Code signing certificates from publicly trusted Certification Authorities (CAs) fulfill a vital need for authentication of software distributed over the Internet in our interconnected world. As the commonly referred to “Internet of things” continues to grow, consumers have access to millions of applications for their desktops, laptops, and mobile devices. Creative software engineers provide us with applications to cover any of our potential needs or interests. Cybercriminals and others with malicious intent recognize this as an opportunity and seek to trick us into installing malicious software (malware) — programs that hijack our computers, steal our money, or try to inflict harm.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Authority Audits and Browser Root Program Requirements</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/10/15/certificate-authority-audits-and-browser-root-program-requirements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/10/15/certificate-authority-audits-and-browser-root-program-requirements/</guid><description>Recent news stories have highlighted the need for strong security in online communications, and use of SSL certificates issued by a publicly trusted Certification Authority (CA) is perhaps the best way to achieve that. But why should the public trust SSL certificates issued from commercial CA roots, which are embedded as trust anchors in web browsers?
One answer is because of the multiple layers of standards and tough requirements that all commercial CAs must meet – and for which they are audited every year.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2: Configuration</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 01:19:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</guid><description>They say the most complicated skill is to be simple; despite SSL and HTTPS having been around for a long time, they still are not as simple as they could be.
One of the reasons for this is that the security industry is constantly learning more about how to design and build secure systems; as a result, the protocols and software used to secure online services need to continuously evolve to keep up with the latest risks.</description></item><item><title>5 Tips for SMBs to Help Secure Their Online Presence</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/17/5-tips-for-smbs-to-help-secure-their-online-presence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 20:12:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/17/5-tips-for-smbs-to-help-secure-their-online-presence/</guid><description>With National SMB Week upon us, the CASC has come up with its five tips for SMBs to help secure their online presence. By implementing these simple steps SMBs can build trust and loyalty by ensuring their website is safe to visit, search, enter personal information, or complete a transaction.
Create unbreakable passwords – Strong passwords are essential on any account related to your online presence (domain registrar, hosting account, SSL provider, social media, PayPal, etc.</description></item><item><title>Some Comments on Web Security</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/05/some-comments-on-web-security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 02:23:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/05/some-comments-on-web-security/</guid><description>Steve Johnson of the Mercury News posted an article on Web security and highlighted some of the issues.
The posted issues help to explain why we created the Certificate Authority Security Council. We want to determine the issues, have them addressed and provide awareness and education on the solutions. The CAs also work with the browsers and other experts in the industry to develop standards for all CAs to be audited against through the CA/Browser Forum.</description></item><item><title>CAs Support Standards and Regulations</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/10/cas-support-standards-and-regulations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 19:40:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/10/cas-support-standards-and-regulations/</guid><description>There is an industry myth that certification authorities (CAs) are not regulated. In fact publicly-trusted SSL CAs support the development of industry regulations and have been audited annually to ensure compliance to the many requirements.
To provide some history, SSL CAs have always self-policed themselves by having external audits performed. In the ‘90s, the CAs wrote certificate policies and certification practice statements requiring annual compliance audits. Since there were no CA audit criteria, the CAs contracted for SAS 70 audits.</description></item><item><title>Recap of NIST’s Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/17/recap-of-nists-workshop-on-improving-trust-in-the-online-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 18:29:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/17/recap-of-nists-workshop-on-improving-trust-in-the-online-marketplace/</guid><description>On April 10 and 11, NIST held a workshop in Maryland to bring together many parties (industry, research and academia communities, and government sectors) to examine “technical and administrative efforts to increase trust online by improving the Public Key Infrastructure certificate marketplace supporting SSL and TLS.”
From the opening keynote to the final remarks, we heard from experts around the world. There were presentations on the current state of trust infrastructure and audits, the impact of recent breaches, detailed looks on some emerging solutions like Certificate Transparency and DANE, and new ideas to manage and minimize risk in key usage.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at NIST</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</guid><description>This week members of the CASC will be attending and speaking at the NIST Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace. You can also follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Even if you can’t make it to Maryland, you can still watch the event via the live webcast. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item><item><title>What the ICANN SSAC Report Doesn’t Tell You</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/22/what-the-icann-ssac-report-doesnt-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:19:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/22/what-the-icann-ssac-report-doesnt-tell-you/</guid><description>The CA Security Council, which comprises seven of the largest CAs, read with interest the article titled, “Internal-use SSL certificates pose security risk for upcoming domain extensions.” As a group in one of the best positions to understand the impact of the new gTLDs on organizational security infrastructure and the Internet as a whole, we felt it appropriate to comment on this and related stories which summarize the ICANN Security and Stability Advisory Committee (SSAC) report sac 045 Invalid Top Level Domain Queries at the Root Level of the Domain Name System.</description></item></channel></rss>