<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BEAST on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/beast/</link><description>Recent content in BEAST on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 19:30:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/beast/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Heartbleed Bug Vulnerability: Discovery, Impact and Solution</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/09/heartbleed-bug-vulnerability-discovery-impact-and-solution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 19:30:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/09/heartbleed-bug-vulnerability-discovery-impact-and-solution/</guid><description>On April 7, 2014, a vulnerability in the OpenSSL cryptographic library was announced to the Internet community. Aptly labeled as the Heartbleed bug, this vulnerability affects OpenSSL versions 1.0.1 through 1.0.1f (inclusive). The Heartbleed bug is not a flaw in the SSL or TLS protocols; rather, it is a flaw in the OpenSSL implementation of the TLS/DTLS heartbeat functionality. The flaw is not related or introduced by publicly trusted certificates and is instead a problem with server software.</description></item><item><title>2014 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 20:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2013 Protocol Attacks The year started with a couple of SSL/TLS protocol attacks: Lucky Thirteen and RC4 attack. Lucky Thirteen allows the decryption of sensitive information, such as passwords and cookies, when using the CBC-mode cipher suite. Lucky Thirteen can be mitigated by implementing software patches or preferring the cipher suite RC4.
That being said, RC4 was also attacked, where through 16 million sessions a small amount of plaintext can be recovered.</description></item><item><title>It’s Time for TLS 1.2</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/19/its-time-for-tls-1.2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/19/its-time-for-tls-1.2/</guid><description>In a previous post titled Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2, we touched on the recommendation that Web servers be configured to prefer Transport Layer Security (TLS) version 1.2. With the planned release of Firefox 24 and recent release of Chrome 29 adding support for TLS 1.2, now is a great time for website administrators to make the switch.
Transport Layer Security was formerly called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and is the protocol that enables secure “https://” connections to websites.</description></item><item><title>RSA Recap – Securing Your Site</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/08/rsa-recap-securing-your-site/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/08/rsa-recap-securing-your-site/</guid><description>At RSA last week a few of us participated in panel discussions that focused on SSL/TLS. During the panel that I moderated on Friday, one theme we addressed was secure server configuration. One of CASC’s goals is to help harden existing SSL/TLS implementations against vulnerabilities—because most SSL/TLS exploits arise from suboptimal website configurations. These vulnerabilities and attacks can be mitigated or even eliminated with proper server configuration and good website design.</description></item></channel></rss>