<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Doug Beattie on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/authors/doug-beattie/</link><description>Recent content in Doug Beattie on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/authors/doug-beattie/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>The Advantages of Short-Lived SSL Certificates for the Enterprise</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/07/18/the-advantages-of-short-lived-ssl-certificates-for-the-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 18:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/07/18/the-advantages-of-short-lived-ssl-certificates-for-the-enterprise/</guid><description>Short validity period certificates are becoming ever more common to reduce the scope of data compromised if a server vulnerability is uncovered, such as HeartBleed. Good security practice dictates changing keys on a regular basis, normally annually, but if you want to limit your exposure further, you can replace your certificates and underlying keys more frequently.
Sandstorm is an open source server software that makes it easy to install web apps.</description></item><item><title>What Are Subordinate CAs and Why Would You Want Your Own?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</guid><description>Digital certificate and PKI adoption has changed quite a bit in recent years. Gone are the days where certificates were only synonymous with SSL/TLS; compliance drivers like stronger authentication requirements and digital signature regulations (e.g. eIDAS) have greatly expanded the role of PKI within the enterprise.
As PKI usage has expanded, conversation has moved beyond just the number and type of certificates needed and onto deeper dialogue about custom PKI deployments.</description></item><item><title>Lenovo Enables Man-in-the-Middle Attacks Via Superfish Adware</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/02/20/lenovo-enables-man-in-the-middle-attacks-via-superfish-adware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 22:27:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/02/20/lenovo-enables-man-in-the-middle-attacks-via-superfish-adware/</guid><description>Lenovo is selling computers that contain the Superfish application which “supplements” the user’s SSL sessions to enable their adware application to deliver content transparently; however, due to poor security design this leaves users vulnerable to man-in-the-middle attacks.
How it was supposed to work Superfish uses the program “Visual Discovery” to process images in browser content and then displays ads for similar goods and services. This sounds like any other adware application, but in order to maintain SSL sessions and not alert users with security warnings, Superfish is serving up these images over https.</description></item></channel></rss>