<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PKI on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/pki/</link><description>Recent content in PKI on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/pki/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Year Certs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</guid><description>Starting on September 1st, SSL/TLS certificates cannot be issued for longer than 13 months (397 days). This change was first announced by Apple at the CA/Browser Forum Spring Face-to-Face event in Bratislava back in March.</description></item><item><title>5 Ways to Keep Up with Authentication Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/02/24/5-ways-to-keep-up-with-authentication-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 13:38:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/02/24/5-ways-to-keep-up-with-authentication-certificates/</guid><description>When it comes to protecting an organization’s data and users, CISOs have no shortage of hurdles. Identity attacks have become sophisticated and convincing, thanks to ransomware, phishing and deep fakes. CISOs have long known the importance of strong identification and authentication controls, but with threats constantly changing and intensifying, having these controls in place is just one piece of the puzzle; they must be managed correctly in order to do their job.</description></item><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>9 Common Myths About CAs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</guid><description>Over the years misconceptions about CAs and the SSL infrastructure have arisen. Below is a list of common myths related to SSL and CAs.
Myth #1: CAs are not regulated Fact: CAs are subject to various checks and balances, including third-party qualified audits through WebTrust or ETSI and strict criteria set forth by leading browsers, before they are accepted in browser root stores. Similarly, the CA/Browser Forum’s Baseline Requirements and Network Security Guidelines establish global standards for certificate issuance and CA controls that will soon be included in third-party auditing standards.</description></item><item><title>What Are Subordinate CAs and Why Would You Want Your Own?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</guid><description>Digital certificate and PKI adoption has changed quite a bit in recent years. Gone are the days where certificates were only synonymous with SSL/TLS; compliance drivers like stronger authentication requirements and digital signature regulations (e.g. eIDAS) have greatly expanded the role of PKI within the enterprise.
As PKI usage has expanded, conversation has moved beyond just the number and type of certificates needed and onto deeper dialogue about custom PKI deployments.</description></item><item><title>2019 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2018 2018 was an active year for SSL/TLS. We saw the SSL/TLS certificate validity period drop to 825-days and the mass deployment of Certificate Transparency (CT). TLS 1.3 protocol was finally completed and published; and Chrome status bar security indicators changing to remove “secure” and to concentrate on “not secure.” The CA/Browser Forum has been reformed, the London Protocol was announced and the nearly full distrust of Symantec SSL completed.</description></item><item><title>2018 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2017 2017 saw the end of SHA-1 in public trust SSL/TLS certificates and the start of Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) allowing domain owners to authorize their CA. A “Not secure” browser indication was propagated to push more websites to support HTTPS. There was also a change in the certification authority (CA) ownership with DigiCert acquiring Symantec’s SSL and related PKI business and Francisco Partners buying Comodo’s CA.</description></item><item><title>How Does the ROCA Attack Work?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/11/09/how-does-the-roca-attack-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 19:08:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/11/09/how-does-the-roca-attack-work/</guid><description>On October 17th, a group of Czech researchers announced they had found a way to factor the moduli of many RSA public keys generated by hardware produced by Infineon Technologies AG. The technical details were presented in a paper at the 2017 Computer and Communications Security conference, hosted by the Association for Computing Machinery on November 2nd.
The technique only works against the key pairs produced by Infineon’s library, because it exploits the unique method they use to generate RSA primes.</description></item><item><title>Quantum Computing: Real or Exaggerated Threat to the Web PKI?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/08/30/quantum-computing-real-or-exaggerated-threat-to-the-web-pki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 20:14:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/08/30/quantum-computing-real-or-exaggerated-threat-to-the-web-pki/</guid><description>Twenty years ago, paying your phone or electric bill involved receiving it in the mail, writing a check and mailing it back to the company. Today, that has largely been replaced by email and web-based payment submittals. All of this is secured by digital certificates and encryption, which provide privacy and authentication of information transiting the open Internet (aka Web PKI).
The web PKI is predominantly secured by RSA encryption algorithms; mathematical theorems which have been improved over time.</description></item><item><title>The Latest on Certification Authority Authorization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/03/21/the-latest-on-certification-authority-authorization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 20:40:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/03/21/the-latest-on-certification-authority-authorization/</guid><description>Things are certainly heating up at the CA/Browser with exciting proposals surrounding inclusion of the Wi-Fi Alliance (WFA) as a subjectAltName otherName, new validation methods, and debates over how the CAB Forum will continue operating. One of these newly passed ballots requires all CAs to check and process a domain name’s DNS Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) resource record prior to issuing a digital certificate.
Background RFC 6844 created CAA records as a method for domain owners to specify a policy on which certificate authorities are authorized to issue certificates for the associated domain.</description></item><item><title>TLS Certificates on the Web – The Good, The Bad and The Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/05/17/tls-certificates-on-the-web-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/05/17/tls-certificates-on-the-web-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>It might be hard to believe, but the SSL/TLS Ecosystem is nearly 20 years old. It’s time to take stock and see how we’re doing with regards to TLS certificates. In this article, we’ll primarily discuss certificates themselves and not web server configuration, although that is often a source of problems.
In the last few years, we’ve endured three major certificate-based migrations:
Away from the MD2 and MD5 hash algorithms to SHA-1 Away from small RSA keys to 2048-bit keys or larger Away from the SHA-1 hash algorithm to SHA-256 What’s driving these migrations?</description></item><item><title>2015 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/01/06/2015-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2014 End of 1024-Bit Security In 2014, the SSL industry moved to issuing a minimum security of 2048-bit RSA certificates. Keys smaller than 2048 are no longer allowed in server certificates. In addition, Microsoft and Mozilla started to remove 1024-bit roots from their certificate stores. Hopefully, the key size change will support users through to 2030.
Push to Perfect Forward Secrecy Following the Edward Snowden revelations of pervasive surveillance, there was a big push to configure web servers to support Perfect Forward Secrecy.</description></item><item><title>In the Wake of Unauthorized Certificate Issuance by the Indian CA NIC, can Government CAs Still be Considered “Trusted Third Parties”?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</guid><description>Short answer: Government CAs can still be considered “trusted third parties,” provided that they follow the rules applicable to commercial CAs.
Introduction On July 8 Google announced that it had discovered several unauthorized Google certificates issued by the National Informatics Centre of India. It noted that the Indian government CA’s certificates were in the Microsoft Root Store and used by programs on the Windows platform. The Firefox browser on Windows uses its own root store and didn’t have these CA certificates.</description></item><item><title>Reducing the Impact of Government Spying</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/04/reducing-the-impact-of-government-spying/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/04/reducing-the-impact-of-government-spying/</guid><description>Last year, Edward Snowden, an American computer-specialist working as a contractor for the National Security Agency (“NSA”), shocked web-users around the world by publicizing documents showing that the NSA was gathering intelligence on Internet users. The realization that the US government was gathering sensitive information has led to a worldwide demand for better protection of online communication and data and a general worry about the effectiveness of existing infrastructures. Specifically, some entities have asked whether PKI is still a robust way to protect online information.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Reputation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/28/certificate-reputation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/28/certificate-reputation/</guid><description>One of the advantages of having multiple certification authorities (CAs) from which to choose an SSL certificate is that customers have flexibility to choose a CA that meets their specific needs, or even use a number of CAs for redundancy or to have access to a broader toolset. The disadvantage for end users, however, is that they often may not know if a particular CA was authorized to issue the certificate, and there could be a chance that the certificate was fraudulently obtained.</description></item><item><title>CA Day in Berlin</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/24/ca-day-in-berlin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 18:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/24/ca-day-in-berlin/</guid><description>“CA Day” (also known as CA Conformity Assessment) was hosted by the German company TuVIT in Berlin on January 16, 2014. In attendance were approximately 100 people from mostly European CAs. Under the European regulatory framework, CAs are included in a group referred to as “Trust Service Providers” or “TSPs.” CASC members in attendance at CA Day were Symantec, Digicert and Comodo. The dominant theme for this CA Day was the draft Regulation on Electronic identification and trust services for electronic transactions in the internal market (eIDAS) and upcoming changes in EU regulations for Qualified Certificates, which was briefed by Gerard Galler from the European Commission and discussed in greater detail by several European TSPs.</description></item><item><title>2014 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 20:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/01/06/2014-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2013 Protocol Attacks The year started with a couple of SSL/TLS protocol attacks: Lucky Thirteen and RC4 attack. Lucky Thirteen allows the decryption of sensitive information, such as passwords and cookies, when using the CBC-mode cipher suite. Lucky Thirteen can be mitigated by implementing software patches or preferring the cipher suite RC4.
That being said, RC4 was also attacked, where through 16 million sessions a small amount of plaintext can be recovered.</description></item><item><title>ICANN’s Accelerated gTLD Delegation Process and How This Impacts Your Organization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</guid><description>After the CASC’s previous letter addressing ICANN’s proposal to delegate nearly 2000 new gTLDs for use on the public Internet, ICANN identified and initiated an extensive study on two significant security issues. Now, based on the conclusions of the studies, ICANN is moving forward quickly with the delegation process, delegating more than 30 in the last two months alone. With ICANN ramping up the delegation process, nearly all 2000 will be delegated under the new rules, with only .</description></item><item><title>SHA-1 Deprecation, On to SHA-2</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/12/16/sha-1-deprecation-on-to-sha-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 20:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/12/16/sha-1-deprecation-on-to-sha-2/</guid><description>We have previously reviewed implementation of SHA-2, but with Bruce Schneier stating the need to migrate away from SHA-1 and the SHA-1 deprecation policy from Microsoft, the industry must make more progress in 2014.
Web server administrators will have to make plans to move from SSL and code signing certificates signed with the SHA-1 hashing algorithm to certificates signed with SHA-2. This is the result of the new Microsoft Root Certificate Policy where Microsoft deprecates SHA-1 and imposes the following requirements:</description></item><item><title>IETF 88 – Pervasive Surveillance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/26/ietf-88-pervasive-surveillance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 19:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/26/ietf-88-pervasive-surveillance/</guid><description>Internet Surveillance The big news at IETF 88 in Vancouver was the technical plenary on Hardening the Internet which discussed the issue of pervasive surveillance. Pervasive surveillance is a mass surveillance of an entire or a substantial fraction of a population. The surveillance is usually carried out by government, is not targeted and its occurrence may not be overt. It was noted that pervasive surveillance, of the kind revealed in the Snowden-sourced documents, constitutes a misguided and damaging attack on civic society in general and the Internet in particular.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Chains, Key Management and the Number of CAs Counted by Web Crawlers – Oh My</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/04/certificate-chains-key-management-and-the-number-of-cas-counted-by-web-crawlers-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/04/certificate-chains-key-management-and-the-number-of-cas-counted-by-web-crawlers-oh-my/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why your web server certificate has a “chain” of other certificates associated with it?
The main reason is so that browsers can tell if your certificate was issued by an organization that has been verified to meet the security, policy and operational practices that all Publicly Trusted Certificate Authorities are mandated to meet. That certificate at the top of the chain is commonly called the “root.” It’s signature on a certificate below it indicates that the organization operating the root believes that practices of the CA below it meets that same high bar.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2: Configuration</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 01:19:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</guid><description>They say the most complicated skill is to be simple; despite SSL and HTTPS having been around for a long time, they still are not as simple as they could be.
One of the reasons for this is that the security industry is constantly learning more about how to design and build secure systems; as a result, the protocols and software used to secure online services need to continuously evolve to keep up with the latest risks.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at NIST</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/10/casc-happenings-at-nist/</guid><description>This week members of the CASC will be attending and speaking at the NIST Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace. You can also follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Even if you can’t make it to Maryland, you can still watch the event via the live webcast. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item><item><title>IETF 86 – Web PKI Working Group</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:07:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</guid><description>At the IETF 86 meeting in Orlando last week, there was a working group meeting discussing the operations of the Web PKI. At the previous IETF 85 meeting a birds-of-a-feather was held to discuss the purpose of having such a group. The result of the meeting was an established group with the charter that states purposes such as:
Working group will work to improve the consistency of Web security behavior Address problems as seen by the end-users, certificate holders and CAs Describe how the Web PKI actually works Prepare documented deliverables as discussed below The meeting discussed the charter and the four following deliverables.</description></item><item><title>CASC Happenings at RSA</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/25/casc-happenings-at-rsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 15:32:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/25/casc-happenings-at-rsa/</guid><description>We are excited to have members of the CASC attending and speaking at this year’s RSA Conference. The events and panels will cover various topics that revolve around the security of the Internet and CAs as a whole. You can follow the CASC on Twitter for more information and news at @CertCouncil, as well as see some of the presentations after the events on our SlideShare page. Please join us for the following CASC member events:</description></item></channel></rss>