<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Revocation on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/revocation/</link><description>Recent content in Revocation on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:52:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/revocation/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Insecure Elephant in the Room</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/10/10/the-insecure-elephant-in-the-room/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:52:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/10/10/the-insecure-elephant-in-the-room/</guid><description>The purpose of this article The purpose of this article is to demonstrate why I believe browser-based UI for website identity can make the web safer for everyone. I explain in great detail, the reasons why the UI and UX didn’t work in the past. And what’s left is only making the problem worse instead of better.
Some people seem to find it difficult to consume my thoughts about the enforcement of “HTTPS EVERYWHERE”, free DV certs and the browser padlock.</description></item><item><title>9 Common Myths About CAs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/08/01/9-common-myths-about-cas/</guid><description>Over the years misconceptions about CAs and the SSL infrastructure have arisen. Below is a list of common myths related to SSL and CAs.
Myth #1: CAs are not regulated Fact: CAs are subject to various checks and balances, including third-party qualified audits through WebTrust or ETSI and strict criteria set forth by leading browsers, before they are accepted in browser root stores. Similarly, the CA/Browser Forum’s Baseline Requirements and Network Security Guidelines establish global standards for certificate issuance and CA controls that will soon be included in third-party auditing standards.</description></item><item><title>The Advantages of Short-Lived SSL Certificates for the Enterprise</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/07/18/the-advantages-of-short-lived-ssl-certificates-for-the-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 18:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/07/18/the-advantages-of-short-lived-ssl-certificates-for-the-enterprise/</guid><description>Short validity period certificates are becoming ever more common to reduce the scope of data compromised if a server vulnerability is uncovered, such as HeartBleed. Good security practice dictates changing keys on a regular basis, normally annually, but if you want to limit your exposure further, you can replace your certificates and underlying keys more frequently.
Sandstorm is an open source server software that makes it easy to install web apps.</description></item><item><title>What Are Subordinate CAs and Why Would You Want Your Own?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</guid><description>Digital certificate and PKI adoption has changed quite a bit in recent years. Gone are the days where certificates were only synonymous with SSL/TLS; compliance drivers like stronger authentication requirements and digital signature regulations (e.g. eIDAS) have greatly expanded the role of PKI within the enterprise.
As PKI usage has expanded, conversation has moved beyond just the number and type of certificates needed and onto deeper dialogue about custom PKI deployments.</description></item><item><title>2019 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/01/03/2019-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2018 2018 was an active year for SSL/TLS. We saw the SSL/TLS certificate validity period drop to 825-days and the mass deployment of Certificate Transparency (CT). TLS 1.3 protocol was finally completed and published; and Chrome status bar security indicators changing to remove “secure” and to concentrate on “not secure.” The CA/Browser Forum has been reformed, the London Protocol was announced and the nearly full distrust of Symantec SSL completed.</description></item><item><title>2017 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 21:11:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/01/13/2017-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2016 Fortunately, 2016 was not a year full of SSL/TLS vulnerabilities. Although some researchers did prove old cryptography algorithms should be put out to pasture. The year showed the end of public-trusted SHA-1 SSL/TLS certificates. It also showed more transparency should be considered due to issues discovered with a few certification authorities (CAs). The great news is HTTPS is no longer the minority — after 20 years, connections using HTTPS has surpassed HTTP.</description></item><item><title>Leading Certificate Authorities and Microsoft Introduce New Standards to Protect Consumers Online</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 21:05:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</guid><description>San Francisco –December 8, 2016 – the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement web security, today announced the Code Signing Working Group has released new Minimum Requirements for Code Signing for use by all Certificate Authorities (CA). These requirements represent the first-ever standardized code signing guidelines. Code signing is the method of using a certificate-based digital signature to sign executables and scripts in order to verify the author’s identity and ensure that the code has not been changed or corrupted.</description></item><item><title>Minimum Requirements for Code Signing Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/07/20/minimum-requirements-for-code-signing-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 20:47:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/07/20/minimum-requirements-for-code-signing-certificates/</guid><description>It is time for an update on the Baseline Requirements for Code Signing.
First the bad news, the new standard was not approved by the CA/Browser Forum due to philosophical differences among some forum members who felt code signing was not in scope with the Forum’s charter.
The good news is the document was created in a multi-stakeholder environment and substantially improves the current management processes. As such, it was decided to bring the document outside of the forum and finalize it as part of the CA Security Council.</description></item><item><title>2016 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/12/14/2016-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2015 A number of new tactics proved 2015 was no exception to an active year defending against ever increasing security issues. Vendors found new and creative ways to provide vulnerabilities including the now popular man-in-the-middle (MitM) attacks. MitM as well as a host of other new vulnerabilities caused browsers to rethink their security requirements. This article gives a flashback of the exploits and industry changes from 2015 and looks ahead at the latest security requirements and how it impacts IT security teams.</description></item><item><title>Extra Trips are for Frequent Flyers, Not SSL/TLS Performance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/10/30/extra-trips-are-for-frequent-flyers-not-ssl/tls-performance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 16:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/10/30/extra-trips-are-for-frequent-flyers-not-ssl/tls-performance/</guid><description>TLS is quickly becoming a de facto requirement for every website due to increased concerns about spying and Google’s recent move to use HTTPS as a factor in search engine ranking. In a recent article we explained how HSTS helps website operators to ensure that their site is always using TLS, but now we want to ensure that your performance isn’t sacrificed in the name of enhanced security. While the myth that TLS slows down a website has been debunked, some basic settings can make a site using TLS even faster.</description></item><item><title>Who Sets the Rules Governing Certification Authorities?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 15:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/19/who-sets-the-rules-governing-certification-authorities/</guid><description>Every time something positive is published about SSL and encryption,such as Google’s recent decision making use of https encryption a favorable rating factor for a website, or negative, such as the Heartbleed issue – bloggers and others always post questions about public Certification Authorities (CAs), including general questions on who sets the rules that govern CAs. Some bloggers seem to assume there are no rules or standards, and that CAs can operate without any requirements or limitations at all — that’s incorrect.</description></item><item><title>In the Wake of Unauthorized Certificate Issuance by the Indian CA NIC, can Government CAs Still be Considered “Trusted Third Parties”?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</guid><description>Short answer: Government CAs can still be considered “trusted third parties,” provided that they follow the rules applicable to commercial CAs.
Introduction On July 8 Google announced that it had discovered several unauthorized Google certificates issued by the National Informatics Centre of India. It noted that the Indian government CA’s certificates were in the Microsoft Root Store and used by programs on the Windows platform. The Firefox browser on Windows uses its own root store and didn’t have these CA certificates.</description></item><item><title>OCSP Must-Staple</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/06/18/ocsp-must-staple/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 18:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/06/18/ocsp-must-staple/</guid><description>With the announcement of the Heartbleed bug and the resulting need to revoke large numbers of SSL certificates, the topic of certificate revocation has, once again, come to the fore.
There have been many issues with how revocation information is provided to the browsers. First let’s review how SSL certificate status may currently be obtained: How
| How | Definition | Pros | Cons | | signed list of the serial numbers of all revoked certificates that were signed by the CA’s certificate.</description></item><item><title>CASC Heartbleed Response</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/05/08/casc-heartbleed-response/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 15:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/05/08/casc-heartbleed-response/</guid><description>The recent Heartbleed issue has reawakened interest in SSL certificate revocation (see Adam Langley’s blog, Larry Seltzer’s articles here and here, and Steve Gibson’s web pages)
Several years ago, the CA Browser Forum convened a special Revocation Working Group to explore issues and solutions. Leading CAs were actively involved in that group, and many of them invested in moving their OCSP responders to high-performance, high-availability Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) to respond to browser vendors’ requests for increased performance and reliability.</description></item><item><title>Revocation – A Cure For the Common Heartbleed</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/04/28/revocation-a-cure-for-the-common-heartbleed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 21:47:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/04/28/revocation-a-cure-for-the-common-heartbleed/</guid><description>The Heartbleed bug spurred server administrators worldwide to work closely with Certification Authorities (CAs) in rekeying and reissuing potentially vulnerable SSL certificates. Part of this effort included revoking existing certificates used on vulnerable servers to ensure obtained private keys are not later used in a man-in-the-middle attack against the website. Unfortunately, in recent days, certain news reports and blogs addressing certificate revocation and checking for revoked certificates online have failed to discuss the benefits of revocation, instead focusing on the minority of circumstances where widely deployed revocation is not perfect.</description></item><item><title>CA Security Council Members Presentation at RSA 2014 Conference: New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/17/ca-security-council-members-presentation-at-rsa-2014-conference-new-ideas-on-caa-ct-and-public-key-pinning-for-a-safer-internet/</guid><description>CA Security Council (CASC) members Trend Micro, Go Daddy, and Symantec participated in a discussion panel at the 2014 RSA Conference in San Francisco on February 24 entitled “New Ideas on CAA, CT, and Public Key Pinning for a Safer Internet.” Panel members included Kirk Hall of Trend Micro (Moderator), Wayne Thayer of GoDaddy (Panelist), and Rick Andrews of Symantec (Panelist).
Introduction to the Topic Hall began by introducing the topic – all three alternative technologies (Certificate Transparency or CT, Certificate Authority Authorization or CAA, and Certificate Pinning) are intended to make the internet safer by dealing with mis-issued digital certificates, including so-called “rogue” certs like those obtained by a hacker from the now-defunct Diginotar Certification Authority (CA).</description></item><item><title>ICANN’s Accelerated gTLD Delegation Process and How This Impacts Your Organization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/12/18/icanns-accelerated-gtld-delegation-process-and-how-this-impacts-your-organization/</guid><description>After the CASC’s previous letter addressing ICANN’s proposal to delegate nearly 2000 new gTLDs for use on the public Internet, ICANN identified and initiated an extensive study on two significant security issues. Now, based on the conclusions of the studies, ICANN is moving forward quickly with the delegation process, delegating more than 30 in the last two months alone. With ICANN ramping up the delegation process, nearly all 2000 will be delegated under the new rules, with only .</description></item><item><title>IETF 88 – Pervasive Surveillance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/26/ietf-88-pervasive-surveillance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 19:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/26/ietf-88-pervasive-surveillance/</guid><description>Internet Surveillance The big news at IETF 88 in Vancouver was the technical plenary on Hardening the Internet which discussed the issue of pervasive surveillance. Pervasive surveillance is a mass surveillance of an entire or a substantial fraction of a population. The surveillance is usually carried out by government, is not targeted and its occurrence may not be overt. It was noted that pervasive surveillance, of the kind revealed in the Snowden-sourced documents, constitutes a misguided and damaging attack on civic society in general and the Internet in particular.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Chains, Key Management and the Number of CAs Counted by Web Crawlers – Oh My</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/04/certificate-chains-key-management-and-the-number-of-cas-counted-by-web-crawlers-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/04/certificate-chains-key-management-and-the-number-of-cas-counted-by-web-crawlers-oh-my/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why your web server certificate has a “chain” of other certificates associated with it?
The main reason is so that browsers can tell if your certificate was issued by an organization that has been verified to meet the security, policy and operational practices that all Publicly Trusted Certificate Authorities are mandated to meet. That certificate at the top of the chain is commonly called the “root.” It’s signature on a certificate below it indicates that the organization operating the root believes that practices of the CA below it meets that same high bar.</description></item><item><title>The (Soon to Be) Not-So Common Name</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/10/08/the-soon-to-be-not-so-common-name/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/10/08/the-soon-to-be-not-so-common-name/</guid><description>If you are reading this post you are probably already familiar with the use of digital certificates and SSL even if you may not be familiar with the history. Before exploring the history of SSL, let’s review at its core what a digital certificate actually is. Fundamentally, a digital certificate is the binding of entitlements and constraints to a key, in other words a digital certificate would dictate the following, “The holder of the private key associated with this certificate can rightfully use the name John Smith when signing emails.</description></item><item><title>What Is Certificate Transparency and How Does It Propose to Address Certificate Mis-Issuance?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/09/what-is-certificate-transparency-and-how-does-it-propose-to-address-certificate-mis-issuance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/09/what-is-certificate-transparency-and-how-does-it-propose-to-address-certificate-mis-issuance/</guid><description>As originally architected by Netscape and others in the mid-1990s, the certificate issuance process envisioned that the CA would present the certificate and its contents to the named subject who would review and accept the certificate first. Then the CA would publish the certificate to a repository. That process would establish that the certificate’s subject was aware of certificate issuance. (Otherwise, an unscrupulous CA could sign a subscriber’s public key and create a certificate for the subscriber without its knowledge.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to OCSP Multi-Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 21:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</guid><description>OCSP Stapling OCSP is a protocol used to check the validity of certificates to make sure they have not been revoked. OCSP is an alternative to Certificate Revocation Lists (CRLs). Since OCSP responses can be as small as a few hundred bytes, OCSP is particularly useful when the issuing CA has relatively big CRLs, as well as when the client has limited memory and processing power.
OCSP can also provide much more timely information than CRLs about the status of a certificate since the information is generally fetched more frequently.</description></item><item><title>Recap of NIST’s Workshop on Improving Trust in the Online Marketplace</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/04/17/recap-of-nists-workshop-on-improving-trust-in-the-online-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 18:29:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/04/17/recap-of-nists-workshop-on-improving-trust-in-the-online-marketplace/</guid><description>On April 10 and 11, NIST held a workshop in Maryland to bring together many parties (industry, research and academia communities, and government sectors) to examine “technical and administrative efforts to increase trust online by improving the Public Key Infrastructure certificate marketplace supporting SSL and TLS.”
From the opening keynote to the final remarks, we heard from experts around the world. There were presentations on the current state of trust infrastructure and audits, the impact of recent breaches, detailed looks on some emerging solutions like Certificate Transparency and DANE, and new ideas to manage and minimize risk in key usage.</description></item><item><title>IETF 86 – Web PKI Working Group</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:07:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/21/ietf-86-web-pki-working-group/</guid><description>At the IETF 86 meeting in Orlando last week, there was a working group meeting discussing the operations of the Web PKI. At the previous IETF 85 meeting a birds-of-a-feather was held to discuss the purpose of having such a group. The result of the meeting was an established group with the charter that states purposes such as:
Working group will work to improve the consistency of Web security behavior Address problems as seen by the end-users, certificate holders and CAs Describe how the Web PKI actually works Prepare documented deliverables as discussed below The meeting discussed the charter and the four following deliverables.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Revocation Checking Part 2: A Real World Example</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/11/the-importance-of-revocation-checking-part-2-a-real-world-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 16:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/11/the-importance-of-revocation-checking-part-2-a-real-world-example/</guid><description>Just last week, a new security incident related to certificate revocation checking made headlines. It was discovered that a legitimate website was hosting a malicious Java application that installed malware on the computers of people who visited the site. This comes after recent updates that introduced Security Level settings in Java, and then raised the default from Medium to High. At the high level, users are shown a warning before any unsigned Java code is executed.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Checking for Certificate Revocation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/09/the-importance-of-checking-for-certificate-revocation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 03:50:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/09/the-importance-of-checking-for-certificate-revocation/</guid><description>Certificates are typically valid for one to three years, and during that time it’s possible that the web site owner or the CA realizes that end users should not trust the certificate. There are several cases in which this might happen, including these:
The web site owner ceases doing business, no longer owns the domain name used in the certificate, has changed their organization name, or wishes to shut down the web server.</description></item><item><title>OCSP Stapling: Improved Performance and Security, a Win-Win</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/ocsp-stapling-improved-performance-and-security-a-win-win/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 16:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/ocsp-stapling-improved-performance-and-security-a-win-win/</guid><description>The launch of the CASC has given its members a unique platform through which we can educate users about online security and the best practices in utilizing SSL. That’s why we’ve decided to pair the group’s launch with a focused effort on OCSP stapling.
Why OCSP stapling? For one, stapling is already supported by IIS and the newest versions of Apache and nginx. Although server software does not enable OCSP by default, servers can be re-configured with a little education.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Revocation and OCSP Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</guid><description>Revocation As a body of global CAs, the CA Security Council is committed to educating server administrators, end-users and other interested parties about SSL enhancements and best practices that can better protect everyone. An important initiative that can make a practical difference right now is addressing easily implemented improvements to certificate status services that handle revocation of invalid or expired certificates, specifically the implementation of OCSP stapling.
What is certificate revocation?</description></item><item><title>World’s Leading Certificate Authorities Come Together to Advance Internet Security and the Trusted SSL Ecosystem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</guid><description>San Francisco, CA. – February 14, 2013 – Leading global certificate authorities announced the creation of the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group, committed to the exploration and promotion of best practices that advance the security of websites and online transactions. Through public education, collaboration, and advocacy, the CASC strives to improve understanding of critical policies and their potential impact on the internet infrastructure. Members of the CASC include Comodo, DigiCert, Entrust, GlobalSign, Go Daddy, Symantec, and Trend Micro.</description></item></channel></rss>