<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Patrick Nohe on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/authors/patrick-nohe/</link><description>Recent content in Patrick Nohe on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/authors/patrick-nohe/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Year Certs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</guid><description>Starting on September 1st, SSL/TLS certificates cannot be issued for longer than 13 months (397 days). This change was first announced by Apple at the CA/Browser Forum Spring Face-to-Face event in Bratislava back in March.</description></item><item><title>Could Quantum Computing Help Stave Off the Next Great Pandemic?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/06/11/could-quantum-computing-help-stave-off-the-next-great-pandemic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 20:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/06/11/could-quantum-computing-help-stave-off-the-next-great-pandemic/</guid><description>As we settle into month two of isolation in the world’s collective battle against the COVID-19 pandemic, one talking point you’ve undoubtedly heard time and again is that this won’t truly be over until there’s a vaccine. A post about how quantum computing could simplify it and reduce the time it takes exponentially.</description></item><item><title>The CA Security Council Looks Ahead to 2020 and Beyond</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/01/09/the-ca-security-council-looks-ahead-to-2020-and-beyond/</guid><description>A whirlwind of activity will cause dramatic shifts across the PKI world in the year ahead Suffice it to say that 2019 was filled with challenges and contentiousness as Certificate Authorities and Browsers began to watch their shared visions diverge. The debate around Extended Validation continued as CAs pushed for a range of reforms and browsers pushed to strip its visual indicators. And a ballot to shorten maximum certificate validity periods exposed fault-lines at the CAB Forum.</description></item><item><title>Online Identity Is Important: Let’s Upgrade Extended Validation</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/10/21/online-identity-is-important-lets-upgrade-extended-validation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 18:11:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/10/21/online-identity-is-important-lets-upgrade-extended-validation/</guid><description>It’s time for the CA/Browser Forum to focus on the other half of its mandate Let’s have a candid discussion about Extended Validation SSL. What’s working. What’s NOT. And what can be done to fix it so that all parties involved are satisfied.
But first, let’s zoom out and talk big picture. The vast majority of website owners almost never think of SSL. They worry about it once every year or so when it needs to be replaced, but it’s not really a major point of consideration.</description></item></channel></rss>