<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wayne Thayer on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/authors/wayne-thayer/</link><description>Recent content in Wayne Thayer on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 17:04:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/authors/wayne-thayer/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTTP/2 Update</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/10/26/http/2-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 17:04:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/10/26/http/2-update/</guid><description>I wrote about the next version of the HTTP protocol 18 months ago. Since then, HTTP/2 has gained significant traction, but not without generating some controversy along the way.
Performance Perhaps the biggest question lingering over HTTP/2 relates to real-world performance benefits. A demonstration comparing the time it takes to load a website over HTTP/1.1 without SSL/TLS versus HTTP/2 (which only works in browsers over HTTPS) has been criticized for being unrealistic.</description></item><item><title>HTTP/2 Is Speedy and Secure</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/20/http/2-is-speedy-and-secure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/20/http/2-is-speedy-and-secure/</guid><description>Since we last wrote about SSL/TLS performance, there has been a lot of activity in the IETF HTTP Working Group, resulting in the February announcement that the next version of HTTP has been approved. This is big news because it means that major SSL/TLS performance improvements are on the way.
Background When your browser connects to a website today, it most likely uses the HTTP/1.1 protocol that was defined in 1999 in RFC 2616.</description></item><item><title>Extra Trips are for Frequent Flyers, Not SSL/TLS Performance</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/10/30/extra-trips-are-for-frequent-flyers-not-ssl/tls-performance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 16:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/10/30/extra-trips-are-for-frequent-flyers-not-ssl/tls-performance/</guid><description>TLS is quickly becoming a de facto requirement for every website due to increased concerns about spying and Google’s recent move to use HTTPS as a factor in search engine ranking. In a recent article we explained how HSTS helps website operators to ensure that their site is always using TLS, but now we want to ensure that your performance isn’t sacrificed in the name of enhanced security. While the myth that TLS slows down a website has been debunked, some basic settings can make a site using TLS even faster.</description></item><item><title>What To Do When You Rely on Internal Names in TLS/SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/18/what-to-do-when-you-rely-on-internal-names-in-tls/ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 18:20:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/18/what-to-do-when-you-rely-on-internal-names-in-tls/ssl-certificates/</guid><description>A deadline set by the CA/Browser Forum for the use of Internal Names is quickly approaching, and many system administrators need to understand how best to adapt to this change. At the same time, hundreds of new top-level domains are being launched, which redefines what constitutes an Internal Name. In this post we’ll explain what the changes are, why they’re being made, and how you can update your systems in response to the problem.</description></item><item><title>Benefits of Elliptic Curve Cryptography</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/06/10/benefits-of-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/06/10/benefits-of-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</guid><description>Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) has existed since the mid-1980s, but it is still looked on as the newcomer in the world of SSL, and has only begun to gain adoption in the past few years. ECC is a fundamentally different mathematical approach to encryption than the venerable RSA algorithm. An elliptic curve is an algebraic function (y2 = x3 + ax + b) which looks like a symmetrical curve parallel to the x axis when plotted.</description></item><item><title>When to Choose an Extended Validation Certificate</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/25/when-to-choose-an-extended-validation-certificate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/25/when-to-choose-an-extended-validation-certificate/</guid><description>In our last post, we made a case for using Organizationally Validated (OV) or Extended Validation (EV) certificates for e-commerce, but we didn’t go into detail about the differences between OV and EV. EV certificates provide the highest level of assurance about your business, and they visually indicate this to your site’s visitors.
The telltale sign that a business has obtained an EV certificate for their website is commonly referred to as the “green bar” displayed in the browser.</description></item><item><title>Pros and Cons of Single-Domain, Multi-Domain, and Wildcard Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/02/26/pros-and-cons-of-single-domain-multi-domain-and-wildcard-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 17:30:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/02/26/pros-and-cons-of-single-domain-multi-domain-and-wildcard-certificates/</guid><description>We have previously written about the different types of SSL certificates, but in that article we focused on validation levels. A recent post on LinkedIn highlighted the fact that there is another dimension that we haven’t yet explored.
SSL certificates come in three basic packages: “single-domain” certificates that can only be used on one specific website, “multi-domain” certificates that can be used on more than one website, and “wildcard” certificates that can be used on any website within a specific domain name.</description></item><item><title>Ten Steps to Take If Your Website Is Compromised</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/02/12/ten-steps-to-take-if-your-website-is-compromised/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 20:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/02/12/ten-steps-to-take-if-your-website-is-compromised/</guid><description>After the news broke that 40 million credit card numbers were stolen from Target in a data breach of epic proportions, many of their customers went to work checking their accounts for fraudulent purchases and replacing cards we’d used recently at Target. These have become standard responses to news of this sort. In much the same way, there are some common actions that you should be aware of if your website becomes compromised.</description></item><item><title>It’s Time for TLS 1.2</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/19/its-time-for-tls-1.2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/19/its-time-for-tls-1.2/</guid><description>In a previous post titled Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2, we touched on the recommendation that Web servers be configured to prefer Transport Layer Security (TLS) version 1.2. With the planned release of Firefox 24 and recent release of Chrome 29 adding support for TLS 1.2, now is a great time for website administrators to make the switch.
Transport Layer Security was formerly called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and is the protocol that enables secure “https://” connections to websites.</description></item><item><title>Firefox 23 Blocks Mixed Content</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/08/13/firefox-23-blocks-mixed-content/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 17:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/08/13/firefox-23-blocks-mixed-content/</guid><description>The latest version of the Firefox Web browser from Mozilla was released on August 6th with a great new security feature called a “mixed content blocker”. In a nutshell, this feature ensures that all of the parts of a secure Website are indeed encrypted via SSL certificates. All of the data on the website is prevented from being intercepted, and it becomes more difficult to add malware into the site’s content.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 1: Choose the Right Certificate</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/25/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-1-choose-the-right-certificate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 01:09:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/25/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-1-choose-the-right-certificate/</guid><description>SSL and HTTPS are two of the most common security technologies on the internet today, but at the same time their use can be complex and challenging to get right. Over the next few weeks, we’ll be publishing a series of articles aimed at identifying some of the decisions that need to be made when buying, installing, and using SSL certificates. In this first installment, I’ll discuss some of the issues to consider when buying and requesting a certificate.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Revocation Checking Part 2: A Real World Example</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/11/the-importance-of-revocation-checking-part-2-a-real-world-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 16:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/11/the-importance-of-revocation-checking-part-2-a-real-world-example/</guid><description>Just last week, a new security incident related to certificate revocation checking made headlines. It was discovered that a legitimate website was hosting a malicious Java application that installed malware on the computers of people who visited the site. This comes after recent updates that introduced Security Level settings in Java, and then raised the default from Medium to High. At the high level, users are shown a warning before any unsigned Java code is executed.</description></item></channel></rss>