<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSL on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/ssl/</link><description>Recent content in SSL on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/ssl/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Year Certs</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 18:43:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/07/09/one-year-certs/</guid><description>Starting on September 1st, SSL/TLS certificates cannot be issued for longer than 13 months (397 days). This change was first announced by Apple at the CA/Browser Forum Spring Face-to-Face event in Bratislava back in March.</description></item><item><title>How to do HTTPS … The Right Way</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/06/02/how-to-do-https-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 14:30:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/06/02/how-to-do-https-the-right-way/</guid><description>With secure HTTP — aka HTTPS (the “S” is short for “secure”) — swiftly becoming universal on the Internet, it is important to know how to configure HTTPS for your website the right way. The payoff for properly securing your website has many benefits.</description></item><item><title>Chrome Kills Mixed Content for HTTPS</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/12/06/chrome-kills-mixed-content-for-https/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 16:52:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/12/06/chrome-kills-mixed-content-for-https/</guid><description>In a phased approach, Chrome plans to block mixed content on secure websites to improve user security. Most browsers already block some mixed content such as scripts and iframes by default. Chrome is amping it up by gradually taking steps to also block images, audio recordings and videos, according to a recent Google Security blog. Preventing mixed content to load will eventually result in HTTPS websites losing their security indicator downgrading the site to HTTP, which alerts visitors that the site is not secure.</description></item><item><title>How Browser Security Indicators Can Protect You from Phishing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/06/06/how-browser-security-indicators-can-protect-you-from-phishing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 14:04:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/06/06/how-browser-security-indicators-can-protect-you-from-phishing/</guid><description>The media is full of stories about how phishing sites are moving rapidly to encryption using anonymous, free DV certificates they use to imitate login pages for popular sites, such as paypal.com.
As noted in the article PayPal Phishing Certificates Far More Prevalent than Previously Thought, more than 14,000 DV SSL certificates have been issued to PayPal phishing sites since the start of 2016. Based on a random sample, 96.7% of these certificates were intended for use on phishing sites.</description></item><item><title>The Web Is Moving From HTTP to HTTPS</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/11/21/the-web-is-moving-from-http-to-https/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 17:56:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/11/21/the-web-is-moving-from-http-to-https/</guid><description>The four letters, “http”, are known to technical and non-technical users alike as the beginning of any web address. These have been ubiquitous for many years. But things are about to change. Pretty soon, you won’t be able to go to many popular websites just by using those 4 letters. You will need to add an “s” at the end (https). Why is this happening? What are the reasons for this change?</description></item><item><title>Pros and Cons of Single-Domain, Multi-Domain, and Wildcard Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/02/26/pros-and-cons-of-single-domain-multi-domain-and-wildcard-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 17:30:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/02/26/pros-and-cons-of-single-domain-multi-domain-and-wildcard-certificates/</guid><description>We have previously written about the different types of SSL certificates, but in that article we focused on validation levels. A recent post on LinkedIn highlighted the fact that there is another dimension that we haven’t yet explored.
SSL certificates come in three basic packages: “single-domain” certificates that can only be used on one specific website, “multi-domain” certificates that can be used on more than one website, and “wildcard” certificates that can be used on any website within a specific domain name.</description></item><item><title>What Is Certificate Transparency and How Does It Propose to Address Certificate Mis-Issuance?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/09/what-is-certificate-transparency-and-how-does-it-propose-to-address-certificate-mis-issuance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/09/what-is-certificate-transparency-and-how-does-it-propose-to-address-certificate-mis-issuance/</guid><description>As originally architected by Netscape and others in the mid-1990s, the certificate issuance process envisioned that the CA would present the certificate and its contents to the named subject who would review and accept the certificate first. Then the CA would publish the certificate to a repository. That process would establish that the certificate’s subject was aware of certificate issuance. (Otherwise, an unscrupulous CA could sign a subscriber’s public key and create a certificate for the subscriber without its knowledge.</description></item><item><title>What Are the Different Types of SSL Certificates?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/08/07/what-are-the-different-types-of-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 18:18:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/08/07/what-are-the-different-types-of-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Domain Validation (DV) A Domain Validated SSL certificate is issued after proof that the owner has the right to use their domain is established. This is typically done by the CA sending an email to the domain owner (as listed in a WHOIS database). Once the owner responds, the certificate is issued. Many CAs perform additional fraud checks to minimize issuance of a certificate to a domain which may be similar to a high value domain (i.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 3: Optimization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/07/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-3-optimization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 15:03:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/07/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-3-optimization/</guid><description>To get the most out of SSL/TLS, you need to do a bit more than just configure your web server with an SSL certificate. The information below will help you optimize your website’s use of SSL. Making the changes suggested below will also help move your site towards “Always On SSL” (https://otalliance.org/resources/AOSSL/index.html), a best practice in which you serve the entire contents of your website over SSL/TLS.
Changes to the content of your website Some HTML tags can include attributes that are links or paths to other pages on your site.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Out of SSL Part 2: Configuration</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 01:19:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/06/29/getting-the-most-out-of-ssl-part-2-configuration/</guid><description>They say the most complicated skill is to be simple; despite SSL and HTTPS having been around for a long time, they still are not as simple as they could be.
One of the reasons for this is that the security industry is constantly learning more about how to design and build secure systems; as a result, the protocols and software used to secure online services need to continuously evolve to keep up with the latest risks.</description></item><item><title>World’s Leading Certificate Authorities Come Together to Advance Internet Security and the Trusted SSL Ecosystem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/worlds-leading-certificate-authorities-come-together-to-advance-internet-security-and-the-trusted-ssl-ecosystem/</guid><description>San Francisco, CA. – February 14, 2013 – Leading global certificate authorities announced the creation of the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group, committed to the exploration and promotion of best practices that advance the security of websites and online transactions. Through public education, collaboration, and advocacy, the CASC strives to improve understanding of critical policies and their potential impact on the internet infrastructure. Members of the CASC include Comodo, DigiCert, Entrust, GlobalSign, Go Daddy, Symantec, and Trend Micro.</description></item></channel></rss>