<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ben Wilson on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/authors/ben-wilson/</link><description>Recent content in Ben Wilson on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 17:12:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/authors/ben-wilson/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Always-On SSL</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/09/30/always-on-ssl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 17:12:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/09/30/always-on-ssl/</guid><description>There is no doubt that content owners and publishers have a duty to encourage trust and the confidence during internet usage by adopting security best practices. If a customer believes that their data and identity are safe and protected, they are more inclined to continue their online transactions. Industry best practices for website protection should be vendor-neutral, easy to implement, and globally accessible. Websites should take all the reasonable steps possible to adopt best practices in secure design and implementation, and this includes using Always-On SSL across the entire website.</description></item><item><title>What Kind of SSL/TLS Certificate do You Need?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/05/12/what-kind-of-ssl/tls-certificate-do-you-need/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/05/12/what-kind-of-ssl/tls-certificate-do-you-need/</guid><description>In previous blog posts we have discussed the differences among the various types of SSL/TLS certificates available. In this blog post we introduce you to a new infographic that has a decision tree to help you select the right kind of certificate for your needs. In most cases you will need a publicly trusted certificate, but the decision tree notes that one type of certificate is the private trust certificate, which can be obtained and used in situations where a publicly trusted certificate cannot be used.</description></item><item><title>Stay Safe This Tax Season by Looking for SSL/TLS Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/03/30/stay-safe-this-tax-season-by-looking-for-ssl/tls-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 16:05:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/03/30/stay-safe-this-tax-season-by-looking-for-ssl/tls-certificates/</guid><description>It’s tax filing season again, and you need to be aware of scams that tried to steal your sensitive information or even your tax refund. During 2015 the IRS blocked over 4.3 million suspicious returns and more than 1.4 million confirmed identity theft returns. https://www.irs.gov/uac/Newsroom/IRS,-States-and-Tax-Industry-Combat-Identity-Theft-and-Refund-Fraud-on-Many-Fronts.
Phishing emails, account compromise, identity theft, and fake websites are a few approaches used by cyber criminals this time of year. Good computer security hygiene will usually protect you from someone else filing a tax return in your name.</description></item><item><title>Moving to Always on HTTPS, Part 2 of 2; Upgrading to HTTP Strict Transport Security</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/02/18/moving-to-always-on-https-part-2-of-2-upgrading-to-http-strict-transport-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 16:15:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/02/18/moving-to-always-on-https-part-2-of-2-upgrading-to-http-strict-transport-security/</guid><description>Part 1 of this blog post discussed browser security indicators and how to avoid getting warnings about mixed content on your website. (Mixed content leaves a door open that allows an attacker to snoop or inject malicious content during the browsing session.) This Part 2 discusses other technical measures to implement Always on HTTPS. As I noted previously, one of the difficulties with implementing Always on HTTPS is that content is often provided by third parties.</description></item><item><title>Moving to Always on HTTPS, Part 1 of 2; Marking HTTP as Unsecure</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/02/03/moving-to-always-on-https-part-1-of-2-marking-http-as-unsecure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 21:32:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/02/03/moving-to-always-on-https-part-1-of-2-marking-http-as-unsecure/</guid><description>Over the past several years there has been increased discussion about deprecating HTTP and making HTTPS the default protocol for the World Wide Web. (HTTP stands for “HyperText Transfer Protocol” and the “S” in HTTPS is enabled with an SSL/TLS digital certificate properly installed and configured on a web server.) These discussions have taken place in the context of browser security indications and technical improvements simplifying the global movement to “Always on HTTPS.</description></item><item><title>What Are “Application Reputation” and “Publisher Reputation”?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/08/27/what-are-application-reputation-and-publisher-reputation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 02:13:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/08/27/what-are-application-reputation-and-publisher-reputation/</guid><description>As one dog says to the other in Peter Steiner’s classic New Yorker cartoon– “On the Internet, nobody knows you’re a dog.”
Software downloaded from the Internet is similar to people on the Internet–it is hard to tell which ones are dogs–without help, which is what “application reputation” technology provides. “Application reputation” and “publisher reputation” are methods employed by Microsoft’s SmartScreen and other systems to distinguish good software from bad software as it is downloaded from the Internet.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Will Stop Supporting SHA-1 in October</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/06/08/facebook-will-stop-supporting-sha-1-in-october/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 16:14:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/06/08/facebook-will-stop-supporting-sha-1-in-october/</guid><description>On June 2, 2015, Facebook announced that it would stop supporting Facebook-connected apps that were signed with SHA-1, as of October 1, 2015.
“These changes are part of a broader shift in how browsers and web sites encrypt traffic to protect the contents of online communications. Typically, web browsers use a hash function to create a unique fingerprint for a chunk of data or a message. This fingerprint is then digitally signed to prove that a message has not been altered or tampered with when passing through the various servers and systems between your computer and Facebook’s servers.</description></item><item><title>In the Wake of Unauthorized Certificate Issuance by the Indian CA NIC, can Government CAs Still be Considered “Trusted Third Parties”?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/07/24/in-the-wake-of-unauthorized-certificate-issuance-by-the-indian-ca-nic-can-government-cas-still-be-considered-trusted-third-parties/</guid><description>Short answer: Government CAs can still be considered “trusted third parties,” provided that they follow the rules applicable to commercial CAs.
Introduction On July 8 Google announced that it had discovered several unauthorized Google certificates issued by the National Informatics Centre of India. It noted that the Indian government CA’s certificates were in the Microsoft Root Store and used by programs on the Windows platform. The Firefox browser on Windows uses its own root store and didn’t have these CA certificates.</description></item><item><title>Always-On SSL, Part II</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/02/05/always-on-ssl-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 20:30:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/02/05/always-on-ssl-part-ii/</guid><description>The SSL/TLS protocol has more to offer than just providing you with transmission encryption. Its main benefit is that it provides a way for third parties to authenticate connections to your website over the Internet. A user who can connect to your site and retrieve information via SSL/TLS will have greater assurance and trust that information came from you. The point of Always-On SSL is that once a user is able to create an authenticated connection to your point of presence via https, then he or she should not be bounced back outside of that zone of protection.</description></item><item><title>Encryption Still Works – It’s About How You Implement It</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/09/13/encryption-still-works-its-about-how-you-implement-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 17:04:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/09/13/encryption-still-works-its-about-how-you-implement-it/</guid><description>The September 5th joint article by the New York Times and Guardian newspapers on NSA’s and GCHQ’s efforts to circumvent encryption implementation have left many people speculating on the security of the data they are transmitting over the Internet. Hopefully, this blog post will provide some guidance and help understand SSL in light of these recent articles. Importantly, the articles point out that the primary means of attacking SSL/TLS do not exploit a vulnerability in the protocol itself but instead aim to exploit poor implementations of the protocol, insecure servers, and weak cryptography.</description></item><item><title>RSA Recap – Securing Your Site</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/03/08/rsa-recap-securing-your-site/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/03/08/rsa-recap-securing-your-site/</guid><description>At RSA last week a few of us participated in panel discussions that focused on SSL/TLS. During the panel that I moderated on Friday, one theme we addressed was secure server configuration. One of CASC’s goals is to help harden existing SSL/TLS implementations against vulnerabilities—because most SSL/TLS exploits arise from suboptimal website configurations. These vulnerabilities and attacks can be mitigated or even eliminated with proper server configuration and good website design.</description></item></channel></rss>