<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chris Bailey on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/authors/chris-bailey/</link><description>Recent content in Chris Bailey on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 18:07:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/authors/chris-bailey/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 18:07:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/12/06/ca-security-council-casc-2019-predictions-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid><description>As the legendary coach of the NY Yankees Yogi Berra allegedly said, “It’s difficult to make predictions, especially about the future.” But we’re going to try.
Here are the CA Security Council (CASC) 2019 Predictions: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly.
The Good Prediction: By the end of 2019, over 90% of the world’s http traffic will be secured over SSL/TLS
Encryption boosts user security and privacy, and the combined efforts of browsers and Certification Authorities (CAs) over the past few years have moved us rapidly to a world approaching 100% encryption.</description></item><item><title>How Browser Security Indicators Can Protect You from Phishing</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/06/06/how-browser-security-indicators-can-protect-you-from-phishing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 14:04:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/06/06/how-browser-security-indicators-can-protect-you-from-phishing/</guid><description>The media is full of stories about how phishing sites are moving rapidly to encryption using anonymous, free DV certificates they use to imitate login pages for popular sites, such as paypal.com.
As noted in the article PayPal Phishing Certificates Far More Prevalent than Previously Thought, more than 14,000 DV SSL certificates have been issued to PayPal phishing sites since the start of 2016. Based on a random sample, 96.</description></item><item><title>Google to Give Priority Ranking to SSL Enabled Sites</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/21/google-to-give-priority-ranking-to-ssl-enabled-sites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 17:30:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/21/google-to-give-priority-ranking-to-ssl-enabled-sites/</guid><description>Google’s announcement that it will give priority ranking to SSL enabled sites is a key milestone for increased use of SSL on the Internet.
Google announced a change to its ranking algorithm to include use of SSL on the site as a “very lightweight [positive] signal”. Although, this might not have an immediate impact to website owners/operators that are not currently using SSL, this is still an important signal indicating everyone should be prepared to encrypt all their websites if they want to remain relevant.</description></item></channel></rss>