<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SHA1 on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/sha1/</link><description>Recent content in SHA1 on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/sha1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2018 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2017 2017 saw the end of SHA-1 in public trust SSL/TLS certificates and the start of Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) allowing domain owners to authorize their CA. A “Not secure” browser indication was propagated to push more websites to support HTTPS. There was also a change in the certification authority (CA) ownership with DigiCert acquiring Symantec’s SSL and related PKI business and Francisco Partners buying Comodo’s CA.</description></item><item><title>Google Plans to Deprecate SHA-1 Certificates – Updated</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/09/24/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates-updated/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 18:26:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/09/24/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates-updated/</guid><description>UPDATED September 23, 2014: The following blog post has been updated with action taken in recent weeks, as well as to reflect helpful user comments left on our August 28 blog post on this topic.
On August 19, Google announced a new policy that accelerates the deprecation of SHA-1 certificates, potentially causing websites using SHA-1 certificates to display warnings in the near future. While keeping with an earlier Microsoft announcement to accept SHA-1 certificates with an expiration date before Jan.</description></item><item><title>Google Plans to Deprecate SHA-1 Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/08/28/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 14:07:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/08/28/google-plans-to-deprecate-sha-1-certificates/</guid><description>On August 19, Google announced a new policy that accelerates the deprecation of SHA-1 certificates, potentially causing websites using SHA-1 certificates to display warnings in the near future. With the change, Chrome 39 will show a warning for sites that have a SHA-1 certificate expiring in 2016 and require a click through warning for sites with a SHA-1 certificate expiring in 2017 or later. This proposal is scheduled for Chrome 39, which could be released as early as 12 weeks from now.</description></item></channel></rss>