<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OV on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/ov/</link><description>Recent content in OV on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/ov/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CASC Announces Launch of London Protocol to Improve Identity Assurance and Minimize Phishing on Identity Websites</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/casc-announces-launch-of-london-protocol-to-improve-identity-assurance-and-minimize-phishing-on-identity-websites/</guid><description>LONDON – (June 27, 2018) – The Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement of the security of websites and online transactions, announced at the CA/Browser Forum event in London the launch of the London Protocol – an initiative to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted with organization validated (OV) and extended validation (EV) certificates, which contain organization identity information (Identity Certificates).</description></item><item><title>The London Protocol</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/the-london-protocol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/27/the-london-protocol/</guid><description>The objective of The London Protocol is to improve identity assurance and minimize the possibility of phishing activity on websites encrypted by OV (organization validated) and EV (extended validation) certificates (together referred to as “Identity Websites”). The London Protocol reinforces the distinction between Identity Websites making them even more secure for users than websites encrypted by DV (domain validated) certificates. That security feature can then be utilized by others for their own security purposes, including informing users as to the type of website they are visiting and use by antiphishing engines and browser filters in their security algorithms.</description></item><item><title>2018 – Looking Back, Moving Forward</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:31:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/01/06/2018-looking-back-moving-forward/</guid><description>Looking Back at 2017 2017 saw the end of SHA-1 in public trust SSL/TLS certificates and the start of Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) allowing domain owners to authorize their CA. A “Not secure” browser indication was propagated to push more websites to support HTTPS. There was also a change in the certification authority (CA) ownership with DigiCert acquiring Symantec’s SSL and related PKI business and Francisco Partners buying Comodo’s CA.</description></item><item><title>The Latest on Certification Authority Authorization</title><link>https://pkic.org/2017/03/21/the-latest-on-certification-authority-authorization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 20:40:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2017/03/21/the-latest-on-certification-authority-authorization/</guid><description>Things are certainly heating up at the CA/Browser with exciting proposals surrounding inclusion of the Wi-Fi Alliance (WFA) as a subjectAltName otherName, new validation methods, and debates over how the CAB Forum will continue operating. One of these newly passed ballots requires all CAs to check and process a domain name’s DNS Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) resource record prior to issuing a digital certificate.
Background RFC 6844 created CAA records as a method for domain owners to specify a policy on which certificate authorities are authorized to issue certificates for the associated domain.</description></item><item><title>Google Certificate Transparency (CT) to Expand to All Certificates Types</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/11/08/google-certificate-transparency-ct-to-expand-to-all-certificates-types/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 17:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/11/08/google-certificate-transparency-ct-to-expand-to-all-certificates-types/</guid><description>The policy change goes into effect October 2017 A recent Google announcement stated that all publicly trusted SSL/TLS certificates issued in October 2017 or later will be expected to comply with Chrome’s Certificate Transparency (CT) policy or be untrusted by the browser.
Since January 2015, Chrome has required Extended Validation (EV) certificates to comply with CT. With this policy change, the Chrome CT policy will also apply to Domain Validated (DV) and Organization Validated (OV) certificates.</description></item><item><title>Think Twice Before Using DV for E-Commerce</title><link>https://pkic.org/2014/03/12/think-twice-before-using-dv-for-e-commerce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 19:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2014/03/12/think-twice-before-using-dv-for-e-commerce/</guid><description>In a previous blog (What Are the Different Types of SSL Certificates?), we described the various types of SSL certificates available from publicly trusted Certificate Authorities (CAs). CAs are often asked by their customers which certificate type should be used for websites conducting E-Commerce, rather than for just encryption of sensitive data. For the latter case, a Domain Validated (DV) certificate will work fine. A DV cert allows for encryption to take place between the browser and the server.</description></item><item><title>How Organizations Are Authenticated for SSL Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/11/22/how-organizations-are-authenticated-for-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/11/22/how-organizations-are-authenticated-for-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>Certification Authorities (CAs) are trusted third parties that authenticate customers before issuing SSL certificates to secure their servers.
Exactly how do CAs authenticate these organizations? And where are the rules that determine what CAs must do during authentication?
The Rules on Customer Authentication In the past, there were no common rules applicable to CAs as to minimum steps required to authenticate a customer before issuing an SSL certificate. Instead, each CA was permitted to create its own authentication processes, and was only required to describe the process in general terms in its public Certification Practice Statement (CPS).</description></item></channel></rss>