<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Revocation on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/revocation/</link><description>Recent content in Revocation on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 21:03:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/revocation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An Introduction to OCSP Multi-Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 21:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/05/07/an-introduction-to-ocsp-multi-stapling/</guid><description>OCSP Stapling OCSP is a protocol used to check the validity of certificates to make sure they have not been revoked. OCSP is an alternative to Certificate Revocation Lists (CRLs). Since OCSP responses can be as small as a few hundred bytes, OCSP is particularly useful when the issuing CA has relatively big CRLs, as well as when the client has limited memory and processing power.
OCSP can also provide much more timely information than CRLs about the status of a certificate since the information is generally fetched more frequently.</description></item><item><title>Certificate Revocation and OCSP Stapling</title><link>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2013/02/14/certificate-revocation-and-ocsp-stapling/</guid><description>Revocation As a body of global CAs, the CA Security Council is committed to educating server administrators, end-users and other interested parties about SSL enhancements and best practices that can better protect everyone. An important initiative that can make a practical difference right now is addressing easily implemented improvements to certificate status services that handle revocation of invalid or expired certificates, specifically the implementation of OCSP stapling.
What is certificate revocation?</description></item></channel></rss>