<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HSM on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</title><link>https://pkic.org/tags/hsm/</link><description>Recent content in HSM on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>PKI Consortium, Inc. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:18:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pkic.org/tags/hsm/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don’t ‘Compromise’ Your Code Amid Malware Mayhem</title><link>https://pkic.org/2020/05/12/dont-compromise-your-code-amid-malware-mayhem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:18:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2020/05/12/dont-compromise-your-code-amid-malware-mayhem/</guid><description>Code Signing Certificates demand a price premium in the underground online marketplace. This is no surprise considering that criminals sometimes use them to dupe their potential victims into installing malware in their machine.</description></item><item><title>What Are Subordinate CAs and Why Would You Want Your Own?</title><link>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2019/06/26/what-are-subordinate-cas-and-why-would-you-want-your-own/</guid><description>Digital certificate and PKI adoption has changed quite a bit in recent years. Gone are the days where certificates were only synonymous with SSL/TLS; compliance drivers like stronger authentication requirements and digital signature regulations (e.g. eIDAS) have greatly expanded the role of PKI within the enterprise.
As PKI usage has expanded, conversation has moved beyond just the number and type of certificates needed and onto deeper dialogue about custom PKI deployments.</description></item><item><title>Fortify Allows Users to Generate X.509 Certificates in Their Browser</title><link>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-allows-users-to-generate-x.509-certificates-in-their-browser/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2018/06/19/fortify-allows-users-to-generate-x.509-certificates-in-their-browser/</guid><description>Fortify, an open source application sponsored by Certificate Authorities through the CA Security Council, is now available for Windows and Mac. The Fortify app, which is free for all users, connects a user’s web browsers to smart cards, security tokens, and certificates on a user’s local machine. This can allow users to generate X.509 certificates in their browser, replacing the need for the deprecated &amp;lt;keygen&amp;gt; functionality.
Certificate Generation In The Browser The Web Cryptography API, also known as Web Crypto, provides a set of cryptographic capabilities for web browsers through a set of JavaScript APIs.</description></item><item><title>Leading Certificate Authorities and Microsoft Introduce New Standards to Protect Consumers Online</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 21:05:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/12/08/leading-certificate-authorities-and-microsoft-introduce-new-standards-to-protect-consumers-online/</guid><description>San Francisco –December 8, 2016 – the Certificate Authority Security Council (CASC), an advocacy group committed to the advancement web security, today announced the Code Signing Working Group has released new Minimum Requirements for Code Signing for use by all Certificate Authorities (CA). These requirements represent the first-ever standardized code signing guidelines. Code signing is the method of using a certificate-based digital signature to sign executables and scripts in order to verify the author’s identity and ensure that the code has not been changed or corrupted.</description></item><item><title>Minimum Requirements for Code Signing Certificates</title><link>https://pkic.org/2016/07/20/minimum-requirements-for-code-signing-certificates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 20:47:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2016/07/20/minimum-requirements-for-code-signing-certificates/</guid><description>It is time for an update on the Baseline Requirements for Code Signing.
First the bad news, the new standard was not approved by the CA/Browser Forum due to philosophical differences among some forum members who felt code signing was not in scope with the Forum’s charter.
The good news is the document was created in a multi-stakeholder environment and substantially improves the current management processes. As such, it was decided to bring the document outside of the forum and finalize it as part of the CA Security Council.</description></item><item><title>Fighting the Good Fight for Online Trust</title><link>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:47:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pkic.org/2015/04/02/fighting-the-good-fight-for-online-trust/</guid><description>Once again Browsers and Certificate Authorities are in the news over the reported mis-issuance of an SSL server certificate to a google.com domain. Discovered by Google most likely via technology known as key pinning and discussed by Google’s Adam Langley in this blog, a Chinese certificate authority, CNNIC (Chinese Internet Network Information Center), apparently issued an intermediate certificate to an Egyptian company called MCS Holdings. Because the CNNIC root certificate is included in the root store of most major browsers, users would not see any warnings on sites that have certificates issued by CNNIC or MCS Holdings.</description></item></channel></rss>